<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><FreeXml><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the Lord your God has blessed you in all the work of your hands. He knows your going through this great wilderness. These forty years the Lord your God has been with you. You have lacked nothing.”’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 2,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, to which indeed you were called in one body. And be thankful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Are there any among the false gods of the nations that can bring rain? Or can the heavens give showers? Are you not he, O Lord our God? We set our hope on you, for you do all these things. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Incline my heart to your testimonies, and not to selfish gain! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,36</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness, for one’s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will punish you according to the fruit of your deeds, declares the Lord; I will kindle a fire in her forest, and it shall devour all that is around her.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 21,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I bow down toward your holy temple and give thanks to your name for your steadfast love and your faithfulness, for you have exalted above all things your name and your word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 138,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Pray then like this: “Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Epiphanias (Erscheinungsfest)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Out of my distress I called on the Lord; the Lord answered me and set me free. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit; a broken and contrite heart, O God, you will not despise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>whoever speaks, as one who speaks oracles of God; whoever serves, as one who serves by the strength that God supplies—in order that in everything God may be glorified through Jesus Christ. To him belong glory and dominion forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, dress yourself for work; arise, and say to them everything that I command you. Do not be dismayed by them, lest I dismay you before them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For what we proclaim is not ourselves, but Jesus Christ as Lord, with ourselves as your servants for Jesus’ sake. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Return, O faithless sons; I will heal your faithlessness.” “Behold, we come to you, for you are the Lord our God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Draw near to God, and he will draw near to you. Cleanse your hands, you sinners, and purify your hearts, you double-minded. Be wretched and mourn and weep. Let your laughter be turned to mourning and your joy to gloom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 4,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For there is one God, and there is one mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus, who gave himself as a ransom for all, which is the testimony given at the proper time. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>Everyone utters lies to his neighbor; with flattering lips and a double heart they speak. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 12,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Twelve, “Do you want to go away as well?” Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,67-68</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Noah found favor in the eyes of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 6,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But we believe that we will be saved through the grace of the Lord Jesus, just as they will.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 15,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Can a man hide himself in secret places so that I cannot see him? declares the Lord. Do I not fill heaven and earth? declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore Eli said to Samuel, “Go, lie down, and if he calls you, you shall say, ‘Speak, Lord, for your servant hears.’” So Samuel went and lay down in his place.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>One who heard us was a woman named Lydia, from the city of Thyatira, a seller of purple goods, who was a worshiper of God. The Lord opened her heart to pay attention to what was said by Paul. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming, declares the Lord, when the city shall be rebuilt for the Lord from the Tower of Hananel to the Corner Gate. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,38</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“You are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hidden. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It was not because you were more in number than any other people that the Lord set his love on you and chose you, for you were the fewest of all peoples,
 but it is because the Lord loves you and is keeping the oath that he swore to your fathers, that the Lord has brought you out with a mighty hand and redeemed you from the house of slavery, from the hand of Pharaoh king of Egypt. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 7,7-8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then it depends not on human will or exertion, but on God, who has mercy.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Lift up your heads, O gates! And be lifted up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 24,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and be like men who are waiting for their master to come home from the wedding feast, so that they may open the door to him at once when he comes and knocks. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>And he said, “Naked I came from my mother’s womb, and naked shall I return. The Lord gave, and the Lord has taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 1,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for we brought nothing into the world, and we cannot take anything out of the world. But if we have food and clothing, with these we will be content. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,7-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My soul also is greatly troubled. But you, O Lord—how long? Turn, O Lord, deliver my life; save me for the sake of your steadfast love.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 6,3.4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he spoke, and it came to be; he commanded, and it stood firm. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the centurion replied, “Lord, I am not worthy to have you come under my roof, but only say the word, and my servant will be healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and said, “O Lord, God of our fathers, are you not God in heaven? You rule over all the kingdoms of the nations. In your hand are power and might, so that none is able to withstand you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 20,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18-19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is bringing you into a good land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and springs, flowing out in the valleys and hills, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then the angel showed me the river of the water of life, bright as crystal, flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb through the middle of the street of the city; also, on either side of the river, the tree of life with its twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit each month. The leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But now, O Lord, you are our Father; we are the clay, and you are our potter; we are all the work of your hand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 64,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he came and preached peace to you who were far off and peace to those who were near. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Moses and the people of Israel sang this song to the Lord, saying, “I will sing to the Lord, for he has triumphed gloriously; the horse and his rider he has thrown into the sea. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 15,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So if the Son sets you free, you will be free indeed.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>Take care lest your heart be deceived, and you turn aside and serve other gods and worship them; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 11,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Do not lay up for yourselves treasures on earth, where moth and rust destroy and where thieves break in and steal, For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,19-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who would not fear you, O King of the nations? For this is your due; for among all the wise ones of the nations and in all their kingdoms there is none like you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Peter and the apostles answered, “We must obey God rather than men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 5,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Bring me out of prison, that I may give thanks to your name!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 142,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The fear of the Lord is hatred of evil. Pride and arrogance and the way of evil and perverted speech I hate. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 8,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So you also must consider yourselves dead to sin and alive to God in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil, for you are with me; your rod and your staff, they comfort me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 23,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not driven to despair; persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then these men came by agreement and found Daniel making petition and plea before his God.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-01-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yet it was I who taught Ephraim to walk; I took them up by their arms, but they did not know that I healed them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 11,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if we are faithless, he remains faithful— for he cannot deny himself. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Septuagesimae (70 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Behold, the Lord God comes with might, and his arm rules for him; behold, his reward is with him, and his recompense before him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who will not fear, O Lord, and glorify your name? For you alone are holy. All nations will come and worship you, for your righteous acts have been revealed.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have set the Lord always before me; because he is at my right hand, I shall not be shaken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 16,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Spirit of the Lord shall rest upon him, the Spirit of wisdom and understanding, the Spirit of counsel and might, the Spirit of knowledge and the fear of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus was baptized, immediately he went up from the water, and behold, the heavens were opened to him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove and coming to rest on him; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will set my eyes on them for good, and I will bring them back to this land. I will build them up, and not tear them down; I will plant them, and not pluck them up. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 24,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>There is therefore now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfills his purpose for me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 57,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask him! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I know, my God, that you test the heart and have pleasure in uprightness. In the uprightness of my heart I have freely offered all these things, and now I have seen your people, who are present here, offering freely and joyously to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the fear of the Lord is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the Lord are true, and righteous altogether. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 19,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Sexagesimae (60 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>And he said to man, ‘Behold, the fear of the Lord, that is wisdom, and to turn away from evil is understanding.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 28,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the wisdom from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, open to reason, full of mercy and good fruits, impartial and sincere. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Lay down a pledge for me with you; who is there who will put up security for me? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 17,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Surely the righteous shall give thanks to your name; the upright shall dwell in your presence. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 140,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Listen, my beloved brothers, has not God chosen those who are poor in the world to be rich in faith and heirs of the kingdom, which he has promised to those who love him? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 2,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Those who sow in tears shall reap with shouts of joy! He who goes out weeping, bearing the seed for sowing, shall come home with shouts of joy, bringing his sheaves with him.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 126,5-6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And let us not grow weary of doing good, for in due season we will reap, if we do not give up. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Know that the Lord, he is God! It is he who made us, and we are his; we are his people, and the sheep of his pasture. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 100,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we know that the Son of God has come and has given us understanding, so that we may know him who is true; and we are in him who is true, in his Son Jesus Christ. He is the true God and eternal life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let the heavens be glad, and let the earth rejoice, and let them say among the nations, “The Lord reigns!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 16,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord stirred up the spirit of Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, governor of Judah, and the spirit of Joshua the son of Jehozadak, the high priest, and the spirit of all the remnant of the people. And they came and worked on the house of the Lord of hosts, their God, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Haggai 1,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Only let your manner of life be worthy of the gospel of Christ, so that whether I come and see you or am absent, I may hear of you that you are standing firm in one spirit, with one mind striving side by side for the faith of the gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Estomihi (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag><Losungstext>You shall walk in all the way that the Lord your God has commanded you, that you may live, and that it may go well with you, and that you may live long in the land that you shall possess. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As a shepherd seeks out his flock when he is among his sheep that have been scattered, so will I seek out my sheep, and I will rescue them from all places where they have been scattered on a day of clouds and thick darkness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And have mercy on those who doubt</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Jude 22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The keeper of the prison paid no attention to anything that was in Joseph’s charge, because the Lord was with him. And whatever he did, the Lord made it succeed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 39,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For whoever has despised the day of small things shall rejoice, and shall see the plumb line in the hand of Zerubbabel. “These seven are the eyes of the Lord, which range through the whole earth.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 4,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As they were gathering in Galilee, Jesus said to them, “The Son of Man is about to be delivered into the hands of men, and they will kill him, and he will be raised on the third day.” And they were greatly distressed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 17,22-23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord repay you for what you have done, and a full reward be given you by the Lord, the God of Israel, under whose wings you have come to take refuge!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ruth 2,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Praise him, sun and moon, praise him, all you shining stars! Let them praise the name of the Lord! For he commanded and they were created.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 148,3.5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song of the Lamb, saying, “Great and amazing are your deeds, O Lord God the Almighty! Just and true are your ways, O King of the nations! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then King David went in and sat before the Lord and said, “Who am I, O Lord God, and what is my house, that you have brought me thus far? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 7,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who saved us and called us to a holy calling, not because of our works but because of his own purpose and grace, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before the ages began, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You who have escaped from the sword, go, do not stand still! Remember the Lord from far away, and let Jerusalem come into your mind: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 51,50</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we are always of good courage. We know that while we are at home in the body we are away from the Lord, for we walk by faith, not by sight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And all these blessings shall come upon you and overtake you, if you obey the voice of the Lord your God. Blessed shall you be in the city, and blessed shall you be in the field. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 28,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But blessed are your eyes, for they see, and your ears, for they hear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And you shall know that I am the Lord, when I deal with you for my name’s sake, not according to your evil ways, nor according to your corrupt deeds, O house of Israel, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,44</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am writing to you, little children, because your sins are forgiven for his name’s sake. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Shall not all these take up their taunt against him, with scoffing and riddles for him, and say, “Woe to him who heaps up what is not his own— for how long?— and loads himself with pledges!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and to aspire to live quietly, and to mind your own affairs, and to work with your hands, as we instructed you, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have heard Ephraim grieving, ‘You have disciplined me, and I was disciplined, like an untrained calf; bring me back that I may be restored, for you are the Lord my God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said, “Jesus, remember me when you come into your kingdom.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 23,42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Good and upright is the Lord; therefore he instructs sinners in the way. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for the one who is weak in faith, welcome him, but not to quarrel over opinions. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-02-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have told the glad news of deliverance in the great congregation; behold, I have not restrained my lips, as you know, O Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this is the love of God, that we keep his commandments. And his commandments are not burdensome. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Reminiszere (Gedenke, HERR, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Your righteousness is like the mountains of God; your judgments are like the great deep; man and beast you save, O Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 36,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hezekiah received the letter from the hand of the messengers and read it; and Hezekiah went up to the house of the Lord and spread it before the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He loves righteousness and justice; the earth is full of the steadfast love of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My enemies say of me in malice, “When will he die, and his name perish?”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 41,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the prayer of faith will save the one who is sick, and the Lord will raise him up. And if he has committed sins, he will be forgiven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your mercy come to me, that I may live; for your law is my delight. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,77</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Go therefore to the main roads and invite to the wedding feast as many as you find.’
 And those servants went out into the roads and gathered all whom they found, both bad and good. So the wedding hall was filled with guests. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 22,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He is your praise. He is your God, who has done for you these great and terrifying things that your eyes have seen. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, I send an angel before you to guard you on the way and to bring you to the place that I have prepared. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 23,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Are they not all ministering spirits sent out to serve for the sake of those who are to inherit salvation? but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,14-2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Okuli (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den HERRN. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>How great are your works, O Lord! Your thoughts are very deep! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 92,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he laid his hands on her, and immediately she was made straight, and she glorified God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The war horse is a false hope for salvation, and by its great might it cannot rescue. Behold, the eye of the Lord is on those who fear him, on those who hope in his steadfast love, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,17-18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are the circumcision, who worship by the Spirit of God and glory in Christ Jesus and put no confidence in the flesh— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are my help and my deliverer; do not delay, O my God!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and hope does not put us to shame, because God’s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Asa went out to meet him, and they drew up their lines of battle in the Valley of Zephathah at Mareshah. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 14,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have said these things to you, that in me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation. But take heart; I have overcome the world.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “If now I have found favor in your sight, O Lord, please let the Lord go in the midst of us, for it is a stiff-necked people, and pardon our iniquity and our sin, and take us for your inheritance.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 34,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For where two or three are gathered in my name, there am I among them.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but the Lord takes pleasure in those who fear him, in those who hope in his steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that I may know him and the power of his resurrection, and may share his sufferings, becoming like him in his death, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag><Losungstext>From the rising of the sun to its setting, the name of the Lord is to be praised! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 113,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of endurance and encouragement grant you to live in such harmony with one another, in accord with Christ Jesus, that together you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But this command I gave them: ‘Obey my voice, and I will be your God, and you shall be my people. And walk in all the way that I command you, that it may be well with you.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 7,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus answered him, “If anyone loves me, he will keep my word, and my Father will love him, and we will come to him and make our home with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for the ways of the Lord are right, and the upright walk in them, but transgressors stumble in them.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 14,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But those who seek to destroy my life shall go down into the depths of the earth; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 63,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>which is why I suffer as I do. But I am not ashamed, for I know whom I have believed, and I am convinced that he is able to guard until that Day what has been entrusted to me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You turn things upside down! Shall the potter be regarded as the clay, that the thing made should say of its maker, “He did not make me”; or the thing formed say of him who formed it, “He has no understanding”? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But who are you, O man, to answer back to God? Will what is molded say to its molder, “Why have you made me like this?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore I will divide him a portion with the many, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong, because he poured out his soul to death and was numbered with the transgressors; yet he bore the sin of many, and makes intercession for the transgressors. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He disarmed the rulers and authorities and put them to open shame, by triumphing over them in him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the people of Israel cried out to the Lord, saying, “We have sinned against you, because we have forsaken our God and have served the Baals.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 10,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Judika (Gott, schaffe mir Recht! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>and many peoples shall come, and say: “Come, let us go up to the mountain of the Lord, to the house of the God of Jacob, that he may teach us his ways and that we may walk in his paths.” For out of Zion shall go the law, and the word of the Lord from Jerusalem. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And people will come from east and west, and from north and south, and recline at table in the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Both we and our fathers have sinned; we have committed iniquity; we have done wickedness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 106,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus heard it, he said to them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick. I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord God took the man and put him in the garden of Eden to work it and keep it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 2,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Moreover, it is required of stewards that they be found faithful.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he was afraid and said, “How awesome is this place! This is none other than the house of God, and this is the gate of heaven.”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 28,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He was still speaking when, behold, a bright cloud overshadowed them, and a voice from the cloud said, “This is my beloved Son, with whom I am well pleased; listen to him.” But Jesus came and touched them, saying, “Rise, and have no fear.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 17,5-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I have put my words in your mouth and covered you in the shadow of my hand, establishing the heavens and laying the foundations of the earth, and saying to Zion, ‘You are my people.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Lord said to Paul one night in a vision, “Do not be afraid, but go on speaking and do not be silent, for I am with you, and no one will attack you to harm you, for I have many in this city who are my people.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 18,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the people came to Moses and said, “We have sinned, for we have spoken against the Lord and against you. Pray to the Lord, that he take away the serpents from us.” So Moses prayed for the people. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 21,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My little children, I am writing these things to you so that you may not sin. But if anyone does sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He drew me up from the pit of destruction, out of the miry bog, and set my feet upon a rock, making my steps secure. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He delivered us from such a deadly peril, and he will deliver us. On him we have set our hope that he will deliver us again. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Palmsonntag</Sonntag><Losungstext>I made the earth and created man on it; it was my hands that stretched out the heavens, and I commanded all their host. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>yet for us there is one God, the Father, from whom are all things and for whom we exist, and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and through whom we exist. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Look down from your holy habitation, from heaven, and bless your people Israel and the ground that you have given us, as you swore to our fathers, a land flowing with milk and honey.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 26,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,68</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-03-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Ah, you who hide deep from the Lord your counsel, whose deeds are in the dark, and who say, “Who sees us? Who knows us?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Take no part in the unfruitful works of darkness, but instead expose them. But when anything is exposed by the light, it becomes visible</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,11.13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Exalt the Lord our God; worship at his footstool! Holy is he! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 99,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>After this I heard what seemed to be the loud voice of a great multitude in heaven, crying out, “Hallelujah! Salvation and glory and power belong to our God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 19,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Comfort, comfort my people, says your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And at the time for the banquet he sent his servant to say to those who had been invited, ‘Come, for everything is now ready.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag><Losungstext>But he said to them, “Do not delay me, since the Lord has prospered my way. Send me away that I may go to my master.”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 24,56</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And those who passed by derided him, wagging their heads and saying, “You who would destroy the temple and rebuild it in three days, save yourself! If you are the Son of God, come down from the cross.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 27,39-40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you are a people holy to the Lord your God, and the Lord has chosen you to be a people for his treasured possession, out of all the peoples who are on the face of the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 14,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for the Father himself loves you, because you have loved me and have believed that I came from God. I came from the Father and have come into the world, and now I am leaving the world and going to the Father.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,27-28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>the people whom I formed for myself that they might declare my praise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In that same hour he rejoiced in the Holy Spirit and said, “I thank you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, that you have hidden these things from the wise and understanding and revealed them to little children; yes, Father, for such was your gracious will. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For a thousand years in your sight are but as yesterday when it is past, or as a watch in the night. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 90,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The snares of death encompassed me; the pangs of Sheol laid hold on me; I suffered distress and anguish. Then I called on the name of the Lord: “O Lord, I pray, deliver my soul!”</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,3.4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,57</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and that their children, who have not known it, may hear and learn to fear the Lord your God, as long as you live in the land that you are going over the Jordan to possess.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 31,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Jesus called them to him, saying, “Let the children come to me, and do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Waw: Let your steadfast love come to me, O Lord, your salvation according to your promise; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,41</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and return to the Lord your God, you and your children, and obey his voice in all that I command you today, with all your heart and with all your soul, then the Lord your God will restore your fortunes and have mercy on you, and he will gather you again from all the peoples where the Lord your God has scattered you</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and, having been set free from sin, have become slaves of righteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When a man’s ways please the Lord, he makes even his enemies to be at peace with him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of peace be with you all. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag><Losungstext>And I will make of you a great nation, and I will bless you and make your name great, so that you will be a blessing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 12,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“You are the salt of the earth, but if salt has lost its taste, how shall its saltiness be restored? It is no longer good for anything except to be thrown out and trampled under people’s feet. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not wrong one another, but you shall fear your God, for I am the Lord your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 25,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You have taken up my cause, O Lord; you have redeemed my life. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,58</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>We have this as a sure and steadfast anchor of the soul, a hope that enters into the inner place behind the curtain, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Hear, O kings; give ear, O princes; to the Lord I will sing; I will make melody to the Lord, the God of Israel.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 5,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>About midnight Paul and Silas were praying and singing hymns to God, and the prisoners were listening to them, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“The Lord is in the right, for I have rebelled against his word; but hear, all you peoples, and see my suffering; my young women and my young men have gone into captivity. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 1,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I will arise and go to my father, and I will say to him, “Father, I have sinned against heaven and before you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh, let the evil of the wicked come to an end, and may you establish the righteous— you who test the minds and hearts, O righteous God! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>There is only one lawgiver and judge, he who is able to save and to destroy. But who are you to judge your neighbor? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 4,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now therefore go, and I will be with your mouth and teach you what you shall speak.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 4,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“But when the Helper comes, whom I will send to you from the Father, the Spirit of truth, who proceeds from the Father, he will bear witness about me. And you also will bear witness, because you have been with me from the beginning. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,26-27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will cut off the chariot from Ephraim and the war horse from Jerusalem; and the battle bow shall be cut off, and he shall speak peace to the nations; his rule shall be from sea to sea, and from the River to the ends of the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore God has highly exalted him and bestowed on him the name that is above every name, so that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I thank you that you have answered me and have become my salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Job answered the Lord and said:
 “Behold, I am of small account; what shall I answer you? I lay my hand on my mouth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 40,3-4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now Jesus was praying in a certain place, and when he finished, one of his disciples said to him, “Lord, teach us to pray, as John taught his disciples.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the Lord drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 14,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For freedom Christ has set us free; stand firm therefore, and do not submit again to a yoke of slavery. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your sun shall no more go down, nor your moon withdraw itself; for the Lord will be your everlasting light, and your days of mourning shall be ended. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>keep yourselves in the love of God, waiting for the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ that leads to eternal life.</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Jude 21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the eyes of the Lord run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him. You have done foolishly in this, for from now on you will have wars.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 16,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I know your works, your toil and your patient endurance, and how you cannot bear with those who are evil, but have tested those who call themselves apostles and are not, and found them to be false. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 2,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore the Lord has kept ready the calamity and has brought it upon us, for the Lord our God is righteous in all the works that he has done, and we have not obeyed his voice. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 9,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he replied to one of them, ‘Friend, I am doing you no wrong. Did you not agree with me for a denarius? Am I not allowed to do what I choose with what belongs to me? Or do you begrudge my generosity?</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 20,13.15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>To the Lord our God belong mercy and forgiveness, for we have rebelled against him </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 9,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, as one trespass led to condemnation for all men, so one act of righteousness leads to justification and life for all men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now set your mind and heart to seek the Lord your God. Arise and build the sanctuary of the Lord God, so that the ark of the covenant of the Lord and the holy vessels of God may be brought into a house built for the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 22,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Brothers, I do not consider that I have made it my own. But one thing I do: forgetting what lies behind and straining forward to what lies ahead, I press on toward the goal for the prize of the upward call of God in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I believe that I shall look upon the goodness of the Lord in the land of the living! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 27,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Father, I desire that they also, whom you have given me, may be with me where I am, to see my glory that you have given me because you loved me before the foundation of the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you, O God, have tested us; you have tried us as silver is tried. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 66,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed is the man who remains steadfast under trial, for when he has stood the test he will receive the crown of life, which God has promised to those who love him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-04-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have multiplied, O Lord my God, your wondrous deeds and your thoughts toward us; none can compare with you! I will proclaim and tell of them, yet they are more than can be told. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have not bought me sweet cane with money, or satisfied me with the fat of your sacrifices. But you have burdened me with your sins; you have wearied me with your iniquities.
 “I, I am he who blots out your transgressions for my own sake, and I will not remember your sins. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,24-25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,21-22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will make your oppressors eat their own flesh, and they shall be drunk with their own blood as with wine. Then all flesh shall know that I am the Lord your Savior, and your Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>even as the Son of Man came not to be served but to serve, and to give his life as a ransom for many.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 20,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Kantate (Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If a brother or sister is poorly clothed and lacking in daily food, So also faith by itself, if it does not have works, is dead.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 2,15-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be gracious to me, O Lord, for I am in distress; my eye is wasted from grief; my soul and my body also. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>may have strength to comprehend with all the saints what is the breadth and length and height and depth, and to know the love of Christ that surpasses knowledge, that you may be filled with all the fullness of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,18-19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall eat in plenty and be satisfied, and praise the name of the Lord your God, who has dealt wondrously with you. And my people shall never again be put to shame. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet he did not leave himself without witness, for he did good by giving you rains from heaven and fruitful seasons, satisfying your hearts with food and gladness.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For my father and my mother have forsaken me, but the Lord will take me in. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 27,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will walk before the Lord in the land of the living. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Cry aloud; do not hold back; lift up your voice like a trumpet; declare to my people their transgression, to the house of Jacob their sins. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be deceived: God is not mocked, for whatever one sows, that will he also reap. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whom did you dread and fear, so that you lied, and did not remember me, did not lay it to heart? Have I not held my peace, even for a long time, and you do not fear me? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Peter remembered the saying of Jesus, “Before the rooster crows, you will deny me three times.” And he went out and wept bitterly. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 26,75</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag><Losungstext>And they shall know that I am the Lord their God with them, and that they, the house of Israel, are my people, declares the Lord God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,30</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Speak tenderly to Jerusalem, and cry to her that her warfare is ended, that her iniquity is pardoned, that she has received from the Lord’s hand double for all her sins. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he says, “In a favorable time I listened to you, and in a day of salvation I have helped you.” Behold, now is the favorable time; behold, now is the day of salvation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Gideon said to him, “Please, sir, if the Lord is with us, why then has all this happened to us? And where are all his wonderful deeds that our fathers recounted to us, saying, ‘Did not the Lord bring us up from Egypt?’ But now the Lord has forsaken us and given us into the hand of Midian.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 6,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For now we see in a mirror dimly, but then face to face. Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>he says: “It is too light a thing that you should be my servant to raise up the tribes of Jacob and to bring back the preserved of Israel; I will make you as a light for the nations, that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Himmelfahrt des Herrn</Sonntag><Losungstext>He shall judge between the nations, and shall decide disputes for many peoples; and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruning hooks; nation shall not lift up sword against nation, neither shall they learn war anymore. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>because of the tender mercy of our God, whereby the sunrise shall visit us from on high to give light to those who sit in darkness and in the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,78-79</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh that they had such a heart as this always, to fear me and to keep all my commandments, that it might go well with them and with their descendants forever! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be led away by diverse and strange teachings, for it is good for the heart to be strengthened by grace, not by foods, which have not benefited those devoted to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Only fear the Lord and serve him faithfully with all your heart. For consider what great things he has done for you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 12,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who gave himself for us to redeem us from all lawlessness and to purify for himself a people for his own possession who are zealous for good works. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Now therefore, if I have found favor in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favor in your sight. Consider too that this nation is your people.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To him the gatekeeper opens. The sheep hear his voice, and he calls his own sheep by name and leads them out.
 When he has brought out all his own, he goes before them, and the sheep follow him, for they know his voice.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>then will you delight in right sacrifices, in burnt offerings and whole burnt offerings; then bulls will be offered on your altar. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when the Pharisees saw this, they said to his disciples, “Why does your teacher eat with tax collectors and sinners?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will raise up for them a prophet like you from among their brothers. And I will put my words in his mouth, and he shall speak to them all that I command him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 18,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Long ago, at many times and in many ways, God spoke to our fathers by the prophets, but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the one who by his strength established the mountains, being girded with might; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 65,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will instruct you and teach you in the way you should go; I will counsel you with my eye upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 32,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And she had a sister called Mary, who sat at the Lord’s feet and listened to his teaching. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you shall winnow them, and the wind shall carry them away, and the tempest shall scatter them. And you shall rejoice in the Lord; in the Holy One of Israel you shall glory. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Finally, my brothers, rejoice in the Lord. To write the same things to you is no trouble to me and is safe for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Indeed, none who wait for you shall be put to shame; they shall be ashamed who are wantonly treacherous. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Though you have not seen him, you love him. Though you do not now see him, you believe in him and rejoice with joy that is inexpressible and filled with glory, obtaining the outcome of your faith, the salvation of your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Wait for the Lord; be strong, and let your heart take courage; wait for the Lord! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 27,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the Spirit of truth comes, he will guide you into all the truth, for he will not speak on his own authority, but whatever he hears he will speak, and he will declare to you the things that are to come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>In that day the root of Jesse, who shall stand as a signal for the peoples—of him shall the nations inquire, and his resting place shall be glorious. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for my eyes have seen your salvation a light for revelation to the Gentiles, and for glory to your people Israel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,30-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, the Lord’s hand is not shortened, that it cannot save, or his ear dull, that it cannot hear; but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,1-2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am speaking in human terms, because of your natural limitations. For just as you once presented your members as slaves to impurity and to lawlessness leading to more lawlessness, so now present your members as slaves to righteousness leading to sanctification. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Thus says the Lord of hosts, Render true judgments, show kindness and mercy to one another, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the merciful, for they shall receive mercy. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life, and I shall dwell in the house of the Lord forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 23,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And one called to another and said: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord of hosts; the whole earth is full of his glory!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 6,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, I will bring to it health and healing, and I will heal them and reveal to them abundance of prosperity and security. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he went throughout all Galilee, teaching in their synagogues and proclaiming the gospel of the kingdom and healing every disease and every affliction among the people. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 4,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-05-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag><Losungstext>God, the Lord, is my strength; he makes my feet like the deer’s; he makes me tread on my high places. To the choirmaster: with stringed instruments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Habbakuk 3,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we do not lose heart. Though our outer self is wasting away, our inner self is being renewed day by day. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>let the wicked forsake his way, and the unrighteous man his thoughts; let him return to the Lord, that he may have compassion on him, and to our God, for he will abundantly pardon.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore put away all filthiness and rampant wickedness and receive with meekness the implanted word, which is able to save your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Moses said to him, “Are you jealous for my sake? Would that all the Lord’s people were prophets, that the Lord would put his Spirit on them!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 11,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Pursue love, and earnestly desire the spiritual gifts, especially that you may prophesy. On the other hand, the one who prophesies speaks to people for their upbuilding and encouragement and consolation.</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 14,1.3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>all sheep and oxen, and also the beasts of the field,
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 8,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In righteousness you shall be established; you shall be far from oppression, for you shall not fear; and from terror, for it shall not come near you.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they went and woke him, saying, “Save us, Lord; we are perishing.” And he said to them, “Why are you afraid, O you of little faith?” Then he rose and rebuked the winds and the sea, and there was a great calm. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,25-26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My soul thirsts for God, for the living God. When shall I come and appear before God? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 42,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 7,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not withhold good from those to whom it is due, when it is in your power to do it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he answered them, “Whoever has two tunics is to share with him who has none, and whoever has food is to do likewise.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 3,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>He makes peace in your borders; he fills you with the finest of the wheat. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then let us pursue what makes for peace and for mutual upbuilding. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“A son honors his father, and a servant his master. If then I am a father, where is my honor? And if I am a master, where is my fear? says the Lord of hosts to you, O priests, who despise my name. But you say, ‘How have we despised your name?’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 1,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for these nations, which you are about to dispossess, listen to fortune-tellers and to diviners. But as for you, the Lord your God has not allowed you to do this.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 18,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Neither be called instructors, for you have one instructor, the Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 23,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be pleased, O Lord, to deliver me! O Lord, make haste to help me! Let those be put to shame and disappointed altogether who seek to snatch away my life; let those be turned back and brought to dishonor who delight in my hurt!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,13.14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and call upon me in the day of trouble; I will deliver you, and you shall glorify me.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 50,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But this is gain for a land in every way: a king committed to cultivated fields.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 5,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Keep your life free from love of money, and be content with what you have, for he has said, “I will never leave you nor forsake you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, you have brought up my soul from Sheol; you restored me to life from among those who go down to the pit. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 30,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, confess your sins to one another and pray for one another, that you may be healed. The prayer of a righteous person has great power as it is working. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>So I will bless you as long as I live; in your name I will lift up my hands. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 63,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers,
 nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,38-39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, children are a heritage from the Lord, the fruit of the womb a reward. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 127,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and they said to him, “Do you hear what these are saying?” And Jesus said to them, “Yes; have you never read, “‘Out of the mouth of infants and nursing babies you have prepared praise’?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 21,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for it is the Lord our God who brought us and our fathers up from the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery, and who did those great signs in our sight and preserved us in all the way that we went, and among all the peoples through whom we passed.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Savior, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Jude 24-25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A glad heart makes a cheerful face, but by sorrow of heart the spirit is crushed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You brood of vipers! How can you speak good, when you are evil? For out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaks. The good person out of his good treasure brings forth good, and the evil person out of his evil treasure brings forth evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 12,34-35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He makes me lie down in green pastures. He leads me beside still waters. He restores my soul. He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 23,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me. I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, and no one will snatch them out of my hand. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,27-28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But he was pierced for our transgressions; he was crushed for our iniquities; upon him was the chastisement that brought us peace, and with his wounds we are healed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Remove far from me falsehood and lying; give me neither poverty nor riches; feed me with the food that is needful for me, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 30,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Give us this day our daily bread, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You gave a wide place for my steps under me, and my feet did not slip; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 22,37</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As Jesus passed on from there, he saw a man called Matthew sitting at the tax booth, and he said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O Lord, make me dwell in safety. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 4,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Not that I am speaking of being in need, for I have learned in whatever situation I am to be content. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Johannistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Return, O faithless children, declares the Lord; for I am your master; I will take you, one from a city and two from a family, and I will bring you to Zion. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In those days John the Baptist came preaching in the wilderness of Judea, “Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 3,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore the Lord waits to be gracious to you, and therefore he exalts himself to show mercy to you. For the Lord is a God of justice; blessed are all those who wait for him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing for joy, O heavens, and exult, O earth; break forth, O mountains, into singing! For the Lord has comforted his people and will have compassion on his afflicted. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have given him dominion over the works of your hands; you have put all things under his feet, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 8,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Of his own will he brought us forth by the word of truth, that we should be a kind of firstfruits of his creatures. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Arise, O God, defend your cause; remember how the foolish scoff at you all the day! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 74,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“For the kingdom of heaven is like a master of a house who went out early in the morning to hire laborers for his vineyard.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 20,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not seek their peace or their prosperity all your days forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 23,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If anyone hears my words and does not keep them, I do not judge him; for I did not come to judge the world but to save the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-06-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are my hiding place and my shield; I hope in your word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,114</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Is not my word like fire, declares the Lord, and like a hammer that breaks the rock in pieces? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I came to cast fire on the earth, and would that it were already kindled! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,49</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So I have looked upon you in the sanctuary, beholding your power and glory. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 63,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to me, “It is done! I am the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end. To the thirsty I will give from the spring of the water of life without payment. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The angel of the Lord encamps around those who fear him, and delivers them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, a man from the crowd cried out, “Teacher, I beg you to look at my son, for he is my only child. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>lest like a lion they tear my soul apart, rending it in pieces, with none to deliver. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 7,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are you when others revile you and persecute you and utter all kinds of evil against you falsely on my account. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>He raises up the poor from the dust; he lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honor. For the pillars of the earth are the Lord’s, and on them he has set the world. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“What man of you, having a hundred sheep, if he has lost one of them, does not leave the ninety-nine in the open country, and go after the one that is lost, until he finds it? And when he has found it, he lays it on his shoulders, rejoicing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>creating the fruit of the lips. Peace, peace, to the far and to the near,” says the Lord, “and I will heal him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he himself is our peace, who has made us both one and has broken down in his flesh the dividing wall of hostility </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>that your eyes may be open night and day toward this house, the place of which you have said, ‘My name shall be there,’ that you may listen to the prayer that your servant offers toward this place. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but Christ is faithful over God’s house as a son. And we are his house if indeed we hold fast our confidence and our boasting in our hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 3,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For your eyes have seen all the great work of the Lord that he did. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 11,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that which we have seen and heard we proclaim also to you, so that you too may have fellowship with us; and indeed our fellowship is with the Father and with his Son Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then he said to them, “Go your way. Eat the fat and drink sweet wine and send portions to anyone who has nothing ready, for this day is holy to our Lord. And do not be grieved, for the joy of the Lord is your strength.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 8,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, rejoice. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The scatterer has come up against you. Man the ramparts; watch the road; dress for battle; collect all your strength. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nahum 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus said to them again, “Peace be with you. As the Father has sent me, even so I am sending you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 20,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Naaman said, “If not, please let there be given to your servant two mule loads of earth, for from now on your servant will not offer burnt offering or sacrifice to any god but the Lord.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 5,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>It shall come to pass in the latter days that the mountain of the house of the Lord shall be established as the highest of the mountains, and shall be lifted up above the hills; and all the nations shall flow to it,He shall judge between the nations, and shall decide disputes for many peoples; and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruning hooks; nation shall not lift up sword against nation, neither shall they learn war anymore.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,2.4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Soldiers also asked him, “And we, what shall we do?” And he said to them, “Do not extort money from anyone by threats or by false accusation, and be content with your wages.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 3,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and rend your hearts and not your garments.” Return to the Lord your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love; and he relents over disaster. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And David said, “The Lord who delivered me from the paw of the lion and from the paw of the bear will deliver me from the hand of this Philistine.” And Saul said to David, “Go, and the Lord be with you!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,37</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Put not your trust in princes, in a son of man, in whom there is no salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let them alone; they are blind guides. And if the blind lead the blind, both will fall into a pit.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 15,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways and my thoughts than your thoughts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who is the man who fears the Lord? Him will he instruct in the way that he should choose. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore be imitators of God, as beloved children. And walk in love, as Christ loved us and gave himself up for us, a fragrant offering and sacrifice to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 139,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Nathanael said to him, “How do you know me?” Jesus answered him, “Before Philip called you, when you were under the fig tree, I saw you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>May the Lord give strength to his people! May the Lord bless his people with peace! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 29,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord rewards every man for his righteousness and his faithfulness, for the Lord gave you into my hand today, and I would not put out my hand against the Lord’s anointed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 26,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who are persecuted for righteousness’ sake, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Out of them shall come songs of thanksgiving, and the voices of those who celebrate. I will multiply them, and they shall not be few; I will make them honored, and they shall not be small. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 30,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He put another parable before them, saying, “The kingdom of heaven is like a grain of mustard seed that a man took and sowed in his field. It is the smallest of all seeds, but when it has grown it is larger than all the garden plants and becomes a tree, so that the birds of the air come and make nests in its branches.”
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Rejoice not over me, O my enemy; when I fall, I shall rise; when I sit in darkness, the Lord will be a light to me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 7,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have come into the world as light, so that whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You will say in that day: “I will give thanks to you, O Lord, for though you were angry with me, your anger turned away, that you might comfort me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 12,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>All that the Father gives me will come to me, and whoever comes to me I will never cast out. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord kills and brings to life; he brings down to Sheol and raises up. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Those of low estate are but a breath; those of high estate are a delusion; in the balances they go up; they are together lighter than a breath. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 62,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Wondrously show your steadfast love, O Savior of those who seek refuge from their adversaries at your right hand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 17,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this we know love, that he laid down his life for us, and we ought to lay down our lives for the brothers. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“At the set time that I appoint I will judge with equity. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 75,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>There is none like you, O Lord; you are great, and your name is great in might. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He said to them, “But who do you say that I am?”
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I am with you to save you, declares the Lord; I will make a full end of all the nations among whom I scattered you, but of you I will not make a full end. I will discipline you in just measure, and I will by no means leave you unpunished. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 30,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-07-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Lead me in your truth and teach me, for you are the God of my salvation; for you I wait all the day long. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For in the hand of the Lord there is a cup with foaming wine, well mixed, and he pours out from it, and all the wicked of the earth shall drain it down to the dregs. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 75,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard the altar saying, “Yes, Lord God the Almighty, true and just are your judgments!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 16,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“They shall be mine, says the Lord of hosts, in the day when I make up my treasured possession, and I will spare them as a man spares his son who serves him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 3,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Husbands, love your wives, as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her, that he might sanctify her, having cleansed her by the washing of water with the word, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,25-26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the path of the righteous is like the light of dawn, which shines brighter and brighter until full day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 4,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In the same way, let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have you not known? Have you not heard? The Lord is the everlasting God, the Creator of the ends of the earth. He does not faint or grow weary; his understanding is unsearchable. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>to the only wise God be glory forevermore through Jesus Christ! Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Is anything too hard for the Lord? At the appointed time I will return to you, about this time next year, and Sarah shall have a son.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 18,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But overhearing what they said, Jesus said to the ruler of the synagogue, “Do not fear, only believe.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Out of the anguish of his soul he shall see and be satisfied; by his knowledge shall the righteous one, my servant, make many to be accounted righteous, and he shall bear their iniquities. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And being found in human form, he humbled himself by becoming obedient to the point of death, even death on a cross. Therefore God has highly exalted him and bestowed on him the name that is above every name, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As they were going down to the outskirts of the city, Samuel said to Saul, “Tell the servant to pass on before us, and when he has passed on, stop here yourself for a while, that I may make known to you the word of God.”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 9,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Know this, my beloved brothers: let every person be quick to hear, slow to speak, slow to anger; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who say to a tree, ‘You are my father,’ and to a stone, ‘You gave me birth.’ For they have turned their back to me, and not their face. But in the time of their trouble they say, ‘Arise and save us!’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the Lord searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will cast you off forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 28,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when you pray, go into your room and shut the door and pray to your Father who is in secret. And your Father who sees in secret will reward you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Jonathan said to the young man who carried his armor, “Come, let us go over to the garrison of these uncircumcised. It may be that the Lord will work for us, for nothing can hinder the Lord from saving by many or by few.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 14,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>how on the day that you stood before the Lord your God at Horeb, the Lord said to me, ‘Gather the people to me, that I may let them hear my words, so that they may learn to fear me all the days that they live on the earth, and that they may teach their children so.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When he came and saw the grace of God, he was glad, and he exhorted them all to remain faithful to the Lord with steadfast purpose, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 11,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Now therefore fear the Lord and serve him in sincerity and in faithfulness. Put away the gods that your fathers served beyond the River and in Egypt, and serve the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For your obedience is known to all, so that I rejoice over you, but I want you to be wise as to what is good and innocent as to what is evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Great is our Lord, and abundant in power; his understanding is beyond measure. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Because you have made the Lord your dwelling place— the Most High, who is my refuge— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I do not ask that you take them out of the world, but that you keep them from the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, do not your eyes look for truth? You have struck them down, but they felt no anguish; you have consumed them, but they refused to take correction. They have made their faces harder than rock; they have refused to repent. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 5,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember your leaders, those who spoke to you the word of God. Consider the outcome of their way of life, and imitate their faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>‘Say to Joseph, “Please forgive the transgression of your brothers and their sin, because they did evil to you.”’ And now, please forgive the transgression of the servants of the God of your father.” Joseph wept when they spoke to him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 50,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then Peter came up and said to him, “Lord, how often will my brother sin against me, and I forgive him? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “I do not say to you seven times, but seventy-seven times.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,21-22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When words are many, transgression is not lacking, but whoever restrains his lips is prudent. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for by your words you will be justified, and by your words you will be condemned.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 12,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will give them one heart, and a new spirit I will put within them. I will remove the heart of stone from their flesh and give them a heart of flesh, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 11,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord is good, a stronghold in the day of trouble; he knows those who take refuge in him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nahum 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Indeed he was ill, near to death. But God had mercy on him, and not only on him but on me also, lest I should have sorrow upon sorrow.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Truly, you are a God who hides himself, O God of Israel, the Savior. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he will be delivered over to the Gentiles and will be mocked and shamefully treated and spit upon. But they understood none of these things. This saying was hidden from them, and they did not grasp what was said. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,32-34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>he reveals deep and hidden things; he knows what is in the darkness, and the light dwells with him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not pronounce judgment before the time, before the Lord comes, who will bring to light the things now hidden in darkness and will disclose the purposes of the heart. Then each one will receive his commendation from God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you have tasted that the Lord is good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>He gives power to the faint, and to him who has no might he increases strength.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities. For when I am weak, then I am strong. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord has bared his holy arm before the eyes of all the nations, and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of our God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 52,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The true light, which gives light to everyone, was coming into the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord answered and said to his people, “Behold, I am sending to you grain, wine, and oil, and you will be satisfied; and I will no more make you a reproach among the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then he ordered the crowds to sit down on the grass, and taking the five loaves and the two fish, he looked up to heaven and said a blessing. Then he broke the loaves and gave them to the disciples, and the disciples gave them to the crowds. And they all ate and were satisfied. And they took up twelve baskets full of the broken pieces left over.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Jehoshaphat said to the king of Israel, “Inquire first for the word of the Lord.”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 18,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But those that were sown on the good soil are the ones who hear the word and accept it and bear fruit, thirtyfold and sixtyfold and a hundredfold.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and though my condition was a trial to you, you did not scorn or despise me, but received me as an angel of God, as Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, I will bring them from the north country and gather them from the farthest parts of the earth, among them the blind and the lame, the pregnant woman and she who is in labor, together; a great company, they shall return here. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the master said to the servant, ‘Go out to the highways and hedges and compel people to come in, that my house may be filled.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Yet your people say, ‘The way of the Lord is not just,’ when it is their own way that is not just. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 33,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Go, and proclaim these words toward the north, and say, “‘Return, faithless Israel, declares the Lord. I will not look on you in anger, for I am merciful, declares the Lord; I will not be angry forever. Only acknowledge your guilt, that you rebelled against the Lord your God and scattered your favors among foreigners under every green tree, and that you have not obeyed my voice, declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,12-13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-08-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “Behold, I am making a covenant. Before all your people I will do marvels, such as have not been created in all the earth or in any nation. And all the people among whom you are shall see the work of the Lord, for it is an awesome thing that I will do with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 34,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And on the Sabbath he began to teach in the synagogue, and many who heard him were astonished, saying, “Where did this man get these things? What is the wisdom given to him? How are such mighty works done by his hands? Is not this the carpenter, the son of Mary and brother of James and Joses and Judas and Simon? And are not his sisters here with us?” And they took offense at him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,2-3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>With my mouth I will give great thanks to the Lord; I will praise him in the midst of the throng. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 109,30</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And coming up at that very hour she began to give thanks to God and to speak of him to all who were waiting for the redemption of Jerusalem. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And they sang responsively, praising and giving thanks to the Lord, “For he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever toward Israel.” And all the people shouted with a great shout when they praised the Lord, because the foundation of the house of the Lord was laid. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezra 3,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, praising God and having favor with all the people. And the Lord added to their number day by day those who were being saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,46-47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion! Shout aloud, O daughter of Jerusalem! Behold, your king is coming to you; righteous and having salvation is he, humble and mounted on a donkey, on a colt, the foal of a donkey. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 9,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who, though he was in the form of God, did not count equality with God a thing to be grasped, but emptied himself, by taking the form of a servant, being born in the likeness of men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>God shall bless us; let all the ends of the earth fear him!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 67,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Worthy are you, our Lord and God, to receive glory and honor and power, for you created all things, and by your will they existed and were created.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember your mercy, O Lord, and your steadfast love, for they have been from of old. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In this is love, not that we have loved God but that he loved us and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>We will not hide them from their children, but tell to the coming generation the glorious deeds of the Lord, and his might, and the wonders that he has done. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 78,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heal the sick, raise the dead, cleanse lepers, cast out demons. You received without paying; give without pay. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Plead my cause and redeem me; give me life according to your promise! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,154</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Follow the pattern of the sound words that you have heard from me, in the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Salvation belongs to the Lord; your blessing be on your people!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May mercy, peace, and love be multiplied to you.</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Jude 2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let us lift up our hearts and hands to God in heaven: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,41</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For I the Lord do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 3,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I am the Alpha and the Omega,” says the Lord God, “who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And many nations shall join themselves to the Lord in that day, and shall be my people. And I will dwell in your midst, and you shall know that the Lord of hosts has sent me to you.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 2,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; for the same Lord is Lord of all, bestowing his riches on all who call on him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 10,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Teach me your way, O Lord, that I may walk in your truth; unite my heart to fear your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 86,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember Jesus Christ, risen from the dead, the offspring of David, as preached in my gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Incline your ear, and come to me; hear, that your soul may live; and I will make with you an everlasting covenant, my steadfast, sure love for David. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Jews who had believed him, “If you abide in my word, you are truly my disciples, and you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you will not abandon my soul to Sheol, or let your holy one see corruption. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 16,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Wretched man that I am! Who will deliver me from this body of death? Thanks be to God through Jesus Christ our Lord! So then, I myself serve the law of God with my mind, but with my flesh I serve the law of sin.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 7,24-25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So Abram went, as the Lord had told him, and Lot went with him. Abram was seventy-five years old when he departed from Haran. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 12,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By faith Abraham obeyed when he was called to go out to a place that he was to receive as an inheritance. And he went out, not knowing where he was going. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Hezekiah prayed before the Lord and said: “O Lord, the God of Israel, enthroned above the cherubim, you are the God, you alone, of all the kingdoms of the earth; you have made heaven and earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then the seventh angel blew his trumpet, and there were loud voices in heaven, saying, “The kingdom of the world has become the kingdom of our Lord and of his Christ, and he shall reign forever and ever.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 11,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You hem me in, behind and before, and lay your hand upon me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 139,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the Lord of peace himself give you peace at all times in every way. The Lord be with you all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not spurn us, for your name’s sake; do not dishonor your glorious throne; remember and do not break your covenant with us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But I with the voice of thanksgiving will sacrifice to you; what I have vowed I will pay. Salvation belongs to the Lord!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I do not nullify the grace of God, for if righteousness were through the law, then Christ died for no purpose. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 2,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>16. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Keep steady my steps according to your promise, and let no iniquity get dominion over me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,133</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Brothers, do not be children in your thinking. Be infants in evil, but in your thinking be mature. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 14,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let us come into his presence with thanksgiving; let us make a joyful noise to him with songs of praise! For the Lord is a great God, and a great King above all gods. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 95,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>which he will display at the proper time—he who is the blessed and only Sovereign, the King of kings and Lord of lords, who alone has immortality, who dwells in unapproachable light, whom no one has ever seen or can see. To him be honor and eternal dominion. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,15-16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,35-36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Save us, we pray, O Lord! O Lord, we pray, give us success!
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Who is like you, O Lord, among the gods? Who is like you, majestic in holiness, awesome in glorious deeds, doing wonders? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 15,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and there are varieties of activities, but it is the same God who empowers them all in everyone. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O you who love the Lord, hate evil! He preserves the lives of his saints; he delivers them from the hand of the wicked. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 97,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Because you have kept my word about patient endurance, I will keep you from the hour of trial that is coming on the whole world, to try those who dwell on the earth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>like heat in a dry place. You subdue the noise of the foreigners; as heat by the shade of a cloud, so the song of the ruthless is put down. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He has shown strength with his arm; he has scattered the proud in the thoughts of their hearts; he has brought down the mighty from their thrones and exalted those of humble estate; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,51-52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>17. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>who confirms the word of his servant and fulfills the counsel of his messengers, who says of Jerusalem, ‘She shall be inhabited,’ and of the cities of Judah, ‘They shall be built, and I will raise up their ruins’; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now these Jews were more noble than those in Thessalonica; they received the word with all eagerness, examining the Scriptures daily to see if these things were so. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Before I was afflicted I went astray, but now I keep your word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,67</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now as he went on his way, he approached Damascus, and suddenly a light from heaven shone around him. And falling to the ground he heard a voice saying to him, “Saul, Saul, why are you persecuting me?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 9,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Michaelistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord is your keeper; the Lord is your shade on your right hand. The sun shall not strike you by day, nor the moon by night. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 121,5-6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now when they had departed, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared to Joseph in a dream and said, “Rise, take the child and his mother, and flee to Egypt, and remain there until I tell you, for Herod is about to search for the child, to destroy him.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 2,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-09-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you are our Father, though Abraham does not know us, and Israel does not acknowledge us; you, O Lord, are our Father, our Redeemer from of old is your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord, the God of heaven, who took me from my father’s house and from the land of my kindred, and who spoke to me and swore to me, ‘To your offspring I will give this land,’ he will send his angel before you, and you shall take a wife for my son from there. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 24,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now an angel of the Lord said to Philip, “Rise and go toward the south to the road that goes down from Jerusalem to Gaza.” This is a desert place. And he rose and went. And there was an Ethiopian, a eunuch, a court official of Candace, queen of the Ethiopians, who was in charge of all her treasure. He had come to Jerusalem to worship </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 8,26-27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who fear the Lord, praise him! All you offspring of Jacob, glorify him, and stand in awe of him, all you offspring of Israel! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>How then will they call on him in whom they have not believed? And how are they to believe in him of whom they have never heard? And how are they to hear without someone preaching? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 10,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But if he says, ‘I have no pleasure in you,’ behold, here I am, let him do to me what seems good to him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 15,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For if we live, we live to the Lord, and if we die, we die to the Lord. So then, whether we live or whether we die, we are the Lord’s. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Zum Erntedankfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Let your eyes be open to the plea of your servant and to the plea of your people Israel, giving ear to them whenever they call to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,52</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for they did not meet the people of Israel with bread and water, but hired Balaam against them to curse them—yet our God turned the curse into a blessing.
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 13,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that is, in Christ God was reconciling the world to himself, not counting their trespasses against them, and entrusting to us the message of reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For thus says the Lord to the house of Israel: “Seek me and live; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 5,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, there was a man named Zacchaeus. He was a chief tax collector and was rich.
 And he was seeking to see who Jesus was, but on account of the crowd he could not, because he was small in stature. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,2-3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Like birds hovering, so the Lord of hosts will protect Jerusalem; he will protect and deliver it; he will spare and rescue it.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 31,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I desire steadfast love and not sacrifice, the knowledge of God rather than burnt offerings. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 6,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let love be genuine. Abhor what is evil; hold fast to what is good. Love one another with brotherly affection. Outdo one another in showing honor. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and rend your hearts and not your garments.” Return to the Lord your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love; and he relents over disaster. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Behold, we consider those blessed who remained steadfast. You have heard of the steadfastness of Job, and you have seen the purpose of the Lord, how the Lord is compassionate and merciful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let this be recorded for a generation to come, so that a people yet to be created may praise the Lord: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 102,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>19. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>You have set up a banner for those who fear you, that they may flee to it from the bow. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 60,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But when Pharaoh saw that the rain and the hail and the thunder had ceased, he sinned yet again and hardened his heart, he and his servants. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 9,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>See to it that no one fails to obtain the grace of God; that no “root of bitterness” springs up and causes trouble, and by it many become defiled; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed are those who keep his testimonies, who seek him with their whole heart, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “Naked I came from my mother’s womb, and naked shall I return. The Lord gave, and the Lord has taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 1,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope,
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who can say, “I have made my heart pure; I am clean from my sin”? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 20,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,23-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>On your walls, O Jerusalem, I have set watchmen; all the day and all the night they shall never be silent. You who put the Lord in remembrance, take no rest, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 62,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>pray without ceasing, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>There shall not be found among you anyone who burns his son or his daughter as an offering,5 anyone who practices divination or tells fortunes or interprets omens, or a sorcerer for whoever does these things is an abomination to the Lord. And because of these abominations the Lord your God is driving them out before you.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 18,10.12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Claiming to be wise, they became fools, and exchanged the glory of the immortal God for images resembling mortal man and birds and animals and creeping things. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 1,22-23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>This poor man cried, and the Lord heard him and saved him out of all his troubles. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord watches over the sojourners; he upholds the widow and the fatherless, but the way of the wicked he brings to ruin. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Religion that is pure and undefiled before God, the Father, is this: to visit orphans and widows in their affliction, and to keep oneself unstained from the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“There is none holy like the Lord: for there is none besides you; there is no rock like our God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To the King of the ages, immortal, invisible, the only God, be honor and glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Joseph’s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king’s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison. But the Lord was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favor in the sight of the keeper of the prison.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 39,20.21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them, and those who are mistreated, since you also are in the body. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, the nations are like a drop from a bucket, and are accounted as the dust on the scales; behold, he takes up the coastlands like fine dust. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then I saw another angel flying directly overhead, with an eternal gospel to proclaim to those who dwell on earth, to every nation and tribe and language and people. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 14,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The counsel of the Lord stands forever, the plans of his heart to all generations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But that prophet or that dreamer of dreams shall be put to death, because he has taught rebellion against the Lord your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt and redeemed you out of the house of slavery, to make you leave the way in which the Lord your God commanded you to walk. So you shall purge the evil from your midst. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You are my friends if you do what I command you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>21. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Who among you fears the Lord and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the Lord and rely on his God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But immediately Jesus spoke to them, saying, “Take heart; it is I. Do not be afraid.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If the God of my father, the God of Abraham and the Fear of Isaac, had not been on my side, surely now you would have sent me away empty-handed. God saw my affliction and the labor of my hands and rebuked you last night.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 31,42</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Mary said, “My soul magnifies the Lord, for he has looked on the humble estate of his servant. For behold, from now on all generations will call me blessed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,46-48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Please pardon the iniquity of this people, according to the greatness of your steadfast love, just as you have forgiven this people, from Egypt until now.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 14,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He is the propitiation for our sins, and not for ours only but also for the sins of the whole world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming, declares the Lord, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel and the house of Judah, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory— even us whom he has called, not from the Jews only but also from the Gentiles? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,23-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Speak: “Thus declares the Lord, ‘The dead bodies of men shall fall like dung upon the open field, like sheaves after the reaper, and none shall gather them.’” Thus says the Lord: “Let not the wise man boast in his wisdom, let not the mighty man boast in his might, let not the rich man boast in his riches, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 9,22-23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I am not ashamed of the gospel, for it is the power of God for salvation to everyone who believes, to the Jew first and also to the Greek. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord our God be with us, as he was with our fathers. May he not leave us or forsake us, </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,57</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that they should seek God, and perhaps feel their way toward him and find him. Yet he is actually not far from each one of us, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-10-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Return, O my soul, to your rest; for the Lord has dealt bountifully with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be like them, for your Father knows what you need before you ask him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>22. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>You are wearied with your many counsels; let them stand forth and save you, those who divide the heavens, who gaze at the stars, who at the new moons make known what shall come upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 47,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they came to Capernaum. And when he was in the house he asked them, “What were you discussing on the way?” But they kept silent, for on the way they had argued with one another about who was the greatest. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 9,33-34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the Lord, and I will restore your fortunes and gather you from all the nations and all the places where I have driven you, declares the Lord, and I will bring you back to the place from which I sent you into exile. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 29,13-14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Again I say to you, if two of you agree on earth about anything they ask, it will be done for them by my Father in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And these words that I command you today shall be on your heart. You shall teach them diligently to your children, and shall talk of them when you sit in your house, and when you walk by the way, and when you lie down, and when you rise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,6-7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But be doers of the word, and not hearers only, deceiving yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I hate those who pay regard to worthless idols, but I trust in the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then we who are alive, who are left, will be caught up together with them in the clouds to meet the Lord in the air, and so we will always be with the Lord. Therefore encourage one another with these words.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So she called the name of the Lord who spoke to her, “You are a God of seeing,” for she said, “Truly here I have seen him who looks after me.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 16,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And as he passed by, he saw Levi the son of Alphaeus sitting at the tax booth, and he said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall treat the stranger who sojourns with you as the native among you, and you shall love him as yourself, for you were strangers in the land of Egypt: I am the Lord your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “You yourselves know how unlawful it is for a Jew to associate with or to visit anyone of another nation, but God has shown me that I should not call any person common or unclean. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>You shall treat the stranger who sojourns with you as the native among you, and you shall love him as yourself, for you were strangers in the land of Egypt: I am the Lord your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the King will answer them, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord will keep you from all evil; he will keep your life. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 121,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But even the hairs of your head are all numbered. Fear not, therefore; you are of more value than many sparrows. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,30-31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When my life was fainting away, I remembered the Lord, and my prayer came to you, into your holy temple. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Whoever makes a practice of sinning is of the devil, for the devil has been sinning from the beginning. The reason the Son of God appeared was to destroy the works of the devil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Make haste to help me, O Lord, my salvation!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 38,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Lord stood by me and strengthened me, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. So I was rescued from the lion’s mouth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord God: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if service, in our serving; the one who teaches, in his teaching; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For I know their works and their thoughts, and the time is coming to gather all nations and tongues. And they shall come and shall see my glory, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“When the Son of Man comes in his glory, and all the angels with him, then he will sit on his glorious throne. Before him will be gathered all the nations, and he will separate people one from another as a shepherd separates the sheep from the goats. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Serve the Lord with gladness! Come into his presence with singing! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 100,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So, whether you eat or drink, or whatever you do, do all to the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>Blessed are those whose strength is in you, in whose heart are the highways to Zion. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 84,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Through him then let us continually offer up a sacrifice of praise to God, that is, the fruit of lips that acknowledge his name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>great in counsel and mighty in deed, whose eyes are open to all the ways of the children of man, rewarding each one according to his ways and according to the fruit of his deeds. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for “‘In him we live and move and have our being’; as even some of your own poets have said, “‘For we are indeed his offspring.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“See, I am setting before you today a blessing and a curse: and the curse, if you do not obey the commandments of the Lord your God, but turn aside from the way that I am commanding you today, to go after other gods that you have not known. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 11,26-28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus said to him, “I am the way, and the truth, and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Buß- und Bettag</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will make a covenant of peace with them. It shall be an everlasting covenant with them. And I will set them in their land and multiply them, and will set my sanctuary in their midst forevermore. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For all the promises of God find their Yes in him. That is why it is through him that we utter our Amen to God for his glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let not your heart envy sinners, but continue in the fear of the Lord all the day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 23,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven. For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,45</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For behold, I am for you, and I will turn to you, and you shall be tilled and sown. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He has helped his servant Israel, in remembrance of his mercy, as he spoke to our fathers, to Abraham and to his offspring forever.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,54-55</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing to the Lord, bless his name; tell of his salvation from day to day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 96,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres (Ewigkeitssonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You have led in your steadfast love the people whom you have redeemed; you have guided them by your strength to your holy abode. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 15,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But our citizenship is in heaven, and from it we await a Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whoever is slow to anger is better than the mighty, and he who rules his spirit than he who takes a city. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They have all turned aside; together they have become corrupt; there is none who does good, not even one. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 14,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Honor the Lord with your wealth and with the firstfruits of all your produce; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I will say to my soul, “Soul, you have ample goods laid up for many years; relax, eat, drink, be merry.”’ But God said to him, ‘Fool! This night your soul is required of you, and the things you have prepared, whose will they be?’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord will vindicate his people and have compassion on his servants. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 135,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And because of him you are in Christ Jesus, who became to us wisdom from God, righteousness and sanctification and redemption, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My soul makes its boast in the Lord; let the humble hear and be glad. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Is anyone among you suffering? Let him pray. Is anyone cheerful? Let him sing praise. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>All these things my hand has made, and so all these things came to be, declares the Lord. But this is the one to whom I will look: he who is humble and contrite in spirit and trembles at my word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And now I commend you to God and to the word of his grace, which is able to build you up and to give you the inheritance among all those who are sanctified. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 20,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>They feast on the abundance of your house, and you give them drink from the river of your delights. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 36,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>See what kind of love the Father has given to us, that we should be called children of God; and so we are. The reason why the world does not know us is that it did not know him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-11-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In overflowing anger for a moment I hid my face from you, but with everlasting love I will have compassion on you,” says the Lord, your Redeemer. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He alone is my rock and my salvation, my fortress; I shall not be greatly shaken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 62,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Asa went out to meet him, and they drew up their lines of battle in the Valley of Zephathah at Mareshah. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 14,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Lord will rescue me from every evil deed and bring me safely into his heavenly kingdom. To him be the glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If this be so, our God whom we serve is able to deliver us from the burning fiery furnace, and he will deliver us out of your hand, O king. But if not, be it known to you, O king, that we will not serve your gods or worship the golden image that you have set up.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 3,17.18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut. I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The haughty looks of man shall be brought low, and the lofty pride of men shall be humbled, and the Lord alone will be exalted in that day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God shows no partiality. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And behold, now I bring the first of the fruit of the ground, which you, O Lord, have given me.’ And you shall set it down before the Lord your God and worship before the Lord your God. And you shall rejoice in all the good that the Lord your God has given to you and to your house, you, and the Levite, and the sojourner who is among you.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 26,10.11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Arise, shine, for your light has come, and the glory of the Lord has risen upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you are all children of light, children of the day. We are not of the night or of the darkness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They shall not hurt or destroy in all my holy mountain; for the earth shall be full of the knowledge of the Lord as the waters cover the sea. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is good, and it is pleasing in the sight of God our Savior, who desires all people to be saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They will perish, but you will remain; they will all wear out like a garment. You will change them like a robe, and they will pass away, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 102,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said with a loud voice, “Fear God and give him glory, because the hour of his judgment has come, and worship him who made heaven and earth, the sea and the springs of water.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 14,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But my eyes are toward you, O God, my Lord; in you I seek refuge; leave me not defenseless! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 141,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he was in the stern, asleep on the cushion. And they woke him and said to him, “Teacher, do you not care that we are perishing?”
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The lot is cast into the lap, but its every decision is from the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Are not two sparrows sold for a penny? And not one of them will fall to the ground apart from your Father.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And as for me, this is my covenant with them,” says the Lord: “My Spirit that is upon you, and my words that I have put in your mouth, shall not depart out of your mouth, or out of the mouth of your offspring, or out of the mouth of your children’s offspring,” says the Lord, “from this time forth and forevermore.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Keep a close watch on yourself and on the teaching. Persist in this, for by so doing you will save both yourself and your hearers. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh, taste and see that the Lord is good! Blessed is the man who takes refuge in him! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But during the night an angel of the Lord opened the prison doors and brought them out, and said, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>The fear of the Lord is instruction in wisdom, and humility comes before honor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who is wise and understanding among you? By his good conduct let him show his works in the meekness of wisdom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord said to Samuel, “Do not look on his appearance or on the height of his stature, because I have rejected him. For the Lord sees not as man sees: man looks on the outward appearance, but the Lord looks on the heart.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 16,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the angel said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favor with God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Praise the Lord! Oh give thanks to the Lord, for he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 106,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will put my Spirit within you, and you shall live, and I will place you in your own land. Then you shall know that I am the Lord; I have spoken, and I will do it, declares the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the crowds learned it, they followed him, and he welcomed them and spoke to them of the kingdom of God and cured those who had need of healing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For still the vision awaits its appointed time; it hastens to the end—it will not lie. If it seems slow, wait for it; it will surely come; it will not delay. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You also, be patient. Establish your hearts, for the coming of the Lord is at hand. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And if you faithfully obey the voice of the Lord your God, being careful to do all his commandments that I command you today, the Lord your God will set you high above all the nations of the earth. Blessed shall you be when you come in, and blessed shall you be when you go out.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 28,1.6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>fully convinced that God was able to do what he had promised. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 4,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Turn to him from whom people have deeply revolted, O children of Israel. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 31,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the law came in to increase the trespass, but where sin increased, grace abounded all the more, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Praise him for his mighty deeds; praise him according to his excellent greatness! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 150,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Glory to God in the highest, and on earth peace among those with whom he is pleased!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>if you pour yourself out for the hungry and satisfy the desire of the afflicted, then shall your light rise in the darkness and your gloom be as the noonday. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“When a stranger sojourns with you in your land, you shall not do him wrong. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore welcome one another as Christ has welcomed you, for the glory of God.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I spread out my hands all the day to a rebellious people, who walk in a way that is not good, following their own devices; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he arose and came to his father. But while he was still a long way off, his father saw him and felt compassion, and ran and embraced him and kissed him. And the son said to him, ‘Father, I have sinned against heaven and before you. I am no longer worthy to be called your son.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Heiliger Abend</Sonntag><Losungstext>but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>She will bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 1,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>And David and all Israel were celebrating before God with all their might, with song and lyres and harps and tambourines and cymbals and trumpets. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 13,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the shepherds returned, glorifying and praising God for all they had heard and seen, as it had been told them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Even the stork in the heavens knows her times, and the turtledove, swallow, and crane keep the time of their coming, but my people know not the rules of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it.
 </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then the Lord said to him, “Who has made man’s mouth? Who makes him mute, or deaf, or seeing, or blind? Is it not I, the Lord?
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 4,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you that you should go and bear fruit and that your fruit should abide, so that whatever you ask the Father in my name, he may give it to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the people said to Joshua, “The Lord our God we will serve, and his voice we will obey.”
 </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, my beloved brothers, be steadfast, immovable, always abounding in the work of the Lord, knowing that in the Lord your labor is not in vain. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,58</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He changes times and seasons; he removes kings and sets up kings; he gives wisdom to the wise and knowledge to those who have understanding; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>That evening they brought to him many who were oppressed by demons, and he cast out the spirits with a word and healed all who were sick. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2015-12-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Altjahrsabend</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then those who feared the Lord spoke with one another. The Lord paid attention and heard them, and a book of remembrance was written before him of those who feared the Lord and esteemed his name.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 3,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen></FreeXml>