<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><FreeXml><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>for God gave us a spirit not of fear but of power and love and self-control. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Timothy 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>And whenever you stand praying, forgive, if you have anything against anyone, so that your Father also who is in heaven may forgive you your trespasses.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Mark 11,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>John 15,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>Like newborn infants, long for the pure spiritual milk, that by it you may grow up into salvation— But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Peter 2.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>Do you not know that your bodies are temples of the Holy Spirit, who is in you, whom you have received from God? You are not your own</Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Corinthians 6,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation; this is my God, and I will praise him, my father’s God, and I will exalt him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 15,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The Lord.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>Salt is good, but if the salt has lost its saltiness, how will you make it salty again? Have salt in yourselves, and be at peace with one another.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Mark 9,50</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>the Lord appeared to him from far away. I have loved you with an everlasting love; therefore I have continued my faithfulness to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Corinthians 3,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>And we have the prophetic word more fully confirmed, to which you will do well to pay attention as to a lamp shining in a dark place, until the day dawns and the morning star rises in your hearts, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Peter 1,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>my soul waits for the Lord more than watchmen for the morning, more than watchmen for the morning. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 130,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext/><Lehrtextvers> </Lehrtextvers></Losungen></FreeXml>