<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><FreeXml><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>Give thanks to the Lord of lords, for his steadfast love endures forever; to him who alone does great wonders, for his steadfast love endures forever; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 136,3.4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He restores my soul. He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 23,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag><Losungstext>Oh come, let us worship and bow down; let us kneel before the Lord, our Maker! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 95,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Search me, O God, and know my heart! Try me and know my thoughts! And see if there be any grievous way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 139,23-24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith—that you, being rooted and grounded in love, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Satisfy us in the morning with your steadfast love, that we may rejoice and be glad all our days. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 90,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And early in the morning all the people came to him in the temple to hear him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Epiphanias (Erscheinungsfest)</Sonntag><Losungstext>The north and the south, you have created them; Tabor and Hermon joyously praise your name. You have a mighty arm; strong is your hand, high your right hand.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 89,12-13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things were created through him and for him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>All the nations you have made shall come and worship before you, O Lord, and shall glorify your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 86,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sow for yourselves righteousness; reap steadfast love; break up your fallow ground, for it is the time to seek the Lord, that he may come and rain righteousness upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And those who know your name put their trust in you, for you, O Lord, have not forsaken those who seek you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities. For when I am weak, then I am strong. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>And I will give them one heart, and a new spirit I will put within them. I will remove the heart of stone from their flesh and give them a heart of flesh, that they may walk in my statutes and keep my rules and obey them. And they shall be my people, and I will be their God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 11,19.20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Delight yourself in the Lord, and he will give you the desires of your heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 37,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore I tell you, whatever you ask in prayer, believe that you have received it, and it will be yours. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 11,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The God of Israel has spoken; the Rock of Israel has said to me: When one rules justly over men, ruling in the fear of God, he dawns on them like the morning light, like the sun shining forth on a cloudless morning, like rain that makes grass to sprout from the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 23,3-4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Pay careful attention to yourselves and to all the flock, in which the Holy Spirit has made you overseers, to care for the church of God, which he obtained with his own blood. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 20,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When he calls to me, I will answer him; I will be with him in trouble; I will rescue him and honor him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and deliver all those who through fear of death were subject to lifelong slavery. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And no inhabitant will say, “I am sick”; the people who dwell there will be forgiven their iniquity. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus saw their faith, he said to the paralytic, “Son, your sins are forgiven.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, O Lord, know me; you see me, and test my heart toward you. Pull them out like sheep for the slaughter, and set them apart for the day of slaughter. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 12,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not pronounce judgment before the time, before the Lord comes, who will bring to light the things now hidden in darkness and will disclose the purposes of the heart. Then each one will receive his commendation from God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall have no other gods before me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“No one can serve two masters, for either he will hate the one and love the other, or he will be devoted to the one and despise the other. You cannot serve God and money. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will feast the soul of the priests with abundance, and my people shall be satisfied with my goodness, declares the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that having all sufficiency in all things at all times, you may abound in every good work. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord, who makes a way in the sea, a path in the mighty waters, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But overhearing what they said, Jesus said to the ruler of the synagogue, “Do not fear, only believe.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not put the Lord your God to the test, as you tested him at Massah. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“If you love me, you will keep my commandments. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord drove out before us all the peoples, the Amorites who lived in the land. Therefore we also will serve the Lord, for he is our God.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is how one should regard us, as servants of Christ and stewards of the mysteries of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But we your people, the sheep of your pasture, will give thanks to you forever; from generation to generation we will recount your praise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 79,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh give thanks to the Lord; call upon his name; make known his deeds among the peoples! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that we may preach the gospel in lands beyond you, without boasting of work already done in another’s area of influence.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 10,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Anxiety in a man’s heart weighs him down, but a good word makes him glad. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 12,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Septuagesimae (70 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>By your favor, O Lord, you made my mountain stand strong; you hid your face; I was dismayed. To you, O Lord, I cry, and to the Lord I plead for mercy: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 30,7.8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise, you who are younger, be subject to the elders. Clothe yourselves, all of you, with humility toward one another, for “God opposes the proud but gives grace to the humble.” Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God so that at the proper time he may exalt you, casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,5-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>he will bless those who fear the Lord, both the small and the great. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 115,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And at the time for the banquet he sent his servant to say to those who had been invited, ‘Come, for everything is now ready.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You visit the earth and water it; you greatly enrich it; the river of God is full of water; you provide their grain, for so you have prepared it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 65,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then he brought them up into his house and set food before them. And he rejoiced along with his entire household that he had believed in God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You gave your good Spirit to instruct them and did not withhold your manna from their mouth and gave them water for their thirst. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now we have received not the spirit of the world, but the Spirit who is from God, that we might understand the things freely given us by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 2,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said to Moses, “See, I have made you like God to Pharaoh, and your brother Aaron shall be your prophet. You shall speak all that I command you, and your brother Aaron shall tell Pharaoh to let the people of Israel go out of his land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 7,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And now, Lord, look upon their threats and grant to your servants to continue to speak your word with all boldness, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Justice, and only justice, you shall follow, that you may live and inherit the land that the Lord your God is giving you.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 16,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But as for you, O man of God, flee these things. Pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, steadfastness, gentleness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord of hosts: In those days ten men from the nations of every tongue shall take hold of the robe of a Jew, saying, ‘Let us go with you, for we have heard that God is with you.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now among those who went up to worship at the feast were some Greeks. So these came to Philip, who was from Bethsaida in Galilee, and asked him, “Sir, we wish to see Jesus.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-01-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Sexagesimae (60 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“For from the least to the greatest of them, everyone is greedy for unjust gain; and from prophet to priest, everyone deals falsely. They have healed the wound of my people lightly, saying, ‘Peace, peace,’ when there is no peace. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 6,13-14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>just as I try to please everyone in everything I do, not seeking my own advantage, but that of many, that they may be saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I prayed to the Lord, ‘O Lord God, do not destroy your people and your heritage, whom you have redeemed through your greatness, whom you have brought out of Egypt with a mighty hand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 9,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>when God arose to establish judgment, to save all the humble of the earth. Surely the wrath of man shall praise you; the remnant of wrath you will put on like a belt. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 76,9-10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the eyes of the Lord are on the righteous, and his ears are open to their prayer. But the face of the Lord is against those who do evil.”  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord of hosts has purposed, and who will annul it? His hand is stretched out, and who will turn it back? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 14,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord is righteous in all his ways and kind in all his works. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 145,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who will not fear, O Lord, and glorify your name? For you alone are holy. All nations will come and worship you, for your righteous acts have been revealed.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now then, let the fear of the Lord be upon you. Be careful what you do, for there is no injustice with the Lord our God, or partiality or taking bribes.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 19,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And as Jesus reclined at table in the house, behold, many tax collectors and sinners came and were reclining with Jesus and his disciples. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then David said to Solomon his son, “Be strong and courageous and do it. Do not be afraid and do not be dismayed, for the Lord God, even my God, is with you. He will not leave you or forsake you, until all the work for the service of the house of the Lord is finished. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 28,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Think over what I say, for the Lord will give you understanding in everything.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Estomihi (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Trust in the Lord with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,5-6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit by itself, unless it abides in the vine, neither can you, unless you abide in me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>On the eighth day he sent the people away, and they blessed the king and went to their homes joyful and glad of heart for all the goodness that the Lord had shown to David his servant and to Israel his people.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,66</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For it is all for your sake, so that as grace extends to more and more people it may increase thanksgiving, to the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The eyes of all look to you, and you give them their food in due season. You open your hand; you satisfy the desire of every living thing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 145,15-16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Look at the birds of the air: they neither sow nor reap nor gather into barns, and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not of more value than they? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you are not a God who delights in wickedness; evil may not dwell with you.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 5,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And rising very early in the morning, while it was still dark, he departed and went out to a desolate place, and there he prayed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will sing to the Lord, because he has dealt bountifully with me.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 13,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Mary said, “My soul magnifies the Lord, and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,46-47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> Say to your brothers, “You are my people,” and to your sisters, “You have received mercy.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But to all who did receive him, who believed in his name, he gave the right to become children of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for justice will return to the righteous, and all the upright in heart will follow it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 94,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Of David. The Lord is my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? The Lord is the stronghold of my life; of whom shall I be afraid? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 27,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I can do all things through him who strengthens me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But he said to her, “You speak as one of the foolish women would speak. Shall we receive good from God, and shall we not receive evil?” In all this Job did not sin with his lips. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 2,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Incline your ear, and come to me; hear, that your soul may live; and I will make with you an everlasting covenant, my steadfast, sure love for David. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In the same way also he took the cup, after supper, saying, “This cup is the new covenant in my blood. Do this, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of me.”  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 11,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For a majority of the people, many of them from Ephraim, Manasseh, Issachar, and Zebulun, had not cleansed themselves, yet they ate the Passover otherwise than as prescribed. For Hezekiah had prayed for them, saying, “May the good Lord pardon everyone who sets his heart to seek God, the Lord, the God of his fathers, even though not according to the sanctuary’s rules of cleanness.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 30,18.19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, there was a man named Zacchaeus. He was a chief tax collector and was rich.  And he was seeking to see who Jesus was, but on account of the crowd he could not, because he was small in stature. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,2-3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Declare his glory among the nations, his marvelous works among all the peoples!  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 96,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when they arrived and gathered the church together, they declared all that God had done with them, and how he had opened a door of faith to the Gentiles. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>God settles the solitary in a home; he leads out the prisoners to prosperity, but the rebellious dwell in a parched land. O God, when you went out before your people, when you marched through the wilderness, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 68,6-7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the King will answer them, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have I not commanded you? Be strong and courageous. Do not be frightened, and do not be dismayed, for the Lord your God is with you wherever you go.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 1,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for God gave us a spirit not of fear but of power and love and self-control. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Reminiszere (Gedenke, HERR, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag><Losungstext>God is in the midst of her; she shall not be moved; God will help her when morning dawns. The nations rage, the kingdoms totter; he utters his voice, the earth melts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 46,5-6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In him you also are being built together into a dwelling place for God by the Spirit. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were. Our days on the earth are like a shadow, and there is no abiding. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For here we have no lasting city, but we seek the city that is to come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For as the earth brings forth its sprouts, and as a garden causes what is sown in it to sprout up, so the Lord God will cause righteousness and praise to sprout up before all the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who supplies seed to the sower and bread for food will supply and multiply your seed for sowing and increase the harvest of your righteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then I will teach transgressors your ways, and sinners will return to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Even before a word is on my tongue, behold, O Lord, you know it altogether. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 139,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“And when you pray, do not heap up empty phrases as the Gentiles do, for they think that they will be heard for their many words. Do not be like them, for your Father knows what you need before you ask him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,7-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who are wise in their own eyes, and shrewd in their own sight! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And if I have prophetic powers, and understand all mysteries and all knowledge, and if I have all faith, so as to remove mountains, but have not love, I am nothing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now you have been pleased to bless the house of your servant, that it may continue forever before you, for it is you, O Lord, who have blessed, and it is blessed forever.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 17,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Okuli (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den HERRN. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>For I, the Lord your God, hold your right hand; it is I who say to you, “Fear not, I am the one who helps you.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now Simon’s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her. And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,30-31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-02-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Correct me, O Lord, but in justice; not in your anger, lest you bring me to nothing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the moment all discipline seems painful rather than pleasant, but later it yields the peaceful fruit of righteousness to those who have been trained by it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be strong, and let your heart take courage, all you who wait for the Lord!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And you will be hated by all for my name’s sake. But the one who endures to the end will be saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him who brings good news, who publishes peace, who brings good news of happiness, who publishes salvation, who says to Zion, “Your God reigns.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 52,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and, as shoes for your feet, having put on the readiness given by the gospel of peace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who is this who comes from Edom, in crimsoned garments from Bozrah, he who is splendid in his apparel, marching in the greatness of his strength? “It is I, speaking in righteousness, mighty to save.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, as one trespass led to condemnation for all men, so one act of righteousness leads to justification and life for all men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>then hear in heaven your dwelling place and forgive and act and render to each whose heart you know, according to all his ways (for you, you only, know the hearts of all the children of mankind), </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,39</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But I said, “I have labored in vain; I have spent my strength for nothing and vanity; yet surely my right is with the Lord, and my recompense with my God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said, “The kingdom of God is as if a man should scatter seed on the ground. He sleeps and rises night and day, and the seed sprouts and grows; he knows not how. The earth produces by itself, first the blade, then the ear, then the full grain in the ear.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,26-28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag><Losungstext>But go, act, be strong for the battle. Why should you suppose that God will cast you down before the enemy? For God has power to help or to cast down.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus by command of God our Savior and of Christ Jesus our hope, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Honor your father and your mother, that your days may be long in the land that the Lord your God is giving you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But if a widow has children or grandchildren, let them first learn to show godliness to their own household and to make some return to their parents, for this is pleasing in the sight of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 5,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The Lord.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,12-13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For as the new heavens and the new earth that I make shall remain before me, says the Lord, so shall your offspring and your name remain. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He is not greater in this house than I am, nor has he kept back anything from me except you, because you are his wife. How then can I do this great wickedness and sin against God?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 39,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but Christ is faithful over God’s house as a son. And we are his house if indeed we hold fast our confidence and our boasting in our hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 3,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>that people may know, from the rising of the sun and from the west, that there is none besides me; I am the Lord, and there is no other. I form light and create darkness, I make well-being and create calamity, I am the Lord, who does all these things. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,6-7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God, who said, “Let light shine out of darkness,” has shone in our hearts to give the light of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who have made me see many troubles and calamities will revive me again; from the depths of the earth you will bring me up again. You will increase my greatness and comfort me again.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,20-21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when he saw the wind, he was afraid, and beginning to sink he cried out, “Lord, save me.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Judika (Gott, schaffe mir Recht! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>But, O Lord of hosts, who judges righteously, who tests the heart and the mind, let me see your vengeance upon them, for to you have I committed my cause. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 11,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For to this you have been called, because Christ also suffered for you, leaving you an example, so that you might follow in his steps. When he was reviled, he did not revile in return; when he suffered, he did not threaten, but continued entrusting himself to him who judges justly. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,21.23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is better to take refuge in the Lord than to trust in man. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Like an eagle that stirs up its nest, that flutters over its young, spreading out its wings, catching them, bearing them on its pinions, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not plan evil against your neighbor, who dwells trustingly beside you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then, as we have opportunity, let us do good to everyone, and especially to those who are of the household of faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Many bulls encompass me; strong bulls of Bashan surround me; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Let not your hearts be troubled. Believe in God; believe also in me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For as the rain and the snow come down from heaven and do not return there but water the earth, making it bring forth and sprout, giving seed to the sower and bread to the eater, so shall my word be that goes out from my mouth; it shall not return to me empty, but it shall accomplish that which I purpose, and shall succeed in the thing for which I sent it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,10-11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But those that were sown on the good soil are the ones who hear the word and accept it and bear fruit, thirtyfold and sixtyfold and a hundredfold.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Fear not, for you will not be ashamed; be not confounded, for you will not be disgraced; for you will forget the shame of your youth, and the reproach of your widowhood you will remember no more. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet if anyone suffers as a Christian, let him not be ashamed, but let him glorify God in that name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Palmsonntag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For our transgressions are multiplied before you, and our sins testify against us; for our transgressions are with us, and we know our iniquities:  transgressing, and denying the Lord, and turning back from following our God, speaking oppression and revolt, conceiving and uttering from the heart lying words. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,12-13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>that this is God, our God forever and ever. He will guide us forever</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 48,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,12-13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yours, O Lord, is the greatness and the power and the glory and the victory and the majesty, for all that is in the heavens and in the earth is yours. Yours is the kingdom, O Lord, and you are exalted as head above all. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But we see him who for a little while was made lower than the angels, namely Jesus, crowned with glory and honor because of the suffering of death, so that by the grace of God he might taste death for everyone. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he is our God, and we are the people of his pasture, and the sheep of his hand. Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts, as at Meribah, as on the day at Massah in the wilderness, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 95,7-8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But be doers of the word, and not hearers only, deceiving yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>The name of the second he called Ephraim, “For God has made me fruitful in the land of my affliction.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 41,52</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “My soul is very sorrowful, even to death. Remain here and watch.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 14,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For I said, “Steadfast love will be built up forever; in the heavens you will establish your faithfulness.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 89,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that is, in Christ God was reconciling the world to himself, not counting their trespasses against them, and entrusting to us the message of reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>let your ear be attentive and your eyes open, to hear the prayer of your servant that I now pray before you day and night for the people of Israel your servants, confessing the sins of the people of Israel, which we have sinned against you. Even I and my father’s house have sinned. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 1,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I am no longer in the world, but they are in the world, and I am coming to you. Holy Father, keep them in your name, which you have given me, that they may be one, even as we are one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Send out your light and your truth; let them lead me; let them bring me to your holy hill and to your dwelling! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 43,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But in fact Christ has been raised from the dead, the firstfruits of those who have fallen asleep. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Restore us, O Lord God of hosts! Let your face shine, that we may be saved! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 80,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and which now has been manifested through the appearing of our Savior Christ Jesus, who abolished death and brought life and immortality to light through the gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfills his purpose for me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 57,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the evening of that day, the first day of the week, the doors being locked where the disciples were for fear of the Jews, Jesus came and stood among them and said to them, “Peace be with you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 20,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To you, O Lord, belongs righteousness, but to us open shame, as at this day, to the men of Judah, to the inhabitants of Jerusalem, and to all Israel, those who are near and those who are far away, in all the lands to which you have driven them, because of the treachery that they have committed against you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 9,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“What do you think? A man had two sons. And he went to the first and said, ‘Son, go and work in the vineyard today.’ And he answered, ‘I will not,’ but afterward he changed his mind and went. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 21,28-29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-03-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not let my heart incline to any evil, to busy myself with wicked deeds in company with men who work iniquity, and let me not eat of their delicacies! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 141,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So whoever knows the right thing to do and fails to do it, for him it is sin. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 4,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord my God, I cried to you for help, and you have healed me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 30,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For as we share abundantly in Christ’s sufferings, so through Christ we share abundantly in comfort too. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord of hosts is with us; the God of Jacob is our fortress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 46,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Come away by yourselves to a desolate place and rest a while.” For many were coming and going, and they had no leisure even to eat. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the Lord is our judge; the Lord is our lawgiver; the Lord is our king; he will save us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And it shall come to pass that as I have watched over them to pluck up and break down, to overthrow, destroy, and bring harm, so I will watch over them to build and to plant, declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I planted, Apollos watered, but God gave the growth. So neither he who plants nor he who waters is anything, but only God who gives the growth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord will save me, and we will play my music on stringed instruments all the days of our lives, at the house of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,57</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Spirit of the Lord God is upon me, because the Lord has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the Lord’s favor, and the day of vengeance of our God; to comfort all who mourn; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>[[Now when he rose early on the first day of the week, he appeared first to Mary Magdalene, from whom he had cast out seven demons. She went and told those who had been with him, as they mourned and wept. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you have rejected us and disgraced us and have not gone out with our armies. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 44,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing Psalm and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is the Lord who goes before you. He will be with you; he will not leave you or forsake you. Do not fear or be dismayed.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 31,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers,  nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,38.39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My foot stands on level ground; in the great assembly I will bless the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 26,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, praising God and having favor with all the people. And the Lord added to their number day by day those who were being saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,46-47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Blessed be the Lord who has given rest to his people Israel, according to all that he promised. Not one word has failed of all his good promise, which he spoke by Moses his servant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,56</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who calls you is faithful; he will surely do it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Bring the full tithe into the storehouse, that there may be food in my house. And thereby put me to the test, says the Lord of hosts, if I will not open the windows of heaven for you and pour down for you a blessing until there is no more need. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 3,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The point is this: whoever sows sparingly will also reap sparingly, and whoever sows bountifully will also reap bountifully. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For behold, he who forms the mountains and creates the wind, and declares to man what is his thought, who makes the morning darkness, and treads on the heights of the earth— the Lord, the God of hosts, is his name! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 4,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And in the morning, ‘It will be stormy today, for the sky is red and threatening.’ You know how to interpret the appearance of the sky, but you cannot interpret the signs of the times. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For our heart is glad in him, because we trust in his holy name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, preparing your minds for action, and being sober-minded, set your hope fully on the grace that will be brought to you at the revelation of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said: “Because this people draw near with their mouth and honor me with their lips, while their hearts are far from me, and their fear of me is a commandment taught by men, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For whoever does the will of God, he is my brother and sister and mother.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 3,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For if you return to the Lord, your brothers and your children will find compassion with their captors and return to this land. For the Lord your God is gracious and merciful and will not turn away his face from you, if you return to him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 30,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Repent therefore, and turn back, that your sins may be blotted out, that times of refreshing may come from the presence of the Lord, and that he may send the Christ appointed for you, Jesus, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 3,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deliver my soul from the sword, my precious life from the power of the dog! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out and say, “Jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me!” And many rebuked him, telling him to be silent. But he cried out all the more, “Son of David, have mercy on me!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,47-48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>O my Strength, I will sing praises to you, for you, O God, are my fortress, the God who shows me steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 59,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And in the days of those kings the God of heaven will set up a kingdom that shall never be destroyed, nor shall the kingdom be left to another people. It shall break in pieces all these kingdoms and bring them to an end, and it shall stand forever, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,44</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard a loud voice in heaven, saying, “Now the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God and the authority of his Christ have come, for the accuser of our brothers has been thrown down, who accuses them day and night before our God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord is good; his steadfast love endures forever, and his faithfulness to all generations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 100,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>All this is from God, who through Christ reconciled us to himself and gave us the ministry of reconciliation; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore say to them, Thus declares the Lord of hosts: Return to me, says the Lord of hosts, and I will return to you, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 1,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Give attention to me, my people, and give ear to me, my nation; for a law will go out from me, and I will set my justice for a light to the peoples. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is good, and it is pleasing in the sight of God our Savior, who desires all people to be saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I made the earth and created man on it; it was my hands that stretched out the heavens, and I commanded all their host. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song of the Lamb, saying, “Great and amazing are your deeds, O Lord God the Almighty! Just and true are your ways, O King of the nations! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hatred stirs up strife, but love covers all offenses. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Love is patient and kind; love does not envy or boast; it is not arrogant or rude. It does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice at wrongdoing, but rejoices with the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,4-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Kantate (Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>With weeping they shall come, and with pleas for mercy I will lead them back, I will make them walk by brooks of water, in a straight path in which they shall not stumble, for I am a father to Israel, and Ephraim is my firstborn. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So also you have sorrow now, but I will see you again, and your hearts will rejoice, and no one will take your joy from you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>remember the former things of old; for I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me,  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 46,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>yet for us there is one God, the Father, from whom are all things and for whom we exist, and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and through whom we exist. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Does not he see my ways and number all my steps? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 31,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let not your mouth lead you into sin, and do not say before the messenger that it was a mistake. Why should God be angry at your voice and destroy the work of your hands? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 5,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But avoid foolish controversies, genealogies, dissensions, and quarrels about the law, for they are unprofitable and worthless. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are my help and my deliverer; do not delay, O my God!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And taking the five loaves and the two fish he looked up to heaven and said a blessing and broke the loaves and gave them to the disciples to set before the people. And he divided the two fish among them all. And they all ate and were satisfied.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,41-42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I will not contend forever, nor will I always be angry; for the spirit would grow faint before me, and the breath of life that I made. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who saved us and called us to a holy calling, not because of our works but because of his own purpose and grace, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before the ages began, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-04-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“He found him in a desert land, and in the howling waste of the wilderness; he encircled him, he cared for him, he kept him as the apple of his eye. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we have come to know and to believe the love that God has for us. God is love, and whoever abides in love abides in God, and God abides in him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will give them a heart to know that I am the Lord, and they shall be my people and I will be their God, for they shall return to me with their whole heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 24,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember Jesus Christ, risen from the dead, the offspring of David, as preached in my gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore I will divide him a portion with the many, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong, because he poured out his soul to death and was numbered with the transgressors; yet he bore the sin of many, and makes intercession for the transgressors. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For our sake he made him to be sin who knew no sin, so that in him we might become the righteousness of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, open my lips, and my mouth will declare your praise.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and saying, “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Glad songs of salvation are in the tents of the righteous: “The right hand of the Lord does valiantly, the right hand of the Lord exalts, the right hand of the Lord does valiantly!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,15.16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then the righteous will shine like the sun in the kingdom of their Father. He who has ears, let him hear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,43</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Himmelfahrt des Herrn</Sonntag><Losungstext>Therefore we will not fear though the earth gives way, though the mountains be moved into the heart of the sea, though its waters roar and foam, though the mountains tremble at its swelling. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 46,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A soft answer turns away wrath, but a harsh word stirs up anger. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Lord’s servant must not be quarrelsome but kind to everyone, able to teach, patiently enduring evil, correcting his opponents with gentleness. God may perhaps grant them repentance leading to a knowledge of the truth, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,24-25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then once more you shall see the distinction between the righteous and the wicked, between one who serves God and one who does not serve him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 3,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Sing to the Lord; praise the Lord! For he has delivered the life of the needy from the hand of evildoers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 20,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will establish my covenant with you, and you shall know that I am the Lord, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 16,62</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>because of the hope laid up for you in heaven. Of this you have heard before in the word of the truth, the gospel, which has come to you, as indeed in the whole world it is bearing fruit and increasing—as it also does among you, since the day you heard it and understood the grace of God in truth, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And as you have been a byword of cursing among the nations, O house of Judah and house of Israel, so will I save you, and you shall be a blessing. Fear not, but let your hands be strong.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Not that we are sufficient in ourselves to claim anything as coming from us, but our sufficiency is from God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall suck the milk of nations; you shall nurse at the breast of kings; and you shall know that I, the Lord, am your Savior and your Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Taking her by the hand he said to her, “Talitha cumi,” which means, “Little girl, I say to you, arise.” And immediately the girl got up and began walking (for she was twelve years of age), and they were immediately overcome with amazement.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,41-42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said to Joshua, “Do not fear and do not be dismayed. Take all the fighting men with you, and arise, go up to Ai. See, I have given into your hand the king of Ai, and his people, his city, and his land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 8,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Fight the good fight of the faith. Take hold of the eternal life to which you were called and about which you made the good confession in the presence of many witnesses. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But with you there is forgiveness, that you may be feared. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 130,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But if we walk in the light, as he is in the light, we have fellowship with one another, and the blood of Jesus his Son cleanses us from all sin. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And you shall not covet your neighbor’s wife. And you shall not desire your neighbor’s house, his field, or his male servant, or his female servant, his ox, or his donkey, or anything that is your neighbor’s.’  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this is the will of God, your sanctification: that you abstain from sexual immorality; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be led away by diverse and strange teachings, for it is good for the heart to be strengthened by grace, not by foods, which have not benefited those devoted to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>And I will put this third into the fire, and refine them as one refines silver, and test them as gold is tested. They will call upon my name, and I will answer them. I will say, ‘They are my people’; and they will say, ‘The Lord is my God.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 13,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you were straying like sheep, but have now returned to the Shepherd and Overseer of your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but you shall be called the priests of the Lord; they shall speak of you as the ministers of our God; you shall eat the wealth of the nations, and in their glory you shall boast. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this reason I remind you to fan into flame the gift of God, which is in you through the laying on of my hands, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Speak to all the congregation of the people of Israel and say to them, You shall be holy, for I the Lord your God am holy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and to put on the new self, created after the likeness of God in true righteousness and holiness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A voice says, “Cry!” And I said, “What shall I cry?” All flesh is grass, and all its beauty is like the flower of the field. The grass withers, the flower fades, but the word of our God will stand forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,6.8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not spread a false report. You shall not join hands with a wicked man to be a malicious witness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 23,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, having put away falsehood, let each one of you speak the truth with his neighbor, for we are members one of another. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord of hosts, blessed is the one who trusts in you! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 84,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not be anxious, saying, ‘What shall we eat?’ or ‘What shall we drink?’ or ‘What shall we wear?’  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag><Losungstext>The inhabitants of one city shall go to another, saying, ‘Let us go at once to entreat the favor of the Lord and to seek the Lord of hosts; I myself am going.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For through him we both have access in one Spirit to the Father. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall stand up before the gray head and honor the face of an old man, and you shall fear your God: I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Love one another with brotherly affection. Outdo one another in showing honor. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who decree iniquitous decrees, and the writers who keep writing oppression, to turn aside the needy from justice and to rob the poor of my people of their right, that widows may be their spoil, and that they may make the fatherless their prey! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 10,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be unequally yoked with unbelievers. For what partnership has righteousness with lawlessness? Or what fellowship has light with darkness? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he will command his angels concerning you to guard you in all your ways. On their hands they will bear you up, lest you strike your foot against a stone. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Lord stood by me and strengthened me, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. So I was rescued from the lion’s mouth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And you will say in that day: “Give thanks to the Lord, call upon his name, make known his deeds among the peoples, proclaim that his name is exalted. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 12,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Go into all the world and proclaim the gospel to the whole creation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let not the downtrodden turn back in shame; let the poor and needy praise your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 74,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He has redeemed my soul from going down into the pit, and my life shall look upon the light.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 33,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And God raised the Lord and will also raise us up by his power. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 6,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>I stretch out my hands to you; my soul thirsts for you like a parched land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 143,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>God said to Moses, “I am who I am.” And he said, “Say this to the people of Israel, ‘I am has sent me to you.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 3,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-05-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed are they who observe justice, who do righteousness at all times! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 106,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“This is my commandment, that you love one another as I have loved you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I gave them my statutes and made known to them my rules, by which, if a person does them, he shall live. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus answered him, “If anyone loves me, he will keep my word, and my Father will love him, and we will come to him and make our home with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Say to them, As I live, declares the Lord God, I have no pleasure in the death of the wicked, but that the wicked turn from his way and live; turn back, turn back from your evil ways, for why will you die, O house of Israel? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 33,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Just so, I tell you, there will be more joy in heaven over one sinner who repents than over ninety-nine righteous persons who need no repentance. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed are those who dwell in your house, ever singing your praise! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 84,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But I will have mercy on the house of Judah, and I will save them by the Lord their God. I will not save them by bow or by sword or by war or by horses or by horsemen.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then it depends not on human will or exertion, but on God, who has mercy.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>And he said to him, “If your presence will not go with me, do not bring us up from here. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the Spirit of truth comes, he will guide you into all the truth, for he will not speak on his own authority, but whatever he hears he will speak, and he will declare to you the things that are to come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who join house to house, who add field to field, until there is no more room, and you are made to dwell alone in the midst of the land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness, for one’s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You make known to me the path of life; in your presence there is fullness of joy; at your right hand are pleasures forevermore. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 16,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the Lord opens the eyes of the blind. The Lord lifts up those who are bowed down; the Lord loves the righteous. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 7,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>We must all die; we are like water spilled on the ground, which cannot be gathered up again. But God will not take away life, and he devises means so that the banished one will not remain an outcast. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 14,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the scribes of the Pharisees, when they saw that he was eating with sinners and tax collectors, said to his disciples, “Why does he eat with tax collectors and sinners?” And when Jesus heard it, he said to them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick. I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>‘O Lord God, you have only begun to show your servant your greatness and your mighty hand. For what god is there in heaven or on earth who can do such works and mighty acts as yours? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 3,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who can discern his errors? Declare me innocent from hidden faults. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 19,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Take care then how you hear, for to the one who has, more will be given, and from the one who has not, even what he thinks that he has will be taken away.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Teach me to do your will, for you are my God! Let your good Spirit lead me on level ground! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 143,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but whoever drinks of the water that I will give him will never be thirsty again. The water that I will give him will become in him a spring of water welling up to eternal life.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Commit your way to the Lord; trust in him, and he will act. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 37,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he answered and said, “Must I not take care to speak what the Lord puts in my mouth?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 23,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for we cannot but speak of what we have seen and heard.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the Lord—knows the thoughts of man, that they are but a breath. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 94,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Live in harmony with one another. Do not be haughty, but associate with the lowly. Never be wise in your own sight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let the prophet who has a dream tell the dream, but let him who has my word speak my word faithfully. What has straw in common with wheat? declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Beloved, do not believe every spirit, but test the spirits to see whether they are from God, for many false prophets have gone out into the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And this city shall be to me a name of joy, a praise and a glory before all the nations of the earth who shall hear of all the good that I do for them. They shall fear and tremble because of all the good and all the prosperity I provide for it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I tell you that Christ became a servant to the circumcised to show God’s truthfulness, in order to confirm the promises given to the patriarchs, and in order that the Gentiles might glorify God for his mercy. As it is written, “Therefore I will praise you among the Gentiles, and sing to your name.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: “Heaven is my throne, and the earth is my footstool; what is the house that you would build for me, and what is the place of my rest? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And then if anyone says to you, ‘Look, here is the Christ!’ or ‘Look, there he is!’ do not believe it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For though the Lord is high, he regards the lowly, but the haughty he knows from afar. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 138,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>know therefore today, and lay it to your heart, that the Lord is God in heaven above and on the earth beneath; there is no other. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,39</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that they should seek God, and perhaps feel their way toward him and find him. Yet he is actually not far from each one of us, for “‘In him we live and move and have our being’; as even some of your own poets have said, “‘For we are indeed his offspring.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,27-28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And now, Israel, what does the Lord your God require of you, but to fear the Lord your God, to walk in all his ways, to love him, to serve the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but whoever keeps his word, in him truly the love of God is perfected. By this we may know that we are in him: </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You gave a wide place for my steps under me, and my feet did not slip. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 18,36</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God does not consist in talk but in power. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Johannistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>I sought the Lord, and he answered me and delivered me from all my fears. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>There was a man sent from God, whose name was John. He came as a witness, to bear witness about the light, that all might believe through him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the steadfast love of the Lord is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear him, and his righteousness to children’s children, to those who keep his covenant and remember to do his commandments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 103,17-18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>And the Lord appeared to him the same night and said, “I am the God of Abraham your father. Fear not, for I am with you and will bless you and multiply your offspring for my servant Abraham’s sake.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 26,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now when they saw the boldness of Peter and John, and perceived that they were uneducated, common men, they were astonished. And they recognized that they had been with Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be strong, and let your heart take courage, all you who wait for the Lord! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the scribe said to him, “You are right, Teacher. You have truly said that he is one, and there is no other besides him. And to love him with all the heart and with all the understanding and with all the strength, and to love one’s neighbor as oneself, is much more than all whole burnt offerings and sacrifices.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 12,32-33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For you shall go out in joy and be led forth in peace; the mountains and the hills before you shall break forth into singing, and all the trees of the field shall clap their hands. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your hearts be troubled, neither let them be afraid. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And you shall eat and be full, and you shall bless the Lord your God for the good land he has given you.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet he did not leave himself without witness, for he did good by giving you rains from heaven and fruitful seasons, satisfying your hearts with food and gladness.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-06-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have seen his ways, but I will heal him; I will lead him and restore comfort to him and his mourners, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So they went out and proclaimed that people should repent. And they cast out many demons and anointed with oil many who were sick and healed them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,12-13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>your abundance at the present time should supply their need, so that their abundance may supply your need, that there may be fairness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing praises to the Lord, O you his saints, and give thanks to his holy name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 30,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He has delivered us from the domain of darkness and transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved Son, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord utters his voice before his army, for his camp is exceedingly great; he who executes his word is powerful. For the day of the Lord is great and very awesome; who can endure it? “Yet even now,” declares the Lord, “return to me with all your heart, with fasting, with weeping, and with mourning; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The night is far gone; the day is at hand. So then let us cast off the works of darkness and put on the armor of light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 13,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will sing to the Lord as long as I live; I will sing praise to my God while I have being. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 104,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>addressing one another in Psalm and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yodh: Your hands have made and fashioned me; give me understanding that I may learn your commandments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,73</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I give thanks to my God always for you because of the grace of God that was given you in Christ Jesus, that in every way you were enriched in him in all speech and all knowledge— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies. The King of Israel, the Lord, is in your midst; you shall never again fear evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Be watchful, stand firm in the faith, act like men, be strong. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 16,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord said to me, “Do not say, ‘I am only a youth’; for to all to whom I send you, you shall go, and whatever I command you, you shall speak. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Lord said to Paul one night in a vision, “Do not be afraid, but go on speaking and do not be silent, for I am with you, and no one will attack you to harm you, for I have many in this city who are my people.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 18,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of Asaph. The Mighty One, God the Lord, speaks and summons the earth from the rising of the sun to its setting. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 50,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Long ago, at many times and in many ways, God spoke to our fathers by the prophets, but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>‘Ah, Lord God! It is you who have made the heavens and the earth by your great power and by your outstretched arm! Nothing is too hard for you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Indeed, we felt that we had received the sentence of death. But that was to make us rely not on ourselves but on God who raises the dead. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>You shall be a crown of beauty in the hand of the Lord, and a royal diadem in the hand of your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 62,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When they had finished eating the grass of the land, I said, “O Lord God, please forgive! How can Jacob stand? He is so small!” The Lord relented concerning this: “It shall not be,” said the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 7,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>praying at all times in the Spirit, with all prayer and supplication. To that end keep alert with all perseverance, making supplication for all the saints, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Seek good, and not evil, that you may live; and so the Lord, the God of hosts, will be with you, as you have said. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 5,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let all that you do be done in love. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 16,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I was mute and silent; I held my peace to no avail, and my distress grew worse. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 39,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let no corrupting talk come out of your mouths, but only such as is good for building up, as fits the occasion, that it may give grace to those who hear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O you who love the Lord, hate evil! He preserves the lives of his saints; he delivers them from the hand of the wicked. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 97,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this is the will of God, that by doing good you should put to silence the ignorance of foolish people. Live as people who are free, not using your freedom as a cover-up for evil, but living as servants of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,15-16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not commit adultery. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let marriage be held in honor among all, and let the marriage bed be undefiled, for God will judge the sexually immoral and adulterous. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, my strength and my stronghold, my refuge in the day of trouble, to you shall the nations come from the ends of the earth and say: “Our fathers have inherited nothing but lies, worthless things in which there is no profit. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 16,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then came one of the rulers of the synagogue, Jairus by name, and seeing him, he fell at his feet and implored him earnestly, saying, “My little daughter is at the point of death. Come and lay your hands on her, so that she may be made well and live.” And he went with him. And a great crowd followed him and thronged about him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,22-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>He sent redemption to his people; he has commanded his covenant forever. Holy and awesome is his name! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 111,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that the crowd wondered, when they saw the mute speaking, the crippled healthy, the lame walking, and the blind seeing. And they glorified the God of Israel. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 15,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The steadfast love of the Lord never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,22-23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we do not lose heart. Though our outer self is wasting away, our inner self is being renewed day by day. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, declares the Lord.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext> John said to him, “Teacher, we saw someone casting out demons in your name,6 and we tried to stop him, because he was not following us.” But Jesus said, “ Do not stop him. For the one who is not against us is for us.</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 9,38-39a.40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Every man shall give as he is able, according to the blessing of the Lord your God that he has given you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 16,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As each has received a gift, use it to serve one another, as good stewards of God’s varied grace: </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I am the Lord; I will speak the word that I will speak, and it will be performed. It will no longer be delayed, but in your days, O rebellious house, I will speak the word and perform it, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 12,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the Lord direct your hearts to the love of God and to the steadfastness of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your testimonies are my delight; they are my counselors. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>After three days they found him in the temple, sitting among the teachers, listening to them and asking them questions. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Listen to me, you who know righteousness, the people in whose heart is my law; fear not the reproach of man, nor be dismayed at their revilings. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Woe to you, when all people speak well of you, for so their fathers did to the false prophets. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord brings the counsel of the nations to nothing; he frustrates the plans of the peoples. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that he worked in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly places, far above all rule and authority and power and dominion, and above every name that is named, not only in this age but also in the one to come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>By the word of the Lord the heavens were made, and by the breath of his mouth all their host. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>nor is he served by human hands, as though he needed anything, since he himself gives to all mankind life and breath and everything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord God helps me; therefore I have not been disgraced; therefore I have set my face like a flint, and I know that I shall not be put to shame. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He delivered us from such a deadly peril, and he will deliver us. On him we have set our hope that he will deliver us again. You also must help us by prayer, so that many will give thanks on our behalf for the blessing granted us through the prayers of many. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,10-11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Put them in fear, O Lord! Let the nations know that they are but men! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 9,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A merchant, in whose hands are false balances, he loves to oppress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 12,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Put on then, as God’s chosen ones, holy and beloved, compassionate hearts, kindness, humility, meekness, and patience, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your evil will chastise you, and your apostasy will reprove you. Know and see that it is evil and bitter for you to forsake the Lord your God; the fear of me is not in you, declares the Lord God of hosts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am coming soon. Hold fast what you have, so that no one may seize your crown. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the Lord require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 6,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I have given you an example, that you also should do just as I have done to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 13,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-07-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>You shall not curse the deaf or put a stumbling block before the blind, but you shall fear your God: I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when you give a feast, invite the poor, the crippled, the lame, the blind, and you will be blessed, because they cannot repay you. For you will be repaid at the resurrection of the just.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He executes justice for the fatherless and the widow, and loves the sojourner, giving him food and clothing. Love the sojourner, therefore, for you were sojourners in the land of Egypt. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,18.19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>One generation shall commend your works to another, and shall declare your mighty acts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 145,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and you shall be driven from among men, and your dwelling shall be with the beasts of the field. And you shall be made to eat grass like an ox, and seven periods of time shall pass over you, until you know that the Most High rules the kingdom of men and gives it to whom he will.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 4,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then the seventh angel blew his trumpet, and there were loud voices in heaven, saying, “The kingdom of the world has become the kingdom of our Lord and of his Christ, and he shall reign forever and ever.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 11,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Seek the Lord while he may be found; call upon him while he is near; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he says, “In a favorable time I listened to you, and in a day of salvation I have helped you.” Behold, now is the favorable time; behold, now is the day of salvation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>May the Lord give strength to his people! May the Lord bless his people with peace! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 29,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20.21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Many are the sorrows of the wicked, but steadfast love surrounds the one who trusts in the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 32,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Until now you have asked nothing in my name. Ask, and you will receive, that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>But where are your gods that you made for yourself? Let them arise, if they can save you, in your time of trouble; for as many as your cities are your gods, O Judah. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Neither be called instructors, for you have one instructor, the Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 23,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The king is not saved by his great army; a warrior is not delivered by his great strength. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But now that you have come to know God, or rather to be known by God, how can you turn back again to the weak and worthless elementary principles of the world, whose slaves you want to be once more? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So Moses and Aaron went in to Pharaoh and said to him, “Thus says the Lord, the God of the Hebrews, ‘How long will you refuse to humble yourself before me? Let my people go, that they may serve me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 10,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you say, I am rich, I have prospered, and I need nothing, not realizing that you are wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As for me, I am poor and needy, but the Lord takes thought for me. You are my help and my deliverer; do not delay, O my God! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus came to the place, he looked up and said to him, “Zacchaeus, hurry and come down, for I must stay at your house today.” So he hurried and came down and received him joyfully. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Restore us, O Lord God of hosts! Let your face shine, that we may be saved!</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 80,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when the Lord saw her, he had compassion on her and said to her, “Do not weep.” Then he came up and touched the bier, and the bearers stood still. And he said, “Young man, I say to you, arise.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 7,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>that he may incline our hearts to him, to walk in all his ways and to keep his commandments, his statutes, and his rules, which he commanded our fathers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,58</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>His divine power has granted to us all things that pertain to life and godliness, through the knowledge of him who called us to his own glory and excellence, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who knows? God may turn and relent and turn from his fierce anger, so that we may not perish.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>All the earth worships you and sings praises to you; they sing praises to your name.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 66,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that the name of our Lord Jesus may be glorified in you, and you in him, according to the grace of our God and the Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The eyes of the Lord are in every place, keeping watch on the evil and the good. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a net that was thrown into the sea and gathered fish of every kind. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then I will gather the remnant of my flock out of all the countries where I have driven them, and I will bring them back to their fold, and they shall be fruitful and multiply. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I have other sheep that are not of this fold. I must bring them also, and they will listen to my voice. So there will be one flock, one shepherd. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When the poor and needy seek water, and there is none, and their tongue is parched with thirst, I the Lord will answer them; I the God of Israel will not forsake them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Spirit and the Bride say, “Come.” And let the one who hears say, “Come.” And let the one who is thirsty come; let the one who desires take the water of life without price. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Great salvation he brings to his king, and shows steadfast love to his anointed, to David and his offspring forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 18,50</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>proclaiming the kingdom of God and teaching about the Lord Jesus Christ with all boldness and without hindrance. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 28,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For thus says the Lord: Just as I have brought all this great disaster upon this people, so I will bring upon them all the good that I promise them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,42</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Our hope for you is unshaken, for we know that as you share in our sufferings, you will also share in our comfort. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember the wondrous works that he has done, his miracles, and the judgments he uttered, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>See what kind of love the Father has given to us, that we should be called children of God; and so we are. The reason why the world does not know us is that it did not know him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Truly I know that it is so: But how can a man be in the right before God? If one wished to contend with him, one could not answer him once in a thousand times. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this we shall know that we are of the truth and reassure our heart before him;  for whenever our heart condemns us, God is greater than our heart, and he knows everything.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you are my lamp, O Lord, and my God lightens my darkness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 22,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have come into the world as light, so that whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Six days you shall labor, and do all your work, but the seventh day is a Sabbath to the Lord your God. On it you shall not do any work, you, or your son, or your daughter, your male servant, or your female servant, or your livestock, or the sojourner who is within your gates. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,9.10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “The Sabbath was made for man, not man for the Sabbath. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sow for yourselves righteousness; reap steadfast love; break up your fallow ground, for it is the time to seek the Lord, that he may come and rain righteousness upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we urge you, brothers, admonish the idle, encourage the fainthearted, help the weak, be patient with them all. See that no one repays anyone evil for evil, but always seek to do good to one another and to everyone. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,14-15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My lips will shout for joy, when I sing praises to you; my soul also, which you have redeemed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Nevertheless, do not rejoice in this, that the spirits are subject to you, but rejoice that your names are written in heaven.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the king commanded, and those men who had maliciously accused Daniel were brought and cast into the den of lions—they, their children, and their wives. And before they reached the bottom of the den, the lions overpowered them and broke all their bones in pieces. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And many of those who sleep in the dust of the earth shall awake, some to everlasting life, and some to shame and everlasting contempt. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 12,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>on that day when, according to my gospel, God judges the secrets of men by Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 2,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>my God, my rock, in whom I take refuge, my shield, and the horn of my salvation, my stronghold and my refuge, my savior; you save me from violence. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 22,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not driven to despair; persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall do no injustice in court. You shall not be partial to the poor or defer to the great, but in righteousness shall you judge your neighbor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ, the Lord of glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now out of the ground the Lord God had formed every beast of the field and every bird of the heavens and brought them to the man to see what he would call them. And whatever the man called every living creature, that was its name. The man gave names to all livestock and to the birds of the heavens and to every beast of the field. But for Adam there was not found a helper fit for him.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 2,19.20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Are not five sparrows sold for two pennies? And not one of them is forgotten before God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-08-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When I look at your heavens, the work of your fingers, the moon and the stars, which you have set in place, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 8,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when Jesus saw it, he was indignant and said to them, “Let the children come to me; do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Know that the Lord, he is God! It is he who made us, and we are his; we are his people, and the sheep of his pasture. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 100,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Once you were not a people, but now you are God’s people; once you had not received mercy, but now you have received mercy. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall give to him freely, and your heart shall not be grudging when you give to him, because for this the Lord your God will bless you in all your work and in all that you undertake. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 15,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And whoever gives one of these little ones even a cup of cold water because he is a disciple, truly, I say to you, he will by no means lose his reward.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you let men ride over our heads; we went through fire and through water; yet you have brought us out to a place of abundance. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 66,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But stay awake at all times, praying that you may have strength to escape all these things that are going to take place, and to stand before the Son of Man.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>But God will strike the heads of his enemies, the hairy crown of him who walks in his guilty ways. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 68,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “Go out and stand on the mount before the Lord.” And behold, the Lord passed by, and a great and strong wind tore the mountains and broke in pieces the rocks before the Lord, but the Lord was not in the wind. And after the wind an earthquake, but the Lord was not in the earthquake. And after the earthquake a fire, but the Lord was not in the fire. And after the fire the sound of a low whisper.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 19,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For a brief moment I deserted you, but with great compassion I will gather you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ—by grace you have been saved— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But he was pierced for our transgressions; he was crushed for our iniquities; upon him was the chastisement that brought us peace, and with his wounds we are healed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For thus says the Lord: “Sing aloud with gladness for Jacob, and raise shouts for the chief of the nations; proclaim, give praise, and say, ‘O Lord, save your people, the remnant of Israel.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he did not permit him but said to him, “Go home to your friends and tell them how much the Lord has done for you, and how he has had mercy on you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When you pass through the waters, I will be with you; and through the rivers, they shall not overwhelm you; when you walk through fire you shall not be burned, and the flame shall not consume you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he awoke and rebuked the wind and said to the sea, “Peace! Be still!” And the wind ceased, and there was a great calm. He said to them, “Why are you so afraid? Have you still no faith?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,39-40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed is the one you choose and bring near, to dwell in your courts! We shall be satisfied with the goodness of your house, the holiness of your temple! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 65,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>16. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Hide not your face from me. Turn not your servant away in anger, O you who have been my help. Cast me not off; forsake me not, O God of my salvation! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 27,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is the will of him who sent me, that I should lose nothing of all that he has given me, but raise it up on the last day. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I, the Lord, am its keeper; every moment I water it. Lest anyone punish it, I keep it night and day;  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 27,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this my Father is glorified, that you bear much fruit and so prove to be my disciples. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, O Lord, are a shield about me, my glory, and the lifter of my head. I cried aloud to the Lord, and he answered me from his holy hill. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 3,3-4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And a leper came to him, imploring him, and kneeling said to him, “If you will, you can make me clean.” Moved with pity, he stretched out his hand and touched him and said to him, “I will; be clean.”  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,40-41</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord is the true God; he is the living God and the everlasting King. At his wrath the earth quakes, and the nations cannot endure his indignation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>which he will display at the proper time—he who is the blessed and only Sovereign, the King of kings and Lord of lords, who alone has immortality, who dwells in unapproachable light, whom no one has ever seen or can see. To him be honor and eternal dominion. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,15-16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will make with them an everlasting covenant, that I will not turn away from doing good to them. And I will put the fear of me in their hearts, that they may not turn from me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,40</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and I will bring them to dwell in the midst of Jerusalem. And they shall be my people, and I will be their God, in faithfulness and in righteousness.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he is the head of the body, the church. He is the beginning, the firstborn from the dead, that in everything he might be preeminent. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who fear the Lord, trust in the Lord! He is their help and their shield. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 115,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and hope does not put us to shame, because God’s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>17. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>After these things the word of the Lord came to Abram in a vision: “Fear not, Abram, I am your shield; your reward shall be very great.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 15,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And thus Abraham, having patiently waited, obtained the promise. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then my tongue shall tell of your righteousness and of your praise all the day long. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 35,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and then as a widow until she was eighty-four. She did not depart from the temple, worshiping with fasting and prayer night and day. And coming up at that very hour she began to give thanks to God and to speak of him to all who were waiting for the redemption of Jerusalem. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,37-38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You prepare a table before me in the presence of my enemies; you anoint my head with oil; my cup overflows. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 23,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And while he was at Bethany in the house of Simon the leper, as he was reclining at table, a woman came with an alabaster flask of ointment of pure nard, very costly, and she broke the flask and poured it over his head. There were some who said to themselves indignantly, “Why was the ointment wasted like that?  But Jesus said, “Leave her alone. Why do you trouble her? She has done a beautiful thing to me.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 14,3.4.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Look to the right and see: there is none who takes notice of me; no refuge remains to me; no one cares for my soul. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 142,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then the Lord said to Cain, “Where is Abel your brother?” He said, “I do not know; am I my brother’s keeper?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 4,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let each of you look not only to his own interests, but also to the interests of others. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh that you had paid attention to my commandments! Then your peace would have been like a river, and your righteousness like the waves of the sea; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God is not a matter of eating and drinking but of righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. Whoever thus serves Christ is acceptable to God and approved by men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Know then in your heart that, as a man disciplines his son, the Lord your God disciplines you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But grow in the grace and knowledge of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. To him be the glory both now and to the day of eternity. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>18. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will cleanse them from all the guilt of their sin against me, and I will forgive all the guilt of their sin and rebellion against me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>waiting for our blessed hope, the appearing of the glory of our great God and Savior Jesus Christ, who gave himself for us to redeem us from all lawlessness and to purify for himself a people for his own possession who are zealous for good works. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then he took the Book of the Covenant and read it in the hearing of the people. And they said, “All that the Lord has spoken we will do, and we will be obedient.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 24,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be slothful in zeal, be fervent in spirit, serve the Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “My presence will go with you, and I will give you rest.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Since we have such a hope, we are very bold, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And to him was given dominion and glory and a kingdom, that all peoples, nations, and languages should serve him; his dominion is an everlasting dominion, which shall not pass away, and his kingdom one that shall not be destroyed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 7,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For in him all the fullness of God was pleased to dwell, and through him to reconcile to himself all things, whether on earth or in heaven, making peace by the blood of his cross. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Michaelistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Why do you spend your money for that which is not bread, and your labor for that which does not satisfy? Listen diligently to me, and eat what is good, and delight yourselves in rich food. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not work for the food that perishes, but for the food that endures to eternal life, which the Son of Man will give to you. For on him God the Father has set his seal.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-09-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be gracious to me, O Lord, for I am languishing; heal me, O Lord, for my bones are troubled. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 6,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I hold my life in my hand continually, but I do not forget your law. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,109</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,68</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Zum Erntedankfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>He has remembered his steadfast love and faithfulness to the house of Israel. All the ends of the earth have seen the salvation of our God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 98,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Is a lamp brought in to be put under a basket, or under a bed, and not on a stand? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, O God, will cast them down into the pit of destruction; men of blood and treachery shall not live out half their days. But I will trust in you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 55,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In his hand are the depths of the earth; the heights of the mountains are his also.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 95,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The God who made the world and everything in it, being Lord of heaven and earth, does not live in temples made by man, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>some of the gods of the peoples who are around you, whether near you or far off from you, from the one end of the earth to the other, But you shall kill him. Your hand shall be first against him to put him to death, and afterward the hand of all the people. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,7.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Brothers, if anyone is caught in any transgression, you who are spiritual should restore him in a spirit of gentleness. Keep watch on yourself, lest you too be tempted. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Every way of a man is right in his own eyes, but the Lord weighs the heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 21,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“All things are lawful for me,” but not all things are helpful. “All things are lawful for me,” but I will not be dominated by anything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And all that generation also were gathered to their fathers. And there arose another generation after them who did not know the Lord or the work that he had done for Israel.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 2,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that you have prepared in the presence of all peoples, a light for revelation to the Gentiles, and for glory to your people Israel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The unfolding of your words gives light; it imparts understanding to the simple. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,130</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For whatever was written in former days was written for our instruction, that through endurance and through the encouragement of the Scriptures we might have hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then the Lord said, “I have pardoned, according to your word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 14,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>bearing with one another and, if one has a complaint against another, forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord is righteous; he loves righteous deeds; the upright shall behold his face. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 11,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light (for the fruit of light is found in all that is good and right and true), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will recount the steadfast love of the Lord, the praises of the Lord, according to all that the Lord has granted us, and the great goodness to the house of Israel that he has granted them according to his compassion, according to the abundance of his steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you have tasted that the Lord is good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For thus says the Lord God: Behold, I, I myself will search for my sheep and will seek them out. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Passing alongside the Sea of Galilee, he saw Simon and Andrew the brother of Simon casting a net into the sea, for they were fishermen. And Jesus said to them, “Follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I am the Lord; that is my name; my glory I give to no other, nor my praise to carved idols. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For although there may be so-called gods in heaven or on earth—as indeed there are many “gods” and many “lords”— yet for us there is one God, the Father, from whom are all things and for whom we exist, and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and through whom we exist. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,5.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for my people have committed two evils: they have forsaken me, the fountain of living waters, and hewed out cisterns for themselves, broken cisterns that can hold no water. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The woman said to him, “Sir, you have nothing to draw water with, and the well is deep. Where do you get that living water?  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I am the Lord; I will speak the word that I will speak, and it will be performed. It will no longer be delayed, but in your days, O rebellious house, I will speak the word and perform it, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 12,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we did not follow cleverly devised myths when we made known to you the power and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but we were eyewitnesses of his majesty. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>21. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>To the choirmaster. Of David. The fool says in his heart, “There is no God.” They are corrupt, they do abominable deeds, there is none who does good. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 14,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is eternal life, that they know you the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore he shall give them up until the time when she who is in labor has given birth; then the rest of his brothers shall return to the people of Israel. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 5,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You are my witnesses,” declares the Lord, “and my servant whom I have chosen, that you may know and believe me and understand that I am he. Before me no god was formed, nor shall there be any after me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For what we proclaim is not ourselves, but Jesus Christ as Lord, with ourselves as your servants for Jesus’ sake. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord will fulfill his purpose for me; your steadfast love, O Lord, endures forever. Do not forsake the work of your hands. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 138,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand, that we should walk in them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be silent before the Lord God! For the day of the Lord is near; the Lord has prepared a sacrifice and consecrated his guests. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The end of all things is at hand; therefore be self-controlled and sober-minded for the sake of your prayers. Above all, keep loving one another earnestly, since love covers a multitude of sins. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,7-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will turn to you and make you fruitful and multiply you and will confirm my covenant with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 26,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are God’s fellow workers. You are God’s field, God’s building. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For from the rising of the sun to its setting my name will be great among the nations, and in every place incense will be offered to my name, and a pure offering. For my name will be great among the nations, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 1,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I tell you, many will come from east and west and recline at table with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>22. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>We have become like those over whom you have never ruled, like those who are not called by your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And then they will see the Son of Man coming in clouds with great power and glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O Lord, make me dwell in safety.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 4,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he himself is our peace, who has made us both one and has broken down in his flesh the dividing wall of hostility </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, the former things have come to pass, and new things I now declare; before they spring forth I tell you of them.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Great indeed, we confess, is the mystery of godliness: He was manifested in the flesh, vindicated by the Spirit, seen by angels, proclaimed among the nations, believed on in the world, taken up in glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Go and proclaim in the hearing of Jerusalem, Thus says the Lord, “I remember the devotion of your youth, your love as a bride, how you followed me in the wilderness, in a land not sown. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>do not oppress the widow, the fatherless, the sojourner, or the poor, and let none of you devise evil against another in your heart.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 7,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The eye cannot say to the hand, “I have no need of you,” nor again the head to the feet, “I have no need of you.”  On the contrary, the parts of the body that seem to be weaker are indispensable,  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,21-22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Seek the Lord and his strength; seek his presence continually! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now Jesus was praying in a certain place, and when he finished, one of his disciples said to him, “Lord, teach us to pray, as John taught his disciples.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Gideon said to them, “I will not rule over you, and my son will not rule over you; the Lord will rule over you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 8,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus called them to him and said to them, “You know that those who are considered rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them, and their great ones exercise authority over them. But it shall not be so among you. But whoever would be great among you must be your servant, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,42-43</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>23. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The hope of the righteous brings joy, but the expectation of the wicked will perish. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You also, be patient. Establish your hearts, for the coming of the Lord is at hand. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-10-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Shout, and sing for joy, O inhabitant of Zion, for great in your midst is the Holy One of Israel.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 12,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he stands at the right hand of the needy one, to save him from those who condemn his soul to death. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 109,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he who sanctifies and those who are sanctified all have one source. That is why he is not ashamed to call them brothers, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Out of the anguish of his soul he shall see and be satisfied; by his knowledge shall the righteous one, my servant, make many to be accounted righteous, and he shall bear their iniquities. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For even the Son of Man came not to be served but to serve, and to give his life as a ransom for many.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,45</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said to me, “You are my servant, Israel, in whom I will be glorified.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>God has not rejected his people whom he foreknew. Do you not know what the Scripture says of Elijah, how he appeals to God against Israel? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord hears the needy and does not despise his own people who are prisoners. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 69,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I would soon subdue their enemies and turn my hand against their foes. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 81,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>For God will bring every deed into judgment, with every secret thing, whether good or evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 12,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily. Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: “Let not the wise man boast in his wisdom, let not the mighty man boast in his might, let not the rich man boast in his riches, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 9,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I heard the voice of the Lord saying, “Whom shall I send, and who will go for us?” Then I said, “Here I am! Send me.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 6,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To each is given the manifestation of the Spirit for the common good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My soul yearns for you in the night; my spirit within me earnestly seeks you. For when your judgments are in the earth, the inhabitants of the world learn righteousness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 19,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for you have been my help, and in the shadow of your wings I will sing for joy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 63,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a merchant in search of fine pearls,  who, on finding one pearl of great value, went and sold all that he had and bought it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,45-46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who fear the Lord, praise him! All you offspring of Jacob, glorify him, and stand in awe of him, all you offspring of Israel! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of endurance and encouragement grant you to live in such harmony with one another, in accord with Christ Jesus, that together you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>For I will defend this city to save it, for my own sake and for the sake of my servant David.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Moses said to Aaron, “This is what the Lord has said: ‘Among those who are near me I will be sanctified, and before all the people I will be glorified.’” And Aaron held his peace. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 10,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then I shall not be put to shame, having my eyes fixed on all your commandments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Meanwhile the disciples were urging him, saying, “Rabbi, eat.” But he said to them, “I have food to eat that you do not know about.”  So the disciples said to one another, “Has anyone brought him something to eat?” Jesus said to them, “My food is to do the will of him who sent me and to accomplish his work. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 4,31-34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Buß- und Bettag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For you bless the righteous, O Lord; you cover him with favor as with a shield. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 5,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Though you have not seen him, you love him. Though you do not now see him, you believe in him and rejoice with joy that is inexpressible and filled with glory, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, to the Lord your God belong heaven and the heaven of heavens, the earth with all that is in it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For his invisible attributes, namely, his eternal power and divine nature, have been clearly perceived, ever since the creation of the world, in the things that have been made. So they are without excuse. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 1,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Like a swallow or a crane I chirp; I moan like a dove. My eyes are weary with looking upward. O Lord, I am oppressed; be my pledge of safety! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And when they say to you, “Inquire of the mediums and the necromancers who chirp and mutter,” should not a people inquire of their God? Should they inquire of the dead on behalf of the living? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 8,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he who is joined to the Lord becomes one spirit with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 6,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres (Ewigkeitssonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Uphold me according to your promise, that I may live, and let me not be put to shame in my hope! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,116</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace himself sanctify you completely, and may your whole spirit and soul and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Great are the works of the Lord, studied by all who delight in them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 111,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Consider the lilies, how they grow: they neither toil nor spin, yet I tell you, even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As the mountains surround Jerusalem, so the Lord surrounds his people, from this time forth and forevermore. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 125,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Noah did this; he did all that God commanded him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 6,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By faith Noah, being warned by God concerning events as yet unseen, in reverent fear constructed an ark for the saving of his household. By this he condemned the world and became an heir of the righteousness that comes by faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I know that my Redeemer lives, and at the last he will stand upon the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 19,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The heart of man plans his way, but the Lord establishes his steps. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Instead you ought to say, “If the Lord wills, we will live and do this or that.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 4,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He is like a tree planted by streams of water that yields its fruit in its season, and its leaf does not wither. In all that he does, he prospers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 1,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,22-23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>so shall my word be that goes out from my mouth; it shall not return to me empty, but it shall accomplish that which I purpose, and shall succeed in the thing for which I sent it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they went out and preached everywhere, while the Lord worked with them and confirmed the message by accompanying signs.]] </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> Praise the Lord! Blessed is the man who fears the Lord, who greatly delights in his commandments! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 112,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it and how from childhood you have been acquainted with the sacred writings, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 3,14-15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As a pleasing aroma I will accept you, when I bring you out from the peoples and gather you out of the countries where you have been scattered. And I will manifest my holiness among you in the sight of the nations. And you shall know that I am the Lord, when I bring you into the land of Israel, the country that I swore to give to your fathers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,41.42</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the gifts and the calling of God are irrevocable. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-11-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 32,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Keep hold of instruction; do not let go; guard her, for she is your life. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 4,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The aim of our charge is love that issues from a pure heart and a good conscience and a sincere faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will not be afraid of many thousands of people who have set themselves against me all around. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 3,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Greet one another with the kiss of love. Peace to all of you who are in Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of Asaph. Truly God is good to Israel, to those who are pure in heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 73,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now there was a man in Jerusalem, whose name was Simeon, and this man was righteous and devout, waiting for the consolation of Israel, and the Holy Spirit was upon him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>the Lord lift up his countenance upon you and give you peace. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 6,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Be glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the Lord your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people and has raised up a horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,68-69</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Elijah came near to all the people and said, “How long will you go limping between two different opinions? If the Lord is God, follow him; but if Baal, then follow him.” And the people did not answer him a word. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 18,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>No one sews a piece of unshrunk cloth on an old garment. If he does, the patch tears away from it, the new from the old, and a worse tear is made.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The steadfast love of the Lord never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and the grace of our Lord overflowed for me with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “No; but I am the commander of the army of the Lord. Now I have come.” And Joshua fell on his face to the earth and worshiped and said to him, “What does my lord say to his servant?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 5,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said, “Blessed rather are those who hear the word of God and keep it!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Balaam answered and said to the servants of Balak, “Though Balak were to give me his house full of silver and gold, I could not go beyond the command of the Lord my God to do less or more. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 22,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming, declares the Lord, when I will raise up for David a righteous Branch, and he shall reign as king and deal wisely, and shall execute justice and righteousness in the land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And those who went before and those who followed were shouting, “Hosanna! Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord! Blessed is the coming kingdom of our father David! Hosanna in the highest!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 11,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Behold, at that time I will deal with all your oppressors. And I will save the lame and gather the outcast, and I will change their shame into praise and renown in all the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When he went ashore he saw a great crowd, and he had compassion on them, because they were like sheep without a shepherd. And he began to teach them many things. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Open your mouth for the mute, for the rights of all who are destitute. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 31,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them, and those who are mistreated, since you also are in the body. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Moses said, “Please show me your glory.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Philip said to him, “Lord, show us the Father, and it is enough for us.” Jesus said to him, “Have I been with you so long, and you still do not know me, Philip? Whoever has seen me has seen the Father. How can you say, ‘Show us the Father’? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then I replied to them, “The God of heaven will make us prosper, and we his servants will arise and build, but you have no portion or right or claim in Jerusalem.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 2,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are God’s fellow workers. You are God’s field, God’s building. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The living, the living, he thanks you, as I do this day; the father makes known to the children your faithfulness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Therefore every scribe who has been trained for the kingdom of heaven is like a master of a house, who brings out of his treasure what is new and what is old.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have I any pleasure in the death of the wicked, declares the Lord God, and not rather that he should turn from his way and live? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Or do you presume on the riches of his kindness and forbearance and patience, not knowing that God’s kindness is meant to lead you to repentance? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 2,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I love the Lord, because he has heard my voice and my pleas for mercy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the angel said to him, “Do not be afraid, Zechariah, for your prayer has been heard, and your wife Elizabeth will bear you a son, and you shall call his name John. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Who is like the Lord our God, who is seated on high, who looks far down on the heavens and the earth? He raises the poor from the dust and lifts the needy from the ash heap, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 113,5-7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For he was crucified in weakness, but lives by the power of God. For we also are weak in him, but in dealing with you we will live with him by the power of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Light is sown for the righteous, and joy for the upright in heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 97,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When they saw the star, they rejoiced exceedingly with great joy.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who does great things beyond searching out, and marvelous things beyond number. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who are heroes at drinking wine, and valiant men in mixing strong drink, who acquit the guilty for a bribe, and deprive the innocent of his right! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,22.23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For with the judgment you pronounce you will be judged, and with the measure you use it will be measured to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then he said to me, “This is the word of the Lord to Zerubbabel: Not by might, nor by power, but by my Spirit, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 4,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By faith the walls of Jericho fell down after they had been encircled for seven days. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For kingship belongs to the Lord, and he rules over the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The true light, which gives light to everyone, was coming into the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Heiliger Abend</Sonntag><Losungstext>I believed, even when I spoke: “I am greatly afflicted”; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So if the Son sets you free, you will be free indeed.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>The bows of the mighty are broken, but the feeble bind on strength. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>he has brought down the mighty from their thrones and exalted those of humble estate; he has filled the hungry with good things, and the rich he has sent away empty. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,52-53</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>the Lord opens the eyes of the blind. The Lord lifts up those who are bowed down; the Lord loves the righteous. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, what are the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For in death there is no remembrance of you; in Sheol who will give you praise? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 6,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus turned, and seeing her he said, “Take heart, daughter; your faith has made you well.” And instantly the woman was made well. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then the Lord put out his hand and touched my mouth. And the Lord said to me, “Behold, I have put my words in your mouth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And a cloud overshadowed them, and a voice came out of the cloud, “This is my beloved Son; listen to him.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 9,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not be afraid of them, for I am with you to deliver you, declares the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Mightier than the thunders of many waters, mightier than the waves of the sea, the Lord on high is mighty! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 93,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have said these things to you, that in me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation. But take heart; I have overcome the world.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2016-12-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Altjahrsabend</Sonntag><Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. Of David. Behold, how good and pleasant it is when brothers dwell in unity! It is like the dew of Hermon, which falls on the mountains of Zion! For there the Lord has commanded the blessing, life forevermore. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 133,1.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Finally, brothers, rejoice. Aim for restoration, comfort one another, agree with one another, live in peace; and the God of love and peace will be with you. All the saints greet you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,11.13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen></FreeXml>