<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><FreeXml><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the Lord searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will cast you off forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 28,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20.21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yet you have been righteous in all that has come upon us, for you have dealt faithfully and we have acted wickedly. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Reuben said to them, “Shed no blood; throw him into this pit here in the wilderness, but do not lay a hand on him”—that he might rescue him out of their hand to restore him to his father. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 37,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Be merciful, even as your Father is merciful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I rise before dawn and cry for help; I hope in your words. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,147</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deceit is in the heart of those who devise evil, but those who plan peace have joy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 12,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Epiphanias (Erscheinungsfest)</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the yoke of his burden, and the staff for his shoulder, the rod of his oppressor, you have broken as on the day of Midian. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>because of the tender mercy of our God, whereby the sunrise shall visit us from on high to give light to those who sit in darkness and in the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,78.79</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The stone that the builders rejected has become the cornerstone. This is the Lord’s doing; it is marvelous in our eyes.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,22-23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For no one can lay a foundation other than that which is laid, which is Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>You shall not make gods of silver to be with me, nor shall you make for yourselves gods of gold. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Again, the devil took him to a very high mountain and showed him all the kingdoms of the world and their glory. And he said to him, “All these I will give you, if you will fall down and worship me.”  Then Jesus said to him, “Be gone, Satan! For it is written, “‘You shall worship the Lord your God and him only shall you serve.’” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 4,8-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In those days Hezekiah became sick and was at the point of death, and he prayed to the Lord, and he answered him and gave him a sign. But Hezekiah did not make return according to the benefit done to him, for his heart was proud. Therefore wrath came upon him and Judah and Jerusalem. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 32,24-25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he did not permit him but said to him, “Go home to your friends and tell them how much the Lord has done for you, and how he has had mercy on you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who call evil good and good evil, who put darkness for light and light for darkness, who put bitter for sweet and sweet for bitter! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For to this you have been called, because Christ also suffered for you, leaving you an example, so that you might follow in his steps. He committed no sin, neither was deceit found in his mouth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,21-22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A righteous man knows the rights of the poor; a wicked man does not understand such knowledge. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 29,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>your abundance at the present time should supply their need, so that their abundance may supply your need, that there may be fairness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord is merciful and gracious, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 103,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For a people shall dwell in Zion, in Jerusalem; you shall weep no more. He will surely be gracious to you at the sound of your cry. As soon as he hears it, he answers you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out and say, “Jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Because you have made the Lord your dwelling place— the Most High, who is my refuge— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that by two unchangeable things, in which it is impossible for God to lie, we who have fled for refuge might have strong encouragement to hold fast to the hope set before us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>Have we not all one Father? Has not one God created us? Why then are we faithless to one another, profaning the covenant of our fathers? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 2,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 13,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord, the King of Israel and his Redeemer, the Lord of hosts: “I am the first and I am the last; besides me there is no god. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this reason I bow my knees before the Father,  from whom every family in heaven and on earth is named, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,14-15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed is he whose help is the God of Jacob, whose hope is in the Lord his God, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>which is why I suffer as I do. But I am not ashamed, for I know whom I have believed, and I am convinced that he is able to guard until that day what has been entrusted to me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>yet I will rejoice in the Lord; I will take joy in the God of my salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Habbakuk 3,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when they came up out of the water, the Spirit of the Lord carried Philip away, and the eunuch saw him no more, and went on his way rejoicing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 8,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Violence shall no more be heard in your land, devastation or destruction within your borders; you shall call your walls Salvation, and your gates Praise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man.
He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Better is a little with the fear of the Lord than great treasure and trouble with it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Consider the ravens: they neither sow nor reap, they have neither storehouse nor barn, and yet God feeds them. Of how much more value are you than the birds! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord said to him, “Peace be to you. Do not fear; you shall not die.” Then Gideon built an altar there to the Lord and called it, The Lord Is Peace. To this day it still stands at Ophrah, which belongs to the Abiezrites. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 6,23-24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your hearts be troubled, neither let them be afraid. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>As one whom his mother comforts, so I will comfort you; you shall be comforted in Jerusalem. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Six days you shall work, but on the seventh day you shall rest. In plowing time and in harvest you shall rest. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 34,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You were bought with a price; do not become bondservants of men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 7,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whatever the Lord pleases, he does, in heaven and on earth, in the seas and all deeps. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 135,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the men marveled, saying, “What sort of man is this, that even winds and sea obey him?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed is the nation whose God is the Lord, the people whom he has chosen as his heritage! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you cast me into the deep, into the heart of the seas, and the flood surrounded me; all your waves and your billows passed over me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>All that the Father gives me will come to me, and whoever comes to me I will never cast out. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Abner called to Joab, “Shall the sword devour forever? Do you not know that the end will be bitter? How long will it be before you tell your people to turn from the pursuit of their brothers?”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 2,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then Jesus said to him, “Put your sword back into its place. For all who take the sword will perish by the sword. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 26,52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight, so that you may be justified in your words and blameless in your judgment. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ—by grace you have been saved— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>O God, from my youth you have taught me, and I still proclaim your wondrous deeds.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The silver is mine, and the gold is mine, declares the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Haggai 2,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Sell your possessions, and give to the needy. Provide yourselves with moneybags that do not grow old, with a treasure in the heavens that does not fail, where no thief approaches and no moth destroys. For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,33.34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-01-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The children of your servants shall dwell secure; their offspring shall be established before you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 102,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I am the Alpha and the Omega,” says the Lord God, “who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and you have not delivered me into the hand of the enemy; you have set my feet in a broad place. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Until now you have asked nothing in my name. Ask, and you will receive, that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>then shall the lame man leap like a deer, and the tongue of the mute sing for joy. For waters break forth in the wilderness, and streams in the desert; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 35,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Spirit and the Bride say, “Come.” And let the one who hears say, “Come.” And let the one who is thirsty come; let the one who desires take the water of life without price. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh, magnify the Lord with me, and let us exalt his name together! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, rejoice. Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The fear of man lays a snare, but whoever trusts in the Lord is safe. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 29,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now who is there to harm you if you are zealous for what is good? But even if you should suffer for righteousness’ sake, you will be blessed. Have no fear of them, nor be troubled, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord looks down from heaven on the children of man, to see if there are any who understand, who seek after God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 14,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But grow in the grace and knowledge of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. To him be the glory both now and to the day of eternity. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>lest, when you have eaten and are full and have built good houses and live in them, then your heart be lifted up, and you forget the Lord your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,12.14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For who sees anything different in you? What do you have that you did not receive? If then you received it, why do you boast as if you did not receive it? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“It is I who by my great power and my outstretched arm have made the earth, with the men and animals that are on the earth, and I give it to whomever it seems right to me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 27,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights, with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But who can endure the day of his coming, and who can stand when he appears? For he is like a refiner’s fire and like fullers’ soap. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi
3,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that you are not lacking in any gift, as you wait for the revealing of our Lord Jesus Christ, who will sustain you to the end, guiltless in the day of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,7-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the one who by his strength established the mountains, being girded with might; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 65,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will rejoice in Jerusalem and be glad in my people; no more shall be heard in it the sound of weeping and the cry of distress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My dwelling place shall be with them, and I will be their God, and they shall be my people. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Septuagesimae (70 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Behold, you shall call a nation that you do not know, and a nation that did not know you shall run to you, because of the Lord your God, and of the Holy One of Israel, for he has glorified you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And people will come from east and west, and from north and south, and recline at table in the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have set our iniquities before you, our secret sins in the light of your presence. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 90,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For nothing is hidden that will not be made manifest, nor is anything secret that will not be known and come to light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> “You are the Lord, you alone. You have made heaven, the heaven of heavens, with all their host, the earth and all that is on it, the seas and all that is in them; and you preserve all of them; and the host of heaven worships you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Come, everyone who thirsts, come to the waters; and he who has no money, come, buy and eat! Come, buy wine and milk without money and without price. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he came down with them and stood on a level place, with a great crowd of his disciples and a great multitude of people from all Judea and Jerusalem and the seacoast of Tyre and Sidon, who came to hear him and to be healed of their diseases. And those who were troubled with unclean spirits were cured. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he knows our frame; he remembers that we are dust. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 103,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel, “My way is hidden from the Lord, and my right is disregarded by my God”? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I was ready to be sought by those who did not ask for me; I was ready to be found by those who did not seek me. I said, “Here I am, here I am,” to a nation that was not called by my name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. Once you were not a people, but now you are God’s people; once you had not received mercy, but now you have received mercy. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Sexagesimae (60 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord your God will make you abundantly prosperous in all the work of your hand, in the fruit of your womb and in the fruit of your cattle and in the fruit of your ground. For the Lord will again take delight in prospering you, as he took delight in your fathers, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am reminded of your sincere faith, a faith that dwelt first in your grandmother Lois and your mother Eunice and now, I am sure, dwells in you as well. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have set my bow in the cloud, and it shall be a sign of the covenant between me and the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 9,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Lift up your eyes on high and see: who created these? He who brings out their host by number, calling them all by name; by the greatness of his might and because he is strong in power, not one is missing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things were created through him and for him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>therefore, behold, I will again do wonderful things with this people, with wonder upon wonder; and the wisdom of their wise men shall perish, and the discernment of their discerning men shall be hidden.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he will turn many of the children of Israel to the Lord their God,  and he will go before him in the spirit and power of Elijah, to turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the disobedient to the wisdom of the just, to make ready for the Lord a people prepared.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,16-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Restore to me the joy of your salvation, and uphold me with a willing spirit.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I will arise and go to my father, and I will say to him, “Father, I have sinned against heaven and before you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In all their affliction he was afflicted, and the angel of his presence saved them; in his love and in his pity he redeemed them; he lifted them up and carried them all the days of old. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you were straying like sheep, but have now returned to the Shepherd and Overseer of your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whom have I in heaven but you? And there is nothing on earth that I desire besides you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 73,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Though you have not seen him, you love him. Though you do not now see him, you believe in him and rejoice with joy that is inexpressible and filled with glory, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Estomihi (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag><Losungstext> “You are the Lord, you alone. You have made heaven, the heaven of heavens, with all their host, the earth and all that is on it, the seas and all that is in them; and you preserve all of them; and the host of heaven worships you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In him was life, and the life was the light of men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For
the word of the Lord is upright, and all his work is done in faithfulness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfill them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-02-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your steadfast love, O Lord, be upon us, even as we hope in you.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 33,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Nevertheless, do not rejoice in this, that the spirits are subject to you, but rejoice that your names are written in heaven.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But,” he said, “you cannot see my face, for man shall not see me and live.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now faith is the assurance of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen. For by it the people of old received their commendation.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My tears have been my food day and night, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 42,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And not only the creation, but we ourselves, who have the firstfruits of the Spirit, groan inwardly as we wait eagerly for adoption as sons, the redemption of our bodies. For in this hope we were saved. Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,23-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you have kept with your servant David my father what you declared to him. You spoke with your mouth, and with your hand have fulfilled it this day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you have tasted that the Lord is good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember me, O Lord, when you show favor to your people; help me when you save them, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 106,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But I received mercy for this reason, that in me, as the foremost, Jesus Christ might display his perfect patience as an example to those who were to believe in him for eternal life.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming,” declares the Lord God, “when I will send a famine on the land— not a famine of bread, nor a thirst for water, but of hearing the words of the Lord. They shall wander from sea to sea, and from north to east; they shall run to and fro, to seek the word of the Lord, but they shall not find it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 8,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, and we have believed, and have come to know, that you are the Holy One of God.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,68-69</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Ruth said, “Do not urge me to leave you or to return from following you. For where you go I will go, and where you lodge I will lodge. Your people shall be my people, and your God my God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ruth 1,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Praise the Lord! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for it is pleasant, and a song of praise is fitting. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why are you cast down, O my soul, and why are you in turmoil within me? Hope in God; for I shall again praise him, my salvation and my God.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 42,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Truly, truly, I say to you, you will weep and lament, but the world will rejoice. You will be sorrowful, but your sorrow will turn into joy. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For who is God, but the Lord? And who is a rock, except our God?— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 18,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And God said to him, “Because you have asked this, and have not asked for yourself long life or riches or the life of your enemies, but have asked for yourself understanding to discern what is right,  behold, I now do according to your word. Behold, I give you a wise and discerning mind, so that none like you has been before you and none like you shall arise after you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 3,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They confronted me in the day of my calamity, but the Lord was my support.  He brought me out into a broad place; he rescued me, because he delighted in me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 22,19-20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Reminiszere (Gedenke, HERR, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: “Stand by the roads, and look, and ask for the ancient paths, where the good way is; and walk in it, and find rest for your souls. But they said, ‘We will not walk in it.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 6,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that you may not be sluggish, but imitators of those who through faith and patience inherit the promises. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Therefore the Lord, the God of Israel, declares: ‘I promised that your house and the house of your father should go in and out before me forever,’ but now the Lord declares: ‘Far be it from me, for those who honor me I will honor, and those who despise me shall be lightly esteemed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,30</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You call me Teacher and Lord, and you are right, for so I am. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 13,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you have been a stronghold to the poor, a stronghold to the needy in his distress, a shelter from the storm and a shade from the heat; for the breath of the ruthless is like a storm against a wall, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?  No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,35.37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My eyes are awake before the watches of the night, that I may meditate on your promise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,148</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Mary treasured up all these things, pondering them in her heart. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why is my pain unceasing, my wound incurable, refusing to be healed? Will you be to me like a deceitful brook, like waters that fail? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 15,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For now we see in a mirror dimly, but then face to face. Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Teach me your way, O Lord, that I may walk in your truth; unite my heart to fear your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 86,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And going on from there he saw two other brothers, James the son of Zebedee and John his brother, in the boat with Zebedee their father, mending their nets, and he called them.  Immediately they left the boat and their father and followed him.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 4,21-22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I am a sojourner
on the earth; hide not your commandments from me! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But our citizenship is in heaven, and from it we await a Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Okuli  (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den HERRN. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is a merciful God. He will not leave you or destroy you or forget the covenant with your fathers that he swore to them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The lines have fallen for me in pleasant places; indeed, I have a beautiful inheritance. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 16,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that having all sufficiency in all things at all times, you may abound in every good work. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He was despised and rejected by men, a man of sorrows and acquainted with grief; and as one from whom men hide their faces he was despised, and we esteemed him not. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He released the man who had been thrown into prison for insurrection and murder, for whom they asked, but he delivered Jesus over to their will. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 23,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>How great are his signs, how mighty his wonders! His kingdom is an everlasting kingdom, and his dominion endures from generation to generation.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 3,33</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Fear not, little flock, for it is your Father’s good pleasure to give you the kingdom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then the nations that are left all around you shall know that I am the Lord; I have rebuilt the ruined places and replanted that which was desolate. I am the Lord; I have spoken, and I will do it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,36</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for my eyes have seen your salvation that you have prepared in the presence of all peoples, a light for revelation to the Gentiles, and for glory to your people Israel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,30-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but with righteousness he shall judge the poor, and decide with equity for the meek of the earth; and he shall strike the earth with the rod of his mouth, and with the breath of his lips he shall kill the wicked. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he lifted up his eyes on his disciples, and said: “Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who has performed and done this, calling the generations from the beginning? I, the Lord, the first, and with the last; I am he. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that he worked in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly places, far above all rule and authority and power and dominion, and above every name that is named, not only in this age but also in the one to come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag><Losungstext>There is hope for your future, declares the Lord, and your children shall come back to their own country. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The neighbors and those who had seen him before as a beggar were saying, “Is this not the man who used to sit and beg?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 9,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will not let your foot be moved; he who keeps you will not slumber. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 121,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus immediately reached out his hand and took hold of him, saying to him, “O you of little faith, why did you doubt?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now when these signs meet you, do what your hand finds to do, for God is with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 10,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“The Lord is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“If a prophet or a dreamer of dreams arises among you and gives you a sign or a wonder, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to him, “Why do you ask me about what is good? There is only one who is good. If you would enter life, keep the commandments.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 19,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-03-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You crushed Rahab like a carcass; you scattered your enemies with your mighty arm. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 89,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they went and woke him, saying, “Master, Master, we are perishing!” And he awoke and rebuked the wind and the raging waves, and they ceased, and there was a calm. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“So you shall keep my commandments and do them: I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 22,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For this is the love of God, that we keep his commandments. And his commandments are not burdensome. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Judika (Gott, schaffe mir Recht! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Behold, I have refined you, but not as silver; I have tried you in the furnace of affliction. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we who live are always being given over to death for Jesus’ sake, so that the life of Jesus also may be manifested in our mortal flesh.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The jar of flour was not spent, neither did the jug of oil become empty, according to the word of the Lord that he spoke by Elijah.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 17,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Give us each day our daily bread, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If I say, “Surely the darkness shall cover me, and the light about me be night,” even the darkness is not dark to you; the night is bright as the day, for darkness is as light with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 139,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is the message we have heard from him and proclaim to you, that God is light, and in him is no darkness at all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yet I will leave seven thousand in Israel, all the knees that have not bowed to Baal, and every mouth that has not kissed him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 19,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“You are those who have stayed with me in my trials, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They do not say in their hearts, ‘Let us fear the Lord our God, who gives the rain in its season, the autumn rain and the spring rain, and keeps for us the weeks appointed for the harvest.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 5,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet he did not leave himself without witness, for he did good by giving you rains from heaven and fruitful seasons, satisfying your hearts with food and gladness.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They still bear fruit in old age; they are ever full of sap and green,  to declare that the Lord is upright; he is my rock, and there is no unrighteousness in him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 92,14-15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and may the Lord make you increase and abound in love for one another and
for all, as we do for you, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who drink wine in bowls and anoint themselves with the finest oils, but are not grieved over the ruin of Joseph! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 6,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Bear one another’s burdens, and so fulfill the law of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Palmsonntag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For I will pour water on the thirsty land, and streams on the dry ground; I will pour my Spirit upon your offspring, and my blessing on your descendants. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the chief priests and the scribes saw the wonderful things that he did, and the children crying out in the temple, “Hosanna to the Son of David!” they were indignant, and they said to him, “Do you hear what these are saying?” And Jesus said to them, “Yes; have you never read, “‘Out of the mouth of infants and nursing babies you have prepared praise’?” And leaving them, he went out of the city to Bethany and lodged there. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 21,15-17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,57</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>yet I will remember my covenant with you in the days of your youth, and I will establish for you an everlasting covenant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 16,60</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the promise is for you and for your children and for all who are far off, everyone whom the Lord our God calls to himself.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Hannah prayed and said, “My heart exults in the Lord; my horn is exalted in the Lord. My mouth derides my enemies, because I rejoice in your salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>No longer do I call you servants, for the servant does not know what his master is doing; but I have called you friends, for all that I have heard from my Father I have made known to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Between the vestibule and the altar let the priests, the ministers of the Lord, weep and say, “Spare your people, O Lord, and make not your heritage a reproach, a byword among the nations. Why should they say among the peoples, ‘Where is their God?’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The next day he saw Jesus coming toward him, and said, “Behold, the Lamb of God, who takes away the sin of the world! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Remember also your Creator in the days of your youth, before the evil days come and the years draw near of which you will say, “I have no pleasure in them”; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 12,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said, “Jesus, remember me when you come into your kingdom.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 23,42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall remember the Lord your God, for it is he who gives you power to get wealth, that he may confirm his covenant that he swore to your fathers, as it is this day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When Jesus saw his mother and the disciple whom he loved standing nearby, he said to his mother, “Woman, behold, your son!” Then he said to the disciple, “Behold, your mother!” And from that hour the disciple took her to his own home. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 19,26-27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>The years of our life are seventy, or even by reason of strength eighty; yet their span is but toil and trouble; they are soon gone, and we fly away.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 90,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the perishable puts on the imperishable, and the mortal puts on immortality, then shall come to pass the saying that is written: “Death is swallowed up in victory.” “O death, where is your victory? O death, where is your sting?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,54-55</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You shall say to them, Thus says the Lord: When men fall, do they not rise again? If one turns away, does he not return? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He said to him the third time, “Simon, son of John, do you love me?” Peter was grieved because he said to him the third time, “Do you love me?” and he said to him, “Lord, you know everything; you know that I love you.” Jesus said to him, “Feed my sheep. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 21,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In the day of prosperity be joyful, and in the day of adversity consider: God has made the one as well as the other, so that man may not find out anything that will be after him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 7,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I know how to be brought low, and I know how to abound. In any and every circumstance, I have learned the secret of facing plenty and hunger, abundance and need. I can do all things through him who strengthens me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,12-13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus shall you say, every one to his neighbor and every one to his brother, ‘What has the Lord answered?’ or ‘What has the Lord spoken?’  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,35</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Samuel said to all the house of Israel, “If you are returning to the Lord with all your heart, then put away the foreign gods and the Ashtaroth from among you and direct your heart to the Lord and serve him only, and he will deliver you out of the hand of the Philistines.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 7,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Only let your manner of life be worthy of the gospel of Christ, so that whether I come and see you or am absent, I may hear of you that you are standing firm in one spirit, with one mind striving side by side for the faith of the gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And a stone was brought and laid on the mouth of the den, and the king sealed it with his own signet and with the signet of his lords, that nothing might be changed concerning Daniel. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will bear the indignation of the Lord because I have sinned against him, until he pleads my cause and executes judgment for me. He will bring me out to the light; I shall look upon his vindication. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When he was at table with them, he took the bread and blessed and broke it and gave it to them. And their eyes were opened, and they recognized him. And he vanished from their sight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,30-31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag><Losungstext>So you shall keep the commandments of the Lord your God by walking in his ways and by fearing him.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Owe no one anything, except to love each other, for the one who loves another has fulfilled the law. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 13,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As for me, I am poor and needy, but the Lord takes thought for me. You are my help and my deliverer; do not delay, O my God! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus came to the place, he looked up and said to him, “Zacchaeus, hurry and come down, for I must stay at your house today.” So he hurried and came down and received
him joyfully. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord God is a sun and shield; the Lord bestows favor and honor. No good thing does he withhold from those who walk uprightly. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 84,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and will go in and out and find pasture. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who have made me see many troubles and calamities will revive me again; from the depths of the earth you will bring me up again. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Let not your hearts be troubled. Believe in God; believe also in me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Remember not the former things, nor consider the things of old. Behold, I am doing a new thing; now it springs forth, do you not perceive it? I will make a way in the wilderness and rivers in the desert. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,18-19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>It is like a grain of mustard seed that a man took and sowed in his garden, and it grew and became a tree, and the birds of the air made nests in its branches.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Nebuchadnezzar answered and said, “Blessed be the God of Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego, who has sent his angel and delivered his servants, who trusted in him, and set aside the king’s command, and yielded up their bodies rather than serve and worship any god except their own God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 3,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, an angel of the Lord stood next to him, and a light shone in the cell. He struck Peter on the side and woke him, saying, “Get up quickly.” And the chains fell off his hands. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 12,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who has believed what he has heard from us? And to whom has the arm of the Lord been revealed? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>At the same time, pray also for us, that God may open to us a door for the word, to declare the mystery of Christ, on account of which I am in prison— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-04-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag><Losungstext>It is he who remembered us in our low estate, for his steadfast love endures forever; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 136,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So if the Son sets you free, you will be free indeed.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“O house of Israel, can I not do with you as this potter has done? declares the Lord. Behold, like the clay in the potter’s hand, so are you in my hand, O house of Israel. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 18,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand, that we should walk in them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>learn to do good; seek justice, correct oppression; bring justice to the fatherless, plead the widow’s cause. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 1,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that according to the riches of his glory he may grant you to be strengthened with power through his Spirit in your inner being, so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith—that you, being rooted and grounded in love, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,16.17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the Lord that will stand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 19,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Instead of bronze I will bring gold, and instead of iron I will bring silver; instead of wood, bronze, instead of stones, iron. I will make your overseers peace and your taskmasters righteousness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the wisdom from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, open to reason, full of mercy and good fruits, impartial and sincere. And a harvest of righteousness is sown in peace by those who make peace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 3,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“If among you, one of your brothers should become poor, in any of your towns within your land that the Lord your God is giving you, you shall not harden your heart or shut your hand against your poor brother, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 15,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But if anyone has the world’s goods and sees his brother in need, yet closes his heart against him, how does God’s love abide in him? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, he who keeps Israel will neither slumber nor sleep.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 121,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>My mouth is filled with your praise, and with your glory all the day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice always, pray without ceasing, give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,16-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I shall not die, but I shall live, and recount the deeds of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when they had inflicted many blows upon them, they threw them into prison, ordering the jailer to keep them safely.  About midnight Paul and Silas were praying and singing hymns to God, and the prisoners were listening to them, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,23.25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Were I to write for him my laws by the ten thousands, they would be regarded as a strange thing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 8,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am astonished that you are so quickly deserting him who called you in the grace of Christ and are turning to a different gospel— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whoever mocks the poor insults his Maker; he who is glad at calamity will not go unpunished. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 17,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“See that you do not despise one of these little ones. For I tell you that in heaven their angels always see the face of my Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you, O Lord, are my hope, my trust, O Lord, from my youth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we do not lose heart. Though our outer self is wasting away, our inner self is being renewed day by day. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hear, you peoples, all of you; pay attention, O earth, and all that is in it, and let the Lord God be a witness against you, the Lord from his holy temple. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 1,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Go into all the world and proclaim the gospel to the whole creation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the voice of mirth and the voice of gladness, the voice of the bridegroom and the voice of the bride, the voices of those who sing, as they bring thank offerings to the house of the Lord: “‘Give thanks to the Lord of hosts, for the Lord is good, for his steadfast love endures forever!’ For I will restore the fortunes of the land as at first, says the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The one who has the bride is the bridegroom. The friend of the bridegroom, who stands and hears him, rejoices greatly at the bridegroom’s voice. Therefore this joy of mine is now complete. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 3,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Kantate
(Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>I will take you to be my people, and I will be your God, and you shall know that I am the Lord your God, who has brought you out from under the burdens of the Egyptians. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 6,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>See what kind of love the Father has given to us, that we should be called children of God; and so we are. The reason why the world does not know us is that it did not know him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For evils have encompassed me beyond number; my iniquities have overtaken me, and I cannot see; they are more than the hairs of my head; my heart fails me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 40,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace himself sanctify you completely, and may your whole spirit and soul and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ. He who calls you is faithful; he will surely do it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,23-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The words of the Lord are pure words, like silver refined in a furnace on the ground, purified seven times. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 12,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, the Lord has proclaimed to the end of the earth: Say to the daughter of Zion, “Behold, your salvation comes; behold, his reward is with him, and his recompense before him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 62,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For all the promises of God find their Yes in him. That is why it is through him that we utter our Amen to God for his glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So when the woman saw that the tree was good for food, and that it was a delight to the eyes, and that the tree was to be desired to make one wise, she took of its fruit and ate, and she also gave some to her husband who was with her, and he ate. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 3,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For what does it profit a man if he gains the whole world and loses or forfeits himself? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who executes justice for the oppressed, who gives food to the hungry. The Lord sets the prisoners free; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 146,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>They said to him, “We have only five loaves here and two fish.”  And he said, “Bring them here to me.”  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said to Moses, “Is the Lord’s hand shortened? Now you shall see whether my word will come true for you or not.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 11,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>fully convinced that God was able to do what he had promised. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 4,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag><Losungstext>At Gibeon the Lord appeared to Solomon in a dream by night, and God said, “Ask what I shall give you.” Give your servant therefore an understanding mind to govern your people, that I may discern between good and evil, for who is able to govern this your great people?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 3,5.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If any of you lacks wisdom, let him ask God, who gives generously to all without reproach, and it will be given him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For thus says the Lord to the men of Judah and Jerusalem: “Break up your fallow ground, and sow not among thorns. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 4,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whoever despises his neighbor is a sinner, but blessed is he who is generous to the poor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>See that no one repays anyone evil for evil, but always seek to do good to one another and to everyone. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Know therefore that the Lord your God is God, the faithful God who keeps covenant and steadfast love with those who love him and keep his commandments, to a thousand generations, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is eternal life, that they know you, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Himmelfahrt des Herrn</Sonntag><Losungstext>“And those who are far off shall come and help to build the temple of the Lord. And you shall know that the Lord of hosts has sent me to you. And this shall come to pass, if you will diligently obey the voice of the Lord your God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 6,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Ananias answered, “Lord, I have heard from many about this man, how much evil he has done to your saints at Jerusalem. But the Lord said to him, “Go, for he is a chosen instrument of mine to carry my name before the Gentiles and kings and the children of Israel. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 9,13.15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who alone stretched out the heavens and trampled the waves of the sea; who made the Bear and Orion, the Pleiades and the chambers of the south; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,8.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said with a loud voice, “Fear God and give him glory, because the hour of his judgment has come, and worship him who made heaven and earth, the sea and the springs of water.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 14,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And when the Lord smelled the pleasing aroma, the Lord said in his heart, “I will never again curse the ground because of man, for the intention of man’s heart is evil from his youth. Neither will I ever again strike down every living creature as I have done. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 8,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You know that he appeared in order to take away sins, and in him there is no sin. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag><Losungstext>But you do see, for you note mischief and vexation, that you may take it into your hands; to you the helpless commits himself; you have been the helper of the fatherless. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 10,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the crowds learned it, they followed him, and he welcomed them and spoke to them of the kingdom of God and cured those who had need of healing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you bless the righteous, O Lord; you cover him with favor as with a shield.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 5,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“I am the Lord; I have called you in righteousness; I will take you by the hand and keep you; I will give you as a covenant for the people, a light for the nations, to open the eyes that are blind, to bring out the prisoners from the dungeon, from the prison those who sit in darkness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,6.7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them, and those who are mistreated, since you also are in the body. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-05-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My eyes are ever toward the Lord, for he will pluck my feet out of the net. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You also, be patient. Establish your hearts, for the coming of the Lord is at hand. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But David’s heart struck him after he had numbered the people. And David said to the Lord, “I have sinned greatly in what I have done. But now, O Lord, please take away the iniquity of your servant, for I have done very foolishly.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2
Samuel 24,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When I remember God, I moan; when I meditate, my spirit faints. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 77,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the Lord direct your hearts to the love of God and to the steadfastness of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord God has given me the tongue of those who are taught, that I may know how to sustain with a word him who is weary. Morning by morning he awakens; he awakens my ear to hear as those who are taught. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>One who heard us was a woman named Lydia, from the city of Thyatira, a seller of purple goods, who was a worshiper of God. The Lord opened her heart to pay attention to what was said by Paul. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>But I am the Lord your God from the land of Egypt; you know no God but me, and besides me there is no savior. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 13,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this we know that we abide in him and he in us, because he has given us of his Spirit. And we have seen and testify that the Father has sent his Son to be the Savior of the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord God has given me the tongue of those who are taught, that I may know how to sustain with a word him who is weary. Morning by morning he awakens; he awakens my ear to hear as those who are taught. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, O God my Lord, deal on my behalf for your name’s sake; because your steadfast love is good, deliver me! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 109,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he arose and came to his father. But while he was still a long way off, his father saw him and felt compassion, and ran and embraced him and kissed him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing to God, sing praises to his name; lift up a song to him who rides through the deserts; his name is the Lord; exult before him! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 68,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God is not a matter of eating and drinking but of righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits, who forgives all your iniquity, who heals all your diseases, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 103,2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And leaping up, he stood and began to walk, and entered the temple with them, walking and leaping and praising God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 3,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the full number of those who believed were of one heart and soul, and no one said that any of the things that belonged to him was his own, but they had everything in common. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I say to the Lord, “You are my Lord; I have no good apart from you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 16,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Brothers, I do not consider that I have made it my own. But one thing I do: forgetting what lies behind and straining forward to what lies ahead, I press on toward the goal for the prize of the upward call of God in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,13-14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag><Losungstext>He sends out his command to the earth; his word runs swiftly. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 147,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“I, I am he who comforts you; who are you that you are afraid of man who dies, of the son of man who is made like grass, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But even if you should suffer for righteousness’ sake, you will be blessed. Have no fear of them, nor be troubled, but in your hearts honor Christ the Lord as holy, always being prepared to make a defense to anyone who asks you for a reason for the hope that is in you; yet do it with gentleness and respect, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,14-15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“As for me, I would seek God, and to God would I commit my cause,  who does great things and unsearchable, marvelous things without number: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 5,8-9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The sick man answered him, “Sir, I have no one to put me into the pool when the water is stirred up, and while I am going another steps down before me.”  Jesus said to him, “Get up, take up your bed, and walk.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 5,7-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When he calls to me, I will answer him; I will be with him in trouble; I will rescue him and honor him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will heal their apostasy; I will love them freely, for my anger has turned from them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 14,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>whether Paul or Apollos or Cephas or the world or life or death or the present or the future—all are yours,  and you are Christ’s, and Christ is God’s. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,22-23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Rejoice with Jerusalem, and be glad for her, all you who love her; rejoice with her in joy, all you who mourn over her; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then the righteous will shine like the sun in the kingdom of their Father. He who has ears, let him hear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,43</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Why do you contend with me? You have all transgressed against me, declares the Lord.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>saying, “Would that you, even you, had known on this day the things that make for peace! But now they are hidden from your eyes. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Because he holds fast to me in love, I will deliver him; I will protect him, because he knows my name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 91,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The one who conquers, I will make him a pillar in the temple of my God. Never shall he go out of it, and I will write on him the name of my God, and the name of the city of my God, the new Jerusalem, which comes down from my God out of heaven, and my own new name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The wise men shall be put to shame; they shall be dismayed and taken; behold, they have rejected the word of the Lord, so what wisdom is in them? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that your faith might not rest in the wisdom of men but in the power of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 2,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deep calls to deep at the roar of your waterfalls; all your breakers and your waves have gone over me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 42,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John
14,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O my God, I cry by day, but you do not answer, and by night, but I find no rest. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 22,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For because he himself has suffered when tempted, he is able to help those who are being tempted. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and houses full of all good things that you did not fill, and cisterns that you did not dig, and vineyards and olive trees that you did not plant—and when you eat and are full,  then take care lest you forget the Lord, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,11-12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So, whether you eat or drink, or whatever you do, do all to the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, be gracious to us; we wait for you. Be our arm every morning, our salvation in the time of trouble. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Johannistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For behold, your enemies make an uproar; those who hate you have raised their heads. They lay crafty plans against your people; they consult together against your treasured ones. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 83,2-3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the oath that he swore to our father Abraham, to grant us that we, being delivered from the hand of our enemies, might serve him without fear, in holiness and righteousness before him all our days. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,73-75</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>So do not fear; I will provide for you and your little ones.” Thus he comforted them and spoke kindly to them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 50,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And take not the word of truth utterly out of my mouth, for my hope is in your rules. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,43</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is how one should regard us, as servants of Christ and stewards of the mysteries of God. Moreover, it is required of stewards that they be found faithful.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember these things, O Jacob, and Israel, for you are my servant; I formed you; you are my servant; O Israel, you will not be forgotten by me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I ask, then, has God rejected his people? By no means! For I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham, a member of the tribe of Benjamin. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Day to day pours out speech, and night to night reveals knowledge.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 19,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he came up out of the water, immediately he saw the heavens being torn open and the Spirit descending on him like a dove. And a voice came from heaven, “You are my beloved Son; with you I am well pleased.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,10-11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deliver me from sinking in the mire; let me be delivered from my enemies and from the deep waters. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 69,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Is anyone among you suffering? Let him pray. Is anyone cheerful? Let him sing praise. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-06-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the people of Israel said to the Lord, “We have sinned; do to us whatever seems good to you. Only please deliver us this day.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 10,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When I thought, “My foot slips,” your steadfast love, O Lord, held me up. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 94,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And it is God who establishes us with you in Christ, and has anointed us, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You shall not oppress your neighbor or rob him. The wages of a hired worker shall not remain with you all night until the morning. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If I say, “I will not mention him, or speak any more in his name,” there is in my heart as it were a burning fire shut up in my bones, and I am weary with holding it in, and I cannot. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 20,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for we cannot but speak of what we have seen and heard.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember the days of old; consider the years of many generations; ask your father, and he will show you, your elders, and they will tell you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Jesus called them to him, saying, “Let the children come to me, and do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Abraham answered and said, “Behold, I have undertaken to speak to the Lord, I who am but dust and ashes. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 18,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Also henceforth I am he; there is none who can deliver from my hand; I work, and who can turn it back?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He has shown strength with his arm; he has scattered the proud in the thoughts of their hearts; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,51</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Put no trust in extortion; set no vain hopes on robbery; if riches increase, set not your heart on them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 62,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>This is the day that the Lord has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the father said to his servants, ‘Bring quickly the best robe, and put it on him, and put a ring on his hand, and shoes on his feet. And bring the fattened calf and kill it, and let us eat and celebrate. For this my son was dead, and is alive again; he was lost, and is found.’ And they began to celebrate. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,22-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Sing aloud, O daughter of Zion; shout, O Israel! Rejoice and exult with all your heart, O daughter of Jerusalem! The Lord has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies. The King of Israel, the Lord, is in your midst; you shall never again fear evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,14-15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Of this man’s offspring God has brought to Israel a Savior, Jesus, as he promised. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 13,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 1,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By faith we understand that the universe was created by the word of God, so that what is seen was not made out of things that are visible. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be
to me a rock of refuge, to which I may continually come; you have given the command to save me, for you are my rock and my fortress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 71,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he had said these things, he knelt down and prayed with them all. And there was much weeping on the part of all; they embraced Paul and kissed him, being sorrowful most of all because of the word he had spoken, that they would not see his face again. And they accompanied him to the ship. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 20,36-38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will not hide my face anymore from them, when I pour out my Spirit upon the house of Israel, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 39,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In him you also, when you heard the word of truth, the gospel of your salvation, and believed in him, were sealed with the promised Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“But will God indeed dwell on the earth? Behold, heaven and the highest heaven cannot contain you; how much less this house that I have built! </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>No one has ever seen God; the only God, who is at the Father’s side, he has made him known. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Steadfast love and faithfulness meet; righteousness and peace kiss each other. Faithfulness springs up from the ground, and righteousness looks down from the sky.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 85,10.11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But according to his promise we are waiting for new heavens and a new earth in which righteousness dwells. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now therefore, if I have found favor in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favor in your sight. Consider too that this nation is your people.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To him the gatekeeper opens. The sheep hear his voice, and he calls his own sheep by name and leads them out.  When he has brought out all his own, he goes before them, and the sheep follow him, for they know his voice.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Trust in him at all times, O people; pour out your heart before him; God is a refuge for us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 62,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but I have prayed for you that your faith may not fail. And when you have turned again, strengthen your brothers.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will cut off the chariot from Ephraim and the war horse from Jerusalem; and the battle bow shall be cut off, and he shall speak peace to the nations; his rule shall be from sea to sea, and from the River to the ends of the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but in every nation anyone who fears him and does what is right is acceptable to him. As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,35-36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>All the paths of the Lord are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“One who is faithful in a very little is also faithful in much, and one who is dishonest in a very little is also dishonest in much. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 16,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>saying, “If you will diligently listen to the voice of the Lord your God, and do that which is right in his eyes, and give ear to his commandments and keep all his statutes, I will put none of the diseases on you that I put on the Egyptians, for I am the Lord, your healer.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 15,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will heal their apostasy; I will love them freely, for my anger has turned from them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 14,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life. “I know your tribulation and your poverty (but you are rich) and the slander of those who say that they are Jews and are not, but are a synagogue of Satan. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 2,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord! We bless you from the house of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 118,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In this the love of God was made manifest among us, that God sent his only Son into the world, so that we might live through him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You meet him who joyfully works righteousness, those who remember you in your ways. Behold, you were angry, and we sinned; in our sins we have been a long time, and shall we be saved?  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 64,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Lord turned and looked at Peter. And Peter remembered the saying of the Lord, how he had said to him, “Before the rooster crows today, you will deny me three times.” And he went out and wept bitterly.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,61-62</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Talk no more so very proudly, let not arrogance come from your mouth; for the Lord is a God of knowledge, and by him actions are weighed.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Little children, let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And I will give you shepherds after my own heart, who will feed you with knowledge and understanding. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>First of all, then, I urge that supplications, prayers, intercessions, and thanksgivings be made for all people,  for kings and all who are in high positions, that we may lead a peaceful and quiet life, godly and dignified in every way. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you have delivered my soul from death, my eyes from tears, my feet from stumbling; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 116,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Indeed he was ill, near to death. But God had mercy on him, and not only on him but on me also, lest I should have sorrow upon sorrow.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>There is Benjamin, the least of them, in the lead, the princes of Judah in their throng, the princes of Zebulun, the princes of Naphtali. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 68,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of endurance and encouragement grant you to live in such harmony with one another, in accord with Christ Jesus, that together you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,5-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Samuel said, “Has the Lord as great delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices, as in obeying the voice of the Lord? Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice, and to listen than the fat of rams. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 15,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said, “Blessed rather are those who hear the word of God and keep it!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who provides for the raven its prey, when its young ones cry to God for help, and wander about for lack of food? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 38,41</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; for the same Lord is Lord of all, bestowing his riches on all who call on him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 10,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Surely a man goes about as a shadow! Surely for nothing they are in turmoil; man heaps up wealth and does not know who will gather! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm
39,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I do not ask that you take them out of the world, but that you keep them from the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Do not trust in these deceptive words: ‘This is the temple of the Lord, the temple of the Lord, the temple of the Lord.’ “For if you truly amend your ways and your deeds, if you truly execute justice one with another, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 7,4-5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God does not consist in talk but in power. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-07-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For behold, on the stone that I have set before Joshua, on a single stone with seven eyes, I will engrave its inscription, declares the Lord of hosts, and I will remove the iniquity of this land in a single day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>This God—his way is perfect; the word of the Lord proves true; he is a shield for all those who take refuge in him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 18,30</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For everyone who has been born of God overcomes the world. And this is the victory that has overcome the world—our faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord, your Redeemer, who formed you from the womb: “I am the Lord, who made all things, who alone stretched out the heavens, who spread out the earth by myself, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The God who made the world and everything in it, being Lord of heaven and earth, does not live in temples made by man, nor is he served by human hands, as though he needed anything, since he himself gives to all mankind life and breath and everything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,24-25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Trust in the Lord forever, for the Lord God is an everlasting rock.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He said to them, “Where is your faith?” And they were afraid, and they marveled, saying to one another, “Who then is this, that he commands even winds and water, and they obey him?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then David said to the Philistine, “You come to me with a sword and with a spear and with a javelin, but I come to you in the name of the Lord of hosts, the God of the armies of Israel, whom you have defied. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,45</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that according to the riches of his glory he may grant you to be strengthened with power through his Spirit in your inner being, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whether it is good or bad, we will obey the voice of the Lord our God to whom we are sending you, that it may be well with us when we obey the voice of the Lord our God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 42,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not quench the Spirit. Do not despise prophecies, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Glory in his holy name; let the hearts of those who seek the Lord rejoice!  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the first day of the week, when we were gathered together to break bread, Paul talked with them, intending to depart on the next day, and he prolonged his speech until midnight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 20,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>he reveals deep and hidden things; he knows what is in the darkness, and the light dwells with him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Helper, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, he will teach you all things and bring to your remembrance all that I have said to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I was ready to be sought by those who did not ask for me; I was ready to be found by those who did not seek me. I said, “Here I am, here I am,” to a nation that was not called by my name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the servant said, ‘Sir, what you commanded has been done, and still there is room.’  And the master said to the servant, ‘Go out to the highways and hedges and compel people to come in, that my house may be filled.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,22-23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord gives wisdom; from his mouth come knowledge and understanding; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 2,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus returned in the power of the Spirit to Galilee, and a report about him went out through all the surrounding country. And he taught in their synagogues, being glorified by all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 4,14-15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh, fear the Lord, you his saints, for those who fear him have no lack!  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am the living bread that came down from heaven. If anyone eats of this bread, he will live forever. And the bread that I will give for the life of the world is my flesh.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,51</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, I establish my covenant with you and your offspring after you, and with every living creature that is with you, the birds, the livestock, and every beast of the earth with you, as many as came out of the ark; it is for every beast of the earth. I establish my covenant with you, that never again shall all flesh be cut off by the waters of the flood, and never again shall there be a flood to destroy the earth.</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 9,9-10.11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that is, in Christ God was reconciling the world to himself, not counting their trespasses against them, and entrusting to us the message of reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And now, O Lord God, you are God, and your words are true, and you have promised this good thing to your servant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 7,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Many are the afflictions of the righteous, but the Lord delivers him out of them all. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Ananias departed and entered the house. And laying his hands on him he said, “Brother Saul, the Lord Jesus who appeared to you on the road by which you came has sent me so that you may regain your sight and be filled with the Holy Spirit.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 9,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Only be very careful to observe the commandment and the law that Moses the servant of the Lord commanded you, to love the Lord your God, and to walk in all his ways and to keep his commandments and to cling to him and to serve him with all your heart and with all your soul.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 22,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hear, O my people, while I admonish you! O Israel, if you would but listen to me! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 81,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And a leper came to him, imploring him, and kneeling said to him, “If you will, you can make me clean.” Moved with pity, he stretched out his hand and touched him and said to him, “I will; be clean.”  And immediately the leprosy left him, and he was made clean.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,40-42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But let justice roll down like waters, and righteousness like an ever-flowing stream.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 5,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who supplies seed to the sower and bread for food will supply and multiply your seed for sowing and increase the harvest of your righteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He keeps all his bones; not one of them is broken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But
though we had already suffered and been shamefully treated at Philippi, as you know, we had boldness in our God to declare to you the gospel of God in the midst of much conflict. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 2,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>With joy you will draw water from the wells of salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 12,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 7,37-38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your sun shall no more go down, nor your moon withdraw itself; for the Lord will be your everlasting light, and your days of mourning shall be ended. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“So may all your enemies perish, O Lord! But your friends be like the sun as he rises in his might.” And the land had rest for forty years. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 5,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord will not cast off forever, but, though he cause grief, he will have compassion according to the abundance of his steadfast love; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,31-32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord was gracious to them and had compassion on them, and he turned toward them, because of his covenant with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, and would not destroy them, nor has he cast them from his presence until now. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 13,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And if you are Christ’s, then you are Abraham’s offspring, heirs according to promise. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 3,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is God of gods and Lord of lords, the great, the mighty, and the awesome God, who is not partial and takes no bribe. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Once God has spoken; twice have I heard this: that power belongs to God, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 62,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Thus Joseph, who was also called by the apostles Barnabas (which means son of encouragement), a Levite, a native of Cyprus, sold a field that belonged to him and brought the money and laid it at the apostles’ feet. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,36-37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Also take these ten cheeses to the commander of their thousand. See if your brothers are well, and bring some token from them.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for Titus, he is my partner and fellow worker for your benefit. And as for our brothers, they are messengers of the churches, the glory of Christ. So give proof before the churches of your love and of our boasting about you to these men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,23-24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the angel of the Lord came again a second time and touched him and said, “Arise and eat, for the journey is too great for you.”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 19,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And now, Lord, look upon their threats and grant to your servants to continue to speak your word with all boldness, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>And the head of Ephraim is Samaria, and the head of Samaria is the son of Remaliah. If you are not firm in faith, you will not be firm at all.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Examine yourselves, to see whether you are in the faith. Test yourselves. Or do you not realize this about yourselves, that Jesus Christ is in you?—unless indeed you fail to meet the test! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord will be king over all the earth. On that day the Lord will be one and his name one. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 14,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who, though he was in the form of God, did not count equality with God a thing to be grasped, but emptied himself, by taking the form of a servant, being born in the likeness of men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,6-7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not say, “I will do to him as he has done to me; I will pay the man back for what he has done.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 24,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and if he sins against you seven times in the day, and turns to you seven times, saying, ‘I repent,’ you must forgive him.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He delivers and rescues; he works signs and wonders in heaven and on earth, he who has saved Daniel from the power of the lions.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “When you pray, say: “Father, hallowed be your name. Your kingdom come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-08-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, the hope of Israel, all who forsake you shall be put to shame; those who turn away from you shall be written in the earth, for they have forsaken the Lord, the fountain of living water. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 17,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And at the time for the banquet he sent his servant to say to those who had been invited, ‘Come, for everything is now ready.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Prayer of Moses, the man of God. Lord, you have been our dwelling place in all generations. Before the mountains were brought forth, or ever you had formed the earth and the world, from everlasting to everlasting you are God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 90,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>yet for us there is one God, the Father, from whom are all things and for whom we exist, and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and through whom we exist. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your iniquities have turned these away, and your sins have kept good from you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 5,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>They read from the book, from the Law of God, clearly, and they gave the sense, so that the people understood the reading.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 8,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He lived there two whole years at his own expense, and welcomed all who came to him, proclaiming the kingdom of God and teaching about the Lord Jesus Christ with all boldness and without hindrance. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 28,30-31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>All the men and women, the people of Israel, whose heart moved them to bring anything for the work that the Lord had commanded by Moses to be done brought it as a freewill offering to the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 35,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>give, and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured back to you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Out
of the mouth of babies and infants, you have established strength because of your foes, to still the enemy and the avenger. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 8,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore God has highly exalted him and bestowed on him the name that is above every name, so that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O my God, incline your ear and hear. Open your eyes and see our desolations, and the city that is called by your name. For we do not present our pleas before you because of our righteousness, but because of your great mercy. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 9,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But we believe that we will be saved through the grace of the Lord Jesus, just as they will.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 15,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He is wise in heart and mighty in strength —who has hardened himself against him, and succeeded?— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember, then, what you received and heard. Keep it, and repent. If you will not wake up, I will come like a thief, and you will not know at what hour I will come against you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And they heard the sound of the Lord God walking in the garden in the cool of the day, and the man and his wife hid themselves from the presence of the Lord God among the trees of the garden. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 3,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Look down from heaven and see, from your holy and beautiful habitation. Where are your zeal and your might? The stirring of your inner parts and your compassion are held back from me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I came to cast fire on the earth, and would that it were already kindled! I have a baptism to be baptized with, and how great is my distress until it is accomplished! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,49-50</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>My people will abide in a peaceful habitation, in secure dwellings, and in quiet resting places.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 32,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the Lord of peace himself give you peace at all times in every way. The Lord be with you all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who is a God like you, pardoning iniquity and passing over transgression for the remnant of his inheritance? He does not retain his anger forever, because he delights in steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 7,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>by canceling the record of debt that stood against us with its legal demands. This he set aside, nailing it to the cross. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But now thus says the Lord, he who created you, O Jacob, he who formed you, O Israel: “Fear not, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name, you are mine. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To this day I have had the help that comes from God, and so I stand here testifying both to small and great, saying nothing but what the prophets and Moses said would come to pass: </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 26,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will instruct you and teach you in the way you should go; I will counsel you with my eye upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 32,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Jews who had believed him, “If you abide in my word, you are truly my disciples, and you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Make your face shine on your servant; save me in your steadfast love! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 31,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So then let us not sleep, as others do, but let us keep awake and be sober. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Does the snow of Lebanon leave the crags of Sirion? Do the mountain waters run dry, the cold flowing streams?  But my people have forgotten me; they make offerings to false gods; they made them stumble in their ways, in the ancient roads, and to walk into side roads, not the highway, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 18,14-15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> Guard your steps when you go to the house of God. To draw near to listen is better than to offer the sacrifice of fools, for they do not know that they are doing evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 5,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now Jesus was praying in a certain place, and when he finished, one of his disciples said to him, “Lord, teach us to pray, as John taught his disciples.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>in God I trust; I shall not be afraid. What can man do to me? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 56,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>It is the Spirit who gives life; the flesh is no help at all. The words that I have spoken to you are spirit and life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,63</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The heavens are the Lord’s heavens, but the earth he has given to the children of man.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 115,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the one who did not know, and did what deserved a beating, will receive a light beating. Everyone to whom much was given, of him much will be required, and from him to whom they entrusted much, they will demand the more. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For at that time I will change the speech of the peoples to a pure speech, that all of them may call upon the name of the Lord and serve him with one accord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext> “For behold, in those days and at that time, when I restore the fortunes of Judah and Jerusalem, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 3,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Being therefore exalted at the right hand of God, and having received from the Father the promise of the Holy Spirit, he has poured out this that you yourselves are seeing and hearing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is in vain that you rise up early and go late to rest, eating the bread of anxious toil; for he gives to his beloved sleep. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 127,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The hearing ear and the seeing eye, the Lord has made them both. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but test everything; hold fast what is good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yet you have made him a little lower than the heavenly beings and crowned him with glory and honor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 8,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him. In love he predestined us for adoption to himself as sons through Jesus Christ, according to the purpose of his will, to the praise of his glorious grace, with which he has blessed us in the Beloved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,4-6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>I call heaven and earth to witness against you today, that I have set before you life and death, blessing and curse. Therefore choose life, that you and
your offspring may live, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As for me, I said in my prosperity, “I shall never be moved.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 30,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Now, therefore, our God, the great, the mighty, and the awesome God, who keeps covenant and steadfast love, let not all the hardship seem little to you that has come upon us, upon our kings, our princes, our priests, our prophets, our fathers, and all your people, since the time of the kings of Assyria until this day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And many rebuked him, telling him to be silent. But he cried out all the more, “Son of David, have mercy on me!” And Jesus stopped and said, “Call him.” And they called the blind man, saying to him, “Take heart. Get up; he is calling you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,48-49</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I perceived that whatever God does endures forever; nothing can be added to it, nor anything taken from it. God has done it, so that people fear before him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 3,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write: ‘The words of the holy one, the true one, who has the key of David, who opens and no one will shut, who shuts and no one opens. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for the Lord reproves him whom he loves, as a father the son in whom he delights. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Nor did we seek glory from people, whether from you or from others, though we could have made demands as apostles of Christ. But we were gentle among you, like a nursing mother taking care of her own children. So, being affectionately desirous of you, we were ready to share with you not only the gospel of God but also our own selves, because you had become very dear to us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 2,6-8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Michaelistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>And you shall remember the whole way that the Lord your God has led you these forty years in the wilderness, that he might humble you, testing you to know what was in your heart, whether you would keep his commandments or not. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Look carefully then how you walk, not as unwise but as wise, making the best use of the time, because the days are evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,15-16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-09-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Is a trumpet blown in a city, and the people are not afraid? Does disaster come to a city, unless the Lord has done it? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 3,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For if we live, we live to the Lord, and if we die, we die to the Lord. So then, whether we live or whether we die, we are the Lord’s. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Zum Erntedankfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>And she vowed a vow and said, “O Lord of hosts, if you will indeed look on the affliction of your servant and remember me and not forget your servant, but will give to your servant a son, then I will give him to the Lord all the days of his life, and no razor shall touch his head.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 1,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>as it is written, “I have made you the father of many nations”—in the presence of the God in whom he believed, who gives life to the dead and calls into existence the things that do not exist. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 4,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“I am the Lord; I have called you in righteousness; I will take you by the hand and keep you; I will give you as a covenant for the people, a light for the nations, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and gathered in from the lands, from the east and from the west, from the north and from the south. Let them thank the Lord for his steadfast love, for his wondrous works to the children of man! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 107,3.8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For in him all the fullness of God was pleased to dwell, and through him to reconcile to himself all things, whether on earth or in heaven, making peace by the blood of his cross. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you with your own hand drove out the nations, but them you planted; you afflicted the peoples, but them you set free; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 44,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And what more shall I say? For time would fail me to tell of Gideon, Barak, Samson, Jephthah, of David and Samuel and the prophets— who through faith conquered kingdoms, enforced justice, obtained promises, stopped the mouths of lions, quenched the power of fire, escaped the edge of the sword, were made strong out of weakness, became mighty in war, put foreign armies to flight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,32-34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, the Lord God helps me; who will declare me guilty? Behold, all of them will wear out like a garment; the moth will eat them up. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let me hear in the morning of your steadfast love, for in you I trust. Make me know the way I should go, for to you I lift up my soul. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 143,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Simon Peter said to them, “I am going fishing.” They said to him, “We will go with you.” They went out and got into the boat, but that night they caught nothing. Just as day was breaking, Jesus stood on the shore; yet the disciples did not know that it was Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 21,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Moreover, the light of the moon will be as the light of the sun, and the light of the sun will be sevenfold, as the light of seven days, in the day when the Lord binds up the brokenness of his people, and heals the wounds inflicted by his blow. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>17. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Hate evil, and love good, and establish justice in the gate; it may be that the Lord, the God of hosts, will be gracious to the remnant of Joseph. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 5,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But now you must put them all away: anger, wrath, malice, slander, and obscene talk from your mouth. Do not lie to one another, seeing that you have put off the old self with its practices </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,8-9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For everything there is a season, and a time for every matter under heaven: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 3,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And as the men were parting from him, Peter said to Jesus, “Master, it is good that we are here. Let us make three tents, one for you and one for Moses and one for Elijah”—not knowing what he said. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>While the words were still in the king’s mouth, there fell a voice from heaven, “O King Nebuchadnezzar, to you it is spoken: The kingdom has departed from you, and you shall be driven from among men, and your dwelling shall
be with the beasts of the field. And you shall be made to eat grass like an ox, and seven periods of time shall pass over you, until you know that the Most High rules the kingdom of men and gives it to whom he will.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 4,31-32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Peter and the apostles answered, “We must obey God rather than men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 5,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Some went down to the sea in ships, doing business on the great waters; they saw the deeds of the Lord, his wondrous works in the deep.  Let them thank the Lord for his steadfast love, for his wondrous works to the children of man! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 107,23.24.31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that they should seek God, and perhaps feel their way toward him and find him. Yet he is actually not far from each one of us, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I know the plans I have for you, declares the Lord, plans for welfare and not for evil, to give you a future and a hope. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 29,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To them God chose to make known how great among the Gentiles are the riches of the glory of this mystery, which is Christ in you, the hope of glory. Him we proclaim, warning everyone and teaching everyone with all wisdom, that we may present everyone mature in Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,27-28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will greatly rejoice in the Lord; my soul shall exult in my God, for he has clothed me with the garments of salvation; he has covered me with the robe of righteousness, as a bridegroom decks himself like a priest with a beautiful headdress, and as a bride adorns herself with her jewels. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are you who are hungry now, for you shall be satisfied. “Blessed are you who weep now, for you shall laugh. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the word is very near you. It is in your mouth and in your heart, so that you can do it.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the crowds asked him, “What then shall we do?” And he answered them, “Whoever has two tunics is to share with him who has none, and whoever has food is to do likewise.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 3,10-11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>18. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Those who pay regard to vain idols forsake their hope of steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he came to the place, he said to them, “Pray that you may not enter into temptation.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Lift up your eyes to the heavens, and look at the earth beneath; for the heavens vanish like smoke, the earth will wear out like a garment, and they who dwell in it will die in like manner; but my salvation will be forever, and my righteousness will never be dismayed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you have taken my silver and my gold, and have carried my rich treasures into your temples. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 3,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I tell you, ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why have you despised the word of the Lord, to do what is evil in his sight? You have struck down Uriah the Hittite with the sword and have taken his wife to be your wife and have killed him with the sword of the Ammonites. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 12,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The stupid man cannot know; the fool cannot understand this:  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 92,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Male and female he created them, and he blessed them and named them Man when they were created.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 5,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Love one another with brotherly affection. Outdo one another in showing honor. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deliver me from all my transgressions. Do not make me the scorn of the fool! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 39,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to her, “Daughter, your faith has made you well; go in peace.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>19. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>gold, silver, bronze, and iron. Arise and work! The Lord be with you!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 22,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Simon answered, “Master, we toiled all night and took nothing! But at your word I will let down the nets.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Commit your work to the Lord, and your plans will be established. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for it is God who works in you, both to will and to work for his good pleasure. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But be glad and rejoice forever in that which I create; for behold, I create Jerusalem to be a joy, and her people to be a gladness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song of the Lamb, saying, “Great and amazing are your deeds, O Lord God the Almighty! Just and true are your ways, O King of the nations! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is good that one should wait quietly for the salvation of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: “Keep justice, and do righteousness, for soon my salvation will come, and my righteousness be revealed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 56,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let each of you look not only to his own interests, but also to the interests of others. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O house of Jacob, come, let us walk in the light of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you are all children of light, children of the day. We are not of the night or of the darkness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Go out from Babylon, flee from Chaldea, declare this with a shout of joy, proclaim it, send it out to the end of the earth; say, “The Lord has redeemed his servant Jacob!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this gospel of the kingdom will be proclaimed throughout the whole world as a testimony to all nations, and then the end will come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then Amos answered and said to Amaziah, “I was no prophet, nor a prophet’s son, but I was a herdsman and a dresser of sycamore figs. But the Lord took me from following the flock, and the Lord said to me, ‘Go, prophesy to my people Israel.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 7,14-15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the other hand, the one who prophesies speaks to people for their upbuilding and encouragement and consolation.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 14,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And
I will multiply on you man and beast, and they shall multiply and be fruitful. And I will cause you to be inhabited as in your former times, and will do more good to you than ever before. Then you will know that I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-10-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>The eyes of the Lord are toward the righteous and his ears toward their cry. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 34,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore welcome one another as Christ has welcomed you, for the glory of God.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Will it be well with you when he searches you out? Or can you deceive him, as one deceives a man? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 13,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Say to those who have an anxious heart, “Be strong; fear not! Behold, your God will come with vengeance, with the recompense of God. He will come and save you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 35,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why, O Lord, do you stand far away? Why do you hide yourself in times of trouble? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 10,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 15,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be exalted, O Lord, in your strength! We will sing and praise your power. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 21,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The good person out of the good treasure of his heart produces good, and the evil person out of his evil treasure produces evil, for out of the abundance of the heart his mouth speaks. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,45</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>21. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>They refused to obey and were not mindful of the wonders that you performed among them, but they stiffened their neck and appointed a leader to return to their slavery in Egypt. But you are a God ready to forgive, gracious and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love, and did not forsake them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>bearing with one another and, if one has a complaint against another, forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Great is the Lord, and greatly to be praised, and his greatness is unsearchable. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 145,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily, and you have been filled in him, who is the head of all rule and authority. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the king of Israel answered, “Tell him, ‘Let not him who straps on his armor boast himself as he who takes it off.’”  </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 20,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Know this, my beloved brothers: let every person be quick to hear, slow to speak, slow to anger; for the anger of man does not produce the righteousness of God.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,19-20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not spurn us, for your name’s sake; do not dishonor your glorious throne; remember and do not break your covenant with us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and has raised up a horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David, to show the mercy promised to our fathers and to remember his holy covenant, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,69.72</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Spirit of the Lord God is upon me, because the Lord has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the Lord’s favor, and the day of vengeance of our God; to comfort all who mourn; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and saying, “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the wound of the daughter of my people is my heart wounded; I mourn, and dismay has taken hold on me. Is there no balm in Gilead? Is there no physician there? Why then has the health of the daughter of my people not been restored? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,21.22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus answered them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick.  I have not come to call the righteous but sinners to repentance.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 5,31-32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, I will shake my hand over them, and they shall become plunder for those who served them. Then you will know that the Lord of hosts has sent me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 2,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You shall not hate your brother in your heart, but you shall reason frankly with your neighbor, lest you incur sin because of him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we urge you, brothers, admonish the idle, encourage the fainthearted, help the weak, be patient with them all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The troubles of my heart are enlarged; bring me out of my distresses.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 25,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are wearied with your many counsels; let them stand forth and save you, those who divide the heavens, who gaze at the stars, who at the new moons make known what shall come upon you. Behold, they are like stubble; the fire consumes them; they cannot deliver themselves from the power of the flame. No coal for warming oneself is this, no fire to sit before! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 47,13-14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have no greater joy than to hear that my children are walking in the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>3.John 1,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your heart therefore be wholly true to the Lord our God, walking in his statutes and keeping his commandments, as at this day.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,61</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he who is joined to the Lord becomes one spirit with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 6,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And nations shall come to your light, and kings to the brightness of your rising. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, some are last who will be first, and some are first who will be last.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your dead shall live; their bodies shall rise. You who dwell in the dust, awake and sing for joy! For your dew is a dew of light, and the earth will give birth to the dead. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I heard a voice from heaven saying, “Write this: Blessed are the dead who die in the Lord from now on.” “Blessed indeed,” says the Spirit, “that they may rest from their labors, for their deeds follow them!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 14,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>
But there will be no gloom for her who was in anguish. In the former time he brought into contempt the land of Zebulun and the land of Naphtali, but in the latter time he has made glorious the way of the sea, the land beyond the Jordan, Galilee of the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who gave himself for us to redeem us from all lawlessness and to purify for himself a people for his own possession who are zealous for good works. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the Lord your God has blessed you in all the work of your hands. He knows your going through this great wilderness. These forty years the Lord your God has been with you. You have lacked nothing.”’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 2,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So neither he who plants nor he who waters is anything, but only God who gives the growth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not add to the word that I command you, nor take from it, that you may keep the commandments of the Lord your God that I command you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he answered them, “My mother and my brothers are those who hear the word of God and do it.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is well with the man who deals generously and lends; who conducts his affairs with justice. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 112,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And as you wish that others would do to you, do so to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Buß- und Bettag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Oh, save your people and bless your heritage! Be their shepherd and carry them forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 28,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I have other sheep that are not of this fold. I must bring them also, and they will listen to my voice. So there will be one flock, one shepherd. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When I think of your rules from of old, I take comfort, O Lord.  </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,52</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And she had a sister called Mary, who sat at the Lord’s feet and listened to his teaching. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Arise, O Lord! Let not man prevail; let the nations be judged before you! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 9,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then we who are alive, who are left, will be caught up together with them in the clouds to meet the Lord in the air, and so we will always be with the Lord. Therefore encourage one another with these words.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,17-18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be very careful, therefore, to love the Lord your God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 23,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we have come to know and to believe the love that God has for us. God is love, and whoever abides in love abides in God, and God abides in him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres (Ewigkeitssonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>O our God, will you not execute judgment on them? For we are powerless against this great horde that is coming against us. We do not know what to do, but our eyes are on you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He raises up the poor from the dust; he lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honor. For the pillars of the earth are the Lord’s, and on them he has set the world. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. He is the radiance of the glory of God and the exact imprint of his nature, and he upholds the universe by the word of his power. After making purification for sins, he sat down at the right hand of the Majesty on high, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,2-3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If you do well, will you not be accepted? And if you do not do well, sin is crouching at the door. Its desire is contrary to you, but you must rule over it.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 4,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and, having been set free from sin, have become slaves of righteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord of hosts, the God of Israel: Amend your ways and your deeds, and I will let you dwell in this place. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 7,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they were selling their possessions and belongings and distributing the proceeds to all, as any had need. And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, praising God and having favor with all the people. And the Lord added to their number day by day those who were being saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,45-47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-11-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said to Moses, “This very thing that you have spoken I will do, for you have found favor in my sight, and I know you by name.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he came to her and said, “Greetings, O favored one, the Lord is with you!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Pride goes before destruction, and a haughty spirit before a fall. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For if anyone thinks he is something, when he is nothing, he deceives himself. But let each one test his own work, and then his reason to boast will be in himself alone and not in his neighbor. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,3-4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>saying, ‘Turn now, every one of you, from his evil way and evil deeds, and dwell upon the land that the Lord has given to you and your fathers from of old and forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 25,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Bear fruits in keeping with repentance. And do not begin to say to yourselves, ‘We have Abraham as our father.’ For I tell you, God is able from these stones to raise up children for Abraham. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 3,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Sing to the Lord a new song, his praise from the end of the earth, you who go down to the sea, and all that fills it, the coastlands and their inhabitants. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And his father Zechariah was filled with the Holy Spirit and prophesied, saying, “Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,67-68</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For behold, I create new heavens and a new earth, and the former things shall not be remembered or come into mind. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and be like men who are waiting for their master to come home from the wedding feast, so that they may open the door to him at once when he comes and knocks. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>he said to them, “Take to heart all the words by which I am warning you today, that you may command them to your children, that they may be careful to do all the words of this law. For it is no empty word for you, but your very life, and by this word you shall live long in the land that you are going over the Jordan to possess.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,46.47</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>There was a man sent from God, whose name was John. He was not the light, but came to bear witness about the light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,6.8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will rescue my flock; they shall no longer be a prey. And I will judge
between sheep and sheep. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Husbands, love your wives, as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The earth, O Lord, is full of your steadfast love; teach me your statutes! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,64</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As each has received a gift, use it to serve one another, as good stewards of God’s varied grace: </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, O God of my salvation, and my tongue will sing aloud of your righteousness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 51,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The apostles said to the Lord, “Increase our faith!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Toward the scorners he is scornful, but to the humble he gives favor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Have this mind among yourselves, which is yours in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then Abram said to Lot, “Let there be no strife between you and me, and between your herdsmen and my herdsmen, for we are kinsmen. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 13,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As it is, there are many parts, yet one body.  </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord bless you and keep you; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 6,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My tongue will sing of your word, for all your commandments are right. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,172</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Moreover, I gave them my Sabbaths, as a sign between me and them, that they might know that I am the Lord who sanctifies them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By the Holy Spirit who dwells within us, guard the good deposit entrusted to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord God called to the man and said to him, “Where are you?”  And he said, “I heard the sound of you in the garden, and I was afraid, because I was naked, and I hid myself.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 3,9-10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And because you are sons, God has sent the Spirit of his Son into our hearts, crying, “Abba! Father!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Fear not, for you will not be ashamed; be not confounded, for you will not be disgraced; for you will forget the shame of your youth, and the reproach of your widowhood you will remember no more. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By faith he left Egypt, not being afraid of the anger of the king, for he endured as seeing him who is invisible. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who devise wickedness and work evil on their beds! When the morning dawns, they perform it, because it is in the power of their hand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus called them to him and said to them, “You know that those who are considered rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them, and their great ones exercise authority over them. But it shall not be so among you. But whoever would be great among you must be your servant, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,42-43</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>When David’s time to die drew near, he commanded Solomon his son, saying, “I am about to go the way of all the earth. Be strong, and show yourself a man, and keep the charge of the Lord your God, walking in his ways and keeping his statutes, his commandments, his rules, and his testimonies, as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn,</Losungstext><Losungsvers> 1 Kings 2,1-2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And so, from the day we heard, we have not ceased to pray for you, asking that you may be filled with the knowledge of his will in all spiritual wisdom and understanding, so as to walk in a manner worthy of the Lord, fully pleasing to him: bearing fruit in every good work and increasing in the knowledge of God; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,9-10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He remembers his covenant forever, the word that he commanded, for a thousand generations, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For whatever was written in former days was written for our instruction, that through endurance and through the encouragement of the Scriptures we might have hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But my brothers who went up with me made the heart of the people melt; yet I wholly followed the Lord my God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 14,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By your endurance you will gain your lives. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but there is a God in heaven who reveals mysteries, and he has made known to King Nebuchadnezzar what will be in the latter days. Your dream and the visions of your head as you lay in bed are these: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Being asked by the Pharisees when the kingdom of God would come, he answered them, “The kingdom of God is not coming in ways that can be observed, nor will they say, ‘Look, here it is!’ or ‘There!’ for behold, the kingdom of God is in the midst of you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,20-21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I hope for your salvation, O Lord, and I do your commandments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 119,166</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And it had been revealed to him by the Holy Spirit that he would not see death before he had seen the Lord’s Christ. And he came in the Spirit into the temple, and when the parents brought in the child Jesus, to do for him according to the custom of the Law, he took him up in his arms and blessed God and said,</Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,26-27.28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Far be it from us that we should rebel against the Lord and turn away this day from following the Lord by building an altar for burnt offering, grain offering, or sacrifice, other than the altar of the Lord our God that stands before his tabernacle!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 22,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>They said to each other, “Did not our hearts burn within us while he talked to us on the road, while he opened to us the Scriptures?” And they rose that same hour and returned to Jerusalem. And they found the eleven and those who were with them gathered together, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,32-33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, I am with you and will keep you wherever you go, and will bring you back to this land. For I will not leave you until I have done what I have promised you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 28,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we have the prophetic word more fully confirmed, to which you will do well to pay attention as to a lamp shining in a dark place, until the day dawns and the morning star rises in your hearts, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 1,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>The command that Jonadab the son of Rechab gave to his sons, to drink no wine, has been kept, and they drink none to this day, for they have obeyed their father’s command. I have spoken to you persistently, but you have not listened to me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 35,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Long ago, at many times and in many ways, God spoke to our fathers by the prophets, but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,1-2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is a consuming fire, a jealous God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In this is love, not that we have loved God but that he loved us and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>He
is the Lord our God; his judgments are in all the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 105,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is the judgment: the light has come into the world, and people loved the darkness rather than the light because their works were evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 3,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>a bruised reed he will not break, and a faintly burning wick he will not quench; he will faithfully bring forth justice. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this will be a sign for you: you will find a baby wrapped in swaddling cloths and lying in a manger.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>There shall come forth a shoot from the stump of Jesse, and a branch from his roots shall bear fruit. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the fullness of time had come, God sent forth his Son, born of woman, born under the law, to redeem those who were under the law, so that we might receive adoption as sons. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,4-5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For thus says the One who is high and lifted up, who inhabits eternity, whose name is Holy: “I dwell in the high and holy place, and also with him who is of a contrite and lowly spirit, to revive the spirit of the lowly, and to revive the heart of the contrite. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the blind receive their sight and the lame walk, lepers are cleansed and the deaf hear, and the dead are raised up, and the poor have good news preached to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As for man, his days are like grass; he flourishes like a flower of the field; for the wind passes over it, and it is gone, and its place knows it no more. But the steadfast love of the Lord is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear him, and his righteousness to children’s children,</Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalm 103,15-16.17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2017-12-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Altjahresabend</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then the Lord said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 3,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen></FreeXml>